Morning, Rory.
Please tell me you haven't
been standing there all night.
I love you Rory.
Creepy.
- Ooh, waffles?
- Yes, I got up early this morning
and I thought,
"what better way to pass time
than make some of my
famous homemade waffles?"
I can't believe I forgot
about your homemade waffles,
seeing how famous they are.
Infamous, really.
So why'd you get up so early?
Mm, well, couldn't sleep.
And, initially,
I was at a loss.
I mean, how would I pass the time
until my one and only offspring,
- the fruit of my loins --
- Too early.
...loin fruit that she is,
straggled out of bed to
grace me with her presence?
But then I asked
myself, "W.W.T.B.F.C.D.?"
And it came to me in a flash.
"I'm gonna make waffles."
"What would the
barefoot contessa do?"
Exactly.
Barefoot's one word.
Shut up, loin fruit.
So, what? Are you just sleepy
or has last night's "my boyfriend gave
me a love rocket" elation worn off?
It may have worn
off a little bit.
Why? What happened?
The love rocket was making you
swoon for Logan last night.
I'm still plenty swoony.
I just realized that
the rocket doesn't mean
I should be packing
my bags for London.
Why? What happened?
Nothing happend.
I just called Logan, and I was like,
"yeah, yeah.
Oh, I love the love rocket, you know?
And I can't wait
to come see you."
And he was like,
"oh, yeah, me too.
Um, I'm gonna buy you
a ticket for december."
Oh, no. Did you tell him
you want to visit him now?
There wasn't really a point,
you know, because I get it.
He is starting his
first real job.
I mean,
he needs time to adjust and focus
and learn the lay of the land.
I mean, it's good that he's trying
to be a grown-up, you know.
So now I'm trying
to be a grown-up.
So why am I gonna get all pouty
because I don't get to do it?
Hmm.
Well, that sounds like
a real grown-up talking.
Thank you.
You know the one thing that
grown-ups don't call themselves?
What?
Grown-ups.
They say "adults," And they
pronounce it "ah-dults."
- It stinks!
- Oh, it really stinks.
Stupid London!
If he weren't in London right now,
we would be on our Asia trip.
I mean, I knew that it might not happen,
but I hoped it would,
and I just kept planning
and planning and planning.
Wow. Were you planning on
visiting Asia or invading it?
Look at all this wasted effort.
All this highlighter
ink? Wasted.
All of these sticky
notes? Wasted.
We were going to see the
terra-cotta soldiers in Xian.
And we were going to go to Peking
for the opera and the duck.
I want to see Tibet. I want to snorkel
off the an thoi islands in Vietnam.
I want to see the crazy teenage fashions
in the harajuku district of Tokyo.
Oh, wow.
Stupid London!
-  So, no Asia?
- No Asia.
Well, I guess I got
to go to stupid work.
Here's one good piece
of news, though.
Lane called.
She's back from her honeymoon.
- Oh, yay!
- Yeah.
She sounded kind of tired,
which is good, I think.
Tired after a
honeymoon bodes well.
My married friend Lane and
her married husband Zach.
Nutso.
Hmm. Spoken like
a true grown-up.
Say "hey" to her for me.
It's nice to have you home.
Bye.
Morning, Luke.
- You need a hand with this?
- Thanks.
Sure thing.
Just give me one second
to savor this coffee.
So, how are you this
lovely morning?
Just fine.
- Hey, I got a coffee for you, too.
- Thanks.
But then, as it became clear that
you were most likely gonna be late,
I didn't want it to get cold,
so I drank it myself.
I wasn't late.
Who said you were late?
You did, one second ago.
Oh, no, I said you were
mostly likely gonna be late,
but it turns out you weren't.
Who knew?
Sounds like you need a little caffeine,
my friend.
What say you and I go over to
the diner across the street
and pick us up a
nice cup of coffee?
Forget it. I'm fine.
What diner across the street?
This place --
Kirk's. Great place.
The owner's a real character.
And the coffee's fantastic.
Come on, let me get you a cup,
though maybe you ought to pay, seeing
as I did pick us up the last round.
Eggs sunny side up
with a side of bacon.
And who's got the
scrambled with hashbrowns?
Here we go.
What the hell is going on here?
Welcome to Kirk's.
I'll be right with you.
What is this?
It's a diner, Luke.
A diner called Kirk's?
It's the name my
mother gave me.
Top you off there, Jake?
Why  are you doing this?
I just saw a need,
and I filled it.
Seemed  to me Stars Hollow was in
want of a real neighborhood joint,
a watering hole where the
townsfolk could mingle,
a place where a fella could come and
get a piece of pie, a cup of arbuckles',
and a soupcon of
small-town charm.
Yeah, well,
Stars Hollow has already got that place.
It's right across the street.
It's called Luke's.
Luke's. Ring any bells?
Sounds a little like Kirk's,
doesn't it?
Luke, if you are suggesting that
you were the very first person
to ever think of naming a
restaurant after yourself,
I think that Denny Arby,
and Tony Roma
might have something
to say about that,
not to mention Mr.
Chuck E. Cheese.
Chuck E. Cheese... Chuck E.
Cheese is not a person.
Luke, do you think a giant mouse opened
a national restaurant franchise by himself?
Look at this -- french toast,
pancakes, buttermilk pancakes.
You stole my menu.
You did not invent
pancakes, Luke.
Anyway, I heard Luke's
went out of business.
Luke's did not go out of business.
Luke's is closed for repairs.
And you want to know
why it's closed?
Because some nincompoop yesterday
drove his car through my diner!
Would you care to step
outside for a moment, Luke?
Outside? Outside what?
I think it would behoove you
not to use slanderous language
like nincompoop in my
place of business, Luke,
because, let me tell you, it is only
out of the kindness of my heart
that I am not suing
the pants off of you.
You're gonna sue me after
you crash a car into my diner
and bust a giant
hole in my wall?
For all you know,
I could have brain damage.
Oh, I'm pretty sure you do.
You know what, Kirk?
Go ahead. Sue me.
Crash into my diner,
make me lose a week's business,
make me pay for the repairs,
and then sue me for damages --
for brain damages!
That sounds fair.
Luke, calm down.
I get where you're coming from.
I think we can work
something out.
What is this?
A job application.
The way business is picking up,
I'm totally gonna need a fry guy.
What, it sounded like your
finances were kind of tight.
If you came expecting a handout,
you came to the wrong guy.
I'm of the "teach a man
to fish" school, Luke.
You do not throw trash on the
floor of a restaurant, Luke.
Not cool.
Okay, this is easy.
You put in your snow crab.
You put in your avocado.
You put in your cucumber.
You match it together.
And then you just roll it up.
Slice it up like this,
and voilà.
Or whatever they say in Japan.
- Arigato.
- Karate.
Look, it's those little coin shapes,
just like in a japanese restaurant.
Arigato karate, babe.
Yep. Okay.
I'm gonna make one
more California roll,
and then we can make your
meat-loaf sushi as promised.
Yay! Do you want to put
suntan lotion in there?
Did you just say sun--
Oh! Of course.
Because a California roll would
have some suntan lotion in it.
You're such a pity laugher.
Mmm! Good!
- Good?
- So good!
It's the best non-meat-loaf
sushi I've ever had.
Ooh! What about
fried-chicken sushi?
With some slaw in it.
That would be so good.
Or chinese-food sushi.
Or P.B.-and-J. sushi.
Or, hey, dessert sushi.
Oh, my god, that's genius.
That is why you are the chef.
That and because you're
the one who can cook.
So, um...
Hey, um...
So I-I told him.
Told who what?
- Telling him that?
- Yeah.
Are you saying you told
Luke about Christopher?
Yes. What did you think
I was talking about?
I don't know.
I'm hoping there's
something that I forgot,
like maybe you were debating
on whether or not to tell Kirk
the difference between
antiperspirant and deodorant.
You told Luke
about Christopher?
Yes.
I thought no matter what
you weren't going to.
I wasn't.
Oh, honey, why?
Because Luke showed up
at my house this morning
with the truck fully packed,
ready to elope.
- Oh, god, he did?
- Yeah.
And he wouldn't take no for an answer,
and so I had to tell him.
That's the only way he
was gonna believe me
because it had to be no.
Did it have to be?
I mean,
did the answer have to be no?
No. I mean,
I guess I could be married right now
to someone who doesn't
want to be married to me
and who doesn't know that I slept with
someone two nights before we got married.
Well, when you
put it that way...
Must have been horrible.
It was one of the most horrible
moments of my whole life.
Are you okay?
No.
I mean, no, not at all.
I'm so very not fine,
but what am I gonna do,
you know?
I have to be fine.
Oh, honey.
Yeah.
Hey, Zach.
So, the honeymoon's over.
Is  the honeymoon over?
What?
How was Mexico?
Full of parasites.
Oh, gee, that's no good.
The whole trip was
a total fiasco.
It was the Stones at
Altamont times a billion.
But you and Lane were
so excited about it.
From the way you talked,
I was worried you'd move there
and start a mariachi band.
Mexico sucks.
And we were psyched.
That's part of why
it sucked so bad.
I thought I found this
amazing deal online, right?
Pedro's Paradise.
It all sounded good.
The website said it had ocean views,
its own kitchen, and a jacuzzi.
And nobody loves jacuzzis
more than me. Nobody.
And then we get there,
and it turns out Pedro's Paradise
is just this room in this dude
Pedro's crappy apartment.
No. His apartment?
23 miles from the ocean, with a view of
a billboard for mexican nasal spray.
So the website lied.
And the kitchen we were promised --
it smelled like rice-a-roni
and was always full of
Pedro's jerky friends
listening to the devil's music,
playing cards,
and making snide remarks
about us in code.
Pedro's friends talked in code?
Well, spanish, technically.
Same difference.
They knew I couldn't understand them.
Pedro was evil, man.
Man.
Anyway, on the second day,
I got some parasite,
and I've been barfing Linda
Blair style ever since.
I'm getting better,
but now it looks like Lane's got it.
Oh no!
I'm heading over to
Doose's right now
to get some ginger
ale and saltines,
which, by the way, was all we
ate in the way of mexican food.
Oh,  I'm sorry your
trip was so sucky.
Yeah, well, live and learn.
Like, now I know not to
drink the water in Mexico,
which, by the way,
somebody should really tell you.
And I learned that I'm not
morally against murder.
I just wish I had
the guts to do it.
Well, I'm glad you didn't kill Pedro.
I mean, he's not worth it.
Yeah, whatever.
Hello.
Hola, Rory.
Hey, sicko.
Oh, welcome home.
I heard Pedro's Paradise
wasn't so paradisey.
Mexico sucked.
Oh. But guess who I heard it from --
your husband.
Can we not squeal about that?
I don't really want to squeal.
But if you feel like squealing,
go ahead.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Of course you don't feel like squealing.
You're sick.
I actually feel okay right now.
My aversion to squealing is
more emotional than physical.
I'm so sorry your honeymoon
was such a bummer.
On, like, the fourth day,
Zach got so paranoid
that Pedro and his friends were
talking lasciviously about me in code
that he lunged at Pedro --
leapt at him from behind the door.
Luckily, Zach was so weak from
parasites that he missed --
just flopped to
the kitchen floor
Like he was a pancake someone
threw across the room.
People throw pancakes?
I just stared at him lying
on the floor and thought,
"I just married that man."
And you didn't squeal for joy.
Nope.
I went into the other room
and stared at Pedro's poster
of Spuds McKenzie hanging 20
and ate my 20th
saltine of the day.
The whole trip sounds
kind of rough.
Oh, you have no idea.
What I just told you are the
highlights compared to the real stuff.
No. What?
We can't talk here.
The walls have ears.
And giant sombrero.
And big mouth.
Let's go for a walk.
No, you're not feeling right.
You should take care of yourself.
I'm feeling all right
right now, actually.
Besides, I have a doctor's
appointment tomorrow,
and if I start to
barf in public,
you could just pretend we
were partying too hard.
Which would do
wonders for my rep.
All right, Mrs. Van Gerbig,
let's blow this popsicle stand.
Okay. So tell me --
what are we thinking
about here?
Well, the basic idea is
to fix the giant hole.
Yeah, but how?
'Cause I've been thinking about it.
I got a couple ideas about
a sort of log-cabin thing.
I think what might really be nice
is a giant stained-glass window.
Yeah, I don't think so.
Don't rule it out so quick.
I can picture what you're picturing,
like with all scary religious pictures.
It wouldn't have to be
a bloody crucifixion.
It could just be an
image of a happy animal.
I don't know,
a smiling penguin or...
or perhaps a
peaceful-looking giraffe.
You think I should put up
a stained-glass window
of a peaceful-looking giraffe
on the side of my diner?
I'm just spitballing.
Nothing's written in stone.
Oh, well, that's good.
How about diamond shapes?
You know what, T.J.?
Why don't we just get to work?
- You're in a bit of a mood.
- I'm not in a mood, damn it.
Okay! I'm sorry
I said anything.
I won't say anything else.
You know what, T.J., forget it.
I'm sorry.
I really appreciate the
help you're giving me.
I know it was
last-minute. Okay?
No problem, buddy.
What are brother-in-laws for?
Actually...
I'm glad for an excuse
to be out of the house.
Because being pregnant
makes Liz incredibly horny.
- T.J.
- Yeah, Luke?
Can we not talk about
my sister's sexuality?
Oh, yeah. Well, sure.
I guess it's something about all
those hormones racing around in there.
You should totally knock
Lorelai up, though.
T.J.
What, I'm not talking
about your sister.
I'm talking about your fiancée.
I  got a feeling pregnancy would
make Lorelai particularly randy.
T.J.!
Just think how cool it would be if
we raised our families together.
You should get
started now, though.
Right.
So how many kids you guys want?
You know what?
I think I'm gonna go get the primer.
- Now?
- Yeah. I'm just...
worried about the hardware
store's gonna run out.
'Cause you know,
it is the primer season.
- Good thinking.
- Yeah, I'll be right back.
So, now I know.
Know what?
That it's bad. It's terrible.
Sex.
Oh. No. Sex was bad?
You can drop the act, Rory.
It's okay.
I've known the real deal
about Santa Claus for years.
And now I know about sex.
- Lane --
- You know what's funny?
I really thought my mother
was being an insane prude
when she said that sex
was horrible for women.
But now I can see that,
in fact,
my mother was the only
woman who wasn't willing
to maintain this ridiculous,
pervasive, media-supported charade.
What ridiculous, pervasive,
media-supported charade?
That sex is normal.
That sex is a
wonderful part of life.
That sex is sexy.
I mean,
can we just not admit it?
Sex is not sexy.
Sex is horrible.
Sex doesn't have
to be horrible.
In a way, I'm impressed with
the depth of the conspiracy.
If you think about it, it says something
about the potential power of women
that the entire
gender could collude
in creating the
"sex is sexy" myth.
So sex with Zach was bad?
Unbelievably bad.
Every time?
Yeah, right. Every time.
You only did it once.
That's right, and I'm out.
Well, the first
time can be weird.
I mean, my first time definitely
had its weird aspects,
but it gets better.
It gets good.
Um, sorry.
I just don't believe you.
Um... okay. You have to walk
me through what happened.
I mean, not graphically,
but help me out here.
Okay. So we decided that,
for our first time,
since it was such a big
deal and everything,
since we've been waiting
and waiting and --
God, if I'd known what
it was going to be like,
I would have gladly
kept waiting.
But anyway, we decided to re-create
the scene in "From here to eternity."
Wow. Ambitious.
Sex on the beach.
Anyway, the whole
thing was a disaster.
Because you know what
movies don't tell you?
That sand is basically dirt.
It was dirty. It was cold.
My hands were shaking.
I'm trying to remember stuff from
school about condoms and bananas.
And then suddenly I realize,
we got crabs,
live ones that are
scuttling all over us.
And Zach starts freaking out because,
apparently, he's afraid of shellfish.
And it's getting
colder and dirtier.
And at some point,
this pervert with a snorkel mask
appears out of nowhere.
And I'm thinking,
"we took three buses from
Pedro's apartment for this."
Oh, Lane.
Yeah, just talking about it
makes me feel sick and queasy.
Well, you are sick and queasy.
You have a parasite.
But, okay.
Once you feel better, you really should
try sex again indoors in a bed.
I'm open to the idea
of a sexless marriage.
I mean, it happens for some people,
eventually. Why wait?
Try a bed first. Seriously.
You would not believe what a comforter
can do in this kind of situation.
Hey, aren't you supposed
to be in Asia right now?
How come you're not traipsing
around Thailand with Logan?
Um, Logan's job started.
He's far, far away in London.
You're lucky.
Yeah.
Sorry.
Oh. Don't worry about me.
I'm fine.
Are you fine, really?
Because, I mean,
you don't have to be fine.
Because this is really
weird and really hard and...
- I'm not exactly fine.
- You're not?
Of course not.
Well, that's too bad because I am.
I'm fine.
Well... okay.
You know, maybe you should
punch Christopher's lights out.
- That seemed to do it for me.
- What?
Oh, so your boyfriend
didn't tell you.
You punched Christopher?
You two need to work on
your communication skills.
- Oh, stop it.
- What?
Christopher is
not my boyfriend.
I don't care if he is.
I mean, you can date whoever
or whatever you want.
I couldn't care less. I'm fine.
Okay, fine.
Well, if you're so fine,
the next time you get a hankering
to punch someone else, don't, okay?
If you need to take your anger
out on someone, take it out on me.
I'm the one you're mad at.
I'm the one who deserves it.
Look, you're the one
who's still hung up here.
I'm telling you, I'm over it.
I mean, I guess it's just not as
big a deal to me as it is to you.
Oh, it's not as big a deal?
Yeah, so what? We're not getting
married. It's okay by me.
I mean, you're the one who
proposed in the first place.
It looks good.
If you say so.
It's no Sistine chapel.
Well, that's true.
- It's no Taj Mahal.
- No, it is not the Taj Mahal.
So, look,
the window guy's coming by tomorrow,
and he and I are
gonna put it in, so...
after this coat,
you're free to go, okay?
And thanks for the help.
It really looks good.
You sure you don't
want any of this?
No, I'm sure.
- You stop drinking beer?
- No.
It makes you kind of bloated,
but to me, it's worth it.
I'm psyched Kirk's
got a liquor license.
How come you quit
drinking beer?
Whoever said I quit
You know what I like?
Drinking beer outside.
I don't know,
maybe it's 'cause I grew up
watching my dad drink
out behind the tool shed,
and it's got this
romantic image for me.
- But that's my thing.
- Your thing is drinking beer outside?
Beer outside is the greatest.
Oh, except for at ice-skating rinks,
of course.
Of course.
Yeah, there's
something about the way
the zamboni exhaust
mixes with the beer
that's really just
out of this world.
Speaking of which, guess what I just
got -- tickets to the hockettes.
You know the hockettes,
the ice-skating girls? They're amazing.
They do everything the rockettes do,
only they do it with ice skates on.
Oh, that's great, T.J.
Guess how many tickets I got.
Four.
And who did I think might
like to go with me and Liz?
President and Mrs.
Bush. Just kidding.
- You and Lorelai.
- Oh, gee.
I don't...
think we can make that.
Come on! When's the last time
we all had a wild night out?
Yeah, you know,
I think I'm doing something that week.
Man, that sucks.
Wait, which week?
Uh, the week of the rockettes.
Which is which week?
The week they're here.
They're in town a whole month!
And I'm fully willing
to switch my tickets
for whichever night
is best for you guys.
Yeah, I don't --
I don't think so.
- Come on.
- I...
Lorelai and I... broke up.
- T.J., okay!
- It's okay, buddy.
It's okay. Let it out.
There is no shame in experiencing pain.
I'm having trouble breathing.
You are coming over to dinner
tonight with me and Liz.
Hello, honorable Rory-San.
You've made Asia for me?
Mm-hmm. Here's your kimono,
honorable Rory-San.
Thank you.
You made crazy Asia.
Well, actually, believe it or not,
but this is an exact replica
of Japan, China,
Vietnam, Cambodia,
Hong Kong, Korea,
and any other Asian countries that might
have slipped my mind for the moment.
This is exactly what you
would see in the other Asia.
The one that's not
in our living room.
Yeah, the old Asia.
The first attempt, I like to call it
"The prototype".
Asia's a lot smaller
than I thought,
more intimate.
And more fragrant.
Yes, well, miss Patty donated
a bottle of her opium perfume,
- and I spritzed it around a little.
- A little.
Well, little at first,
and then I tripped on my flip-flop
and broke the bottle.
Asia's so pretty.
I love all the lanterns and...
Oh, the poster of Mao.
Very nice.
And one of Sandra Oh. Because oddly,
you have a poster of Sandra Oh.
Well, she's a goddess.
And those aren't posters.
They're billboards.
You've lost perspective.
Ah. I see you feng
shuied the furniture.
Because it was so unfeng shuied before.
It was ridiculous.
Here --
to document our journey.
Xie xie.
Oh, god bless you.
That's "thank you" in mandarin.
I knew that. Just testing you.
Perhaps I shall
outline our itinerary.
Perhaps we shall.
All right, well,
first stop is Japan,
land of the rising sun,
ruled by Hello Kitty,
where we are gonna
make our own sushi.
You, me, and raw fish?
Is that safe?
Well, I took a lesson,
and if you're really nervous,
then we can skip the fugu.
After we're stuffed with sushi,
we will take an invisible rickshaw
to the rice paddies, i.e.
your room,
Where we will spend
hours origamiing.
- Paper cranes!
- Yeah, and paper bulldozers
and paper dump trucks and whatever
else your little heart desires.
Then, we'll take a bullet
train straight back to Tokyo
where we'll relax
with some tai chi
in preparation for the
kabuki play I wrote.
Tai chi's actually chinese.
Duh. I know that.
We're gonna teach
it to the japanese.
- That's nice of us.
- We're very nice that way.
All right. So, finally,
we will conclude our journey
with some fortune cookies
and dessert sushi.
Dessert sushi --
I do love Asia.
And that will be followed
by an educational video,
which includes, but is not limited to,
"Bridge on the river Kwai,"
"The joy luck club," "Karate
kid," "Shanghai surprise,"
The Bruce Lee classic
"Enter the dragon,"
The Tom Selleck
classic "Mr. Baseball,"
- and/or "Breakfast at Tiffany's."
- "Breakfast at Tiffany's"?
Yeah, starring Mickey Rooney in his
tour-de-force racist performance
as holly golightly's
japanese landlord.
Oh, yeah, he's so bad.
All right,
let's make some sushi.
But I'm scared.
Oh, I'll let you in on a secret.
The fish is really fried chicken.
You are honestly
asserting that you like
the "tootsie-roll marshmallow
twizzler" roll better
than the "butterfinger junior
mint chocolate-chip jujube" roll?
Call me crazy. But I just don't
think butterfingers go with jujubes.
Crazy.
The limitations of your
palate astound me.
Hey, I liked the "oreo
red hot" sashimi.
Me too.
See, I'm not a hater.
Did you notice how the red hots
acted as a dessert-sushi wasabi?
I did,
which is something we should remember
when we go to
mass-market these.
I'm telling you, the invention of
dessert sushi is gonna make us
- our first million.
- And our second.
I'd like our third
to be go-go dancing.
Sounds like a plan.
You know,
I'm really not following this plot.
Okay, um... in the last scene,
there was a sign that said,
"No shirt, no shoes, no service."
And this guy, shirtless guy,
is angry about that -- angry.
And he's like, "no, I'm not gonna
wear a shirt! I hate shirts!"
End that really pissed those
other guys off.
Hey, you know what would be
amazing and really asian?
Fried ice cream.
Oh, cows must envy
your stomach.
They do.
I'm so full, I can't move.
I feel like one of those cats
that's bred to have no legs.
Don't get me wrong --
my stomach's ready to explode.
This is not a physical hunger.
It's more of a spiritual hunger.
- For fried ice cream.
- Yeah.
It's an eastern-philosophy thing.
You wouldn't understand.
So, how do you think one actually
goes about frying ice cream?
Probably in a frying pan.
Uh-oh. Bit of a situation here.
What?
We are out of ice cream.
I'm a cat with no legs.
We can't answer it.
We're out of the country.
No ice cream. Unbelievable.
One time I feel like cooking,
there's no ice cream to fry.
Lor, hey, it's me.
Just still trying to reach you.
Sorry I missed
your call before.
But I wasn't calling about that
whole "Luke hitting me" thing.
I don't care about that.
I just want to talk to you.
I want to talk to you
about the other night.
I know you said it was
just a one-night thing,
but I want to talk about it,
and about you and me, so...
call me so we can talk.
Okay. Bye.
So...
You slept with dad.
Yeah. I did.
Um, that's just...
I can't believe
you slept with dad.
Is that why you and Luke broke up,
because you slept with dad?
No, honey. No, I...
believe me, no.
Um, Luke and I had
broken up before.
For how long?
I mean, it couldn't have been long.
Because you and Luke have only been
broken up for what, like three days.
Yeah, it was that night.
The night you and
Luke broke up. Wow.
So you just rushed right over there
the minute you were free, huh?
Rory.
Sounds like you were
in quite a hurry.
Did you put a dummy in the passenger
seat so you could use the car-pool Lane?
Rory.
What? You didn't think of it?
In too much of a rush, I guess.
I hope you buckled your seat belt.
You're supposed to buckle your seat belt
even if you're in a rush.
Hey, Rory --
No, don't "Rory" me.
You don't get to "Rory" me.
You slept with dad.
Yeah. I-I-I...I know.
Are you and dad an item now?
No, it was nothing.
I mean, it...
it had nothing to do
with me and Luke.
What happened between me
and your dad was nothing.
It was nothing.
Mom, you slept with dad.
For the love of god,
will you stop saying that?
No, I can't stop saying
it because it happened.
And you're trying to
pretend like it didn't.
I'm not perfect, okay?
People make mistakes.
I mean, Gwyneth Paltrow dyed
her hair that dark brown.
It was very unflattering.
If she's not perfect,
how do you expect me to be?
Yeah, because what you did is
equivalent to dying your hair.
That's great.
Things were finally
good between you two
And between me and dad.
Did you not care that things were
finally really good between me and dad?
I mean, do you not want us to be close?
Did you mean to ruin that?
No! God, no!
I love that dad's been good
and that things with you
and dad have been good.
I...I was hurting.
I was heartbroken.
And...it happened.
I slept with your dad.
It's over now,
and it was a mistake.
I can't believe you
didn't tell me this.
I mean, first of all,
you say you don't want to talk.
So I figure you're going
through some hard emotional time
and you need some space.
That's fine.
But what you didn't tell me
is that you slept with dad.
No, instead you're going around
joking about, you know,
origami and marshmallow sushi,
like I'm some idiot 5-year-old.
Rory, I was gonna tell you.
- I just wanted --
- You know what, mom?
If you're heartbroken,
you rent "An affair to remember,"
you have a good cry, and drown your
sorrows in a pint of ice cream.
You get a hideously
unflattering breakup haircut.
You don't sleep with dad.
Honey, we're home.
Hi.
Keep your hands off me,
you sex maniac.
Oh, big brother,
I'm so, so sorry.
Aw, thanks.
Come in, come in.
Make yourself at home.
Dinner's still in the oven,
so we have time to have
a cocktail here and talk.
Cocktail hour.
Pretty swanky stuff, huh?
- Very, yeah.
- Sit, sit.
You should be the one
that's sitting, Liz.
- I'm fine.
- She's fine.
Plus, it's good for
her to move around.
Keeps all those
hormones circulating
so they don't settle in one place,
if you know what I mean.
White russian. T.J.
She's trying to liquor me up.
I can see where this is going.
It better not.
We're really into white
russians recently.
- It's our thing.
- Yeah.
Of course, mine's a virgin.
Ironically.
Just cream.
So...
I'm ready to talk.
Oh, you know, it's really okay.
I don't need to talk.
It's just nice to be here.
So was it Anna?
What? No. It wasn't Anna.
- You sure?
- Look, it wasn't Anna, okay?
Lorelai and I broke up,
and I'd really rather not talk about it,
so... if you don't want to
talk about something else,
let's just sit here and
drink our white russians.
Lane?
I'm in here.
Is Zach or Brian here?
No.
Sorry I didn't call first. I don't
know the protocol for married friends.
I just had to get
out of my house.
If I were there for
one more second,
I think I would have had
to karate-chop my mom.
I swear,
just chopped her in half.
I guess I...
Lane, are you okay?
Did the doctor say you have a parasite?
In a manner of speaking.
I'm pregnant.
- Shut up.
- I'm pregnant.
- You're not.
- I am.
- No.
- Yes.
I went to the doctor and he told me.
I'm pregnant with a baby.
- No.
- Yes.
- Wow.
- Yeah, wow.
Oh, my god. Wow.
Wow. How did Zach take it?
He didn't. I haven't told him yet.
I haven't told anyone.
I just came back here
and sat here. Pregnant.
- You're not.
- I am.
- Really?
- Really.
I guess the combination
of salt water
and seaweed and discount
mexican condoms
and terrible,
terrible sex leads to a baby.
A baby.
A baby. Sex sucks so bad.
Sex sucks worse than I thought.
You only did it one time, and --
wow, a baby.
That's what you get,
folks, for making whoopee.
You're going to be a mother.
When the doctor told me,
I just started throwing up.
Well, you had morning sickness.
This was a different
kind of throwing up.
This was the kind of
throwing up that you do
when you have to do
something that you can't do.
You're going to be
a great mother.
Maybe someday, but not now.
I have a picture in my
head of me as a mother.
You know, I can imagine it,
and in that picture,
I'm wearing a skirt and heels,
and my hair is up in a bun.
And I'm pushing one of those really
fancy british baby carriages
that are called silver
surfers or something.
Very Madonna in her
british-mommy phase.
When I'm a mom,
I'll be calm and wise
and have my act together.
I am not calm and not wise,
and I really,
really don't have my act together.
You don't have to wear heels
and push a pram to be a mother.
A pram! See?
I didn't even remember
the word pram.
Mothers know the word pram.
Mothers don't have to
know the word pram.
Yes! Yes, they do!
They have to know
all sorts of things.
They have to know what to
do when your baby is crying
and how to change a diaper
And how to use your wrist to
test if the bottle is too hot.
Why the wrist? I don't know.
I have no idea.
I think because it's handy,
no pun intended,
and it's sensitive.
Wrists are sensitive.
It's just one false move,
one misstep,
and I'll ruin it.
I'm still making mistakes, Rory.
Example "a" -- I'm pregnant.
I can't be making mistakes
when I'm a mother.
I'm not the person I need to
be to be able to do this.
I'm not perfect yet.
I'm so not perfect.
You don't have to be perfect.
I mean,
even Gwyneth Paltrow makes mistakes,
like "Shallow Hal"
and that other movie
that nobody saw
where she played a stewardess.
So who's perfect? Nobody.
Not even mothers.
Yeah.
I'm scared.
I know you are,
but you can do this.
First of all, you are great.
And second of all,
you have nine long months
to study about
bottles and wrists.
That's true.
And, already,
you are way ahead of a lot of people
as far as parenting skills go.
Like Britney.
Britney Spears does not know
which end of a baby goes up.
And Courtney Love?
She's no June Cleaver.
Yeah, I bet I could be a better
mother than Courtney Love.
My sock drawer could be a better
But, yes,
of course you would be.
And Michael Jackson --
you know not to name a child "Blanket."
I do know that.
Do not name your baby
after an inanimate object.
See? Way ahead of the pack.
Yeah. Hey...
I wonder if Blanket ever met
Tom and Katie's baby, Pillow.
Yeah, that would be
a perfect playdate.
Yeah, when it's nap time,
they would be totally set.
And then they could invite
Gwyneth's Apple over afterward
for a little snack.
Banjo, Rachel Griffiths' baby,
could play for them.
And then they could all jump
in Mia Farrow's Satchel
and make fun of, uh...
what's his face?
- Oh, Pilot Inspektor Lee.
- Yeah.
Little more time, looks like.
Can I set you up with another
white russian there, Luke?
One was plenty, thank you.
I can't believe it's not ready.
I thought for sure
it'd be ready by now.
I'm so sorry, Luke.
You must be starving.
Don't worry about it.
Maybe we should start with
a little first course.
Let me see what I have in here.
So what exactly are you making
that cooks for this long?
Tuna loaf.
That sounds amazing.
Well, it's very
thoughtful of you.
- Jello cups!
- Score.
Well, anyway,
invention is the mother of necessity.
Eat your jello course.
So it's not surprising,
you know?
What's not?
You and Lorelai breaking up.
I mean, that's not much of a surprise.
Yeah. I don't know.
I mean, I love Lorelai,
but the two of you were...
Were what?
You were never in sync.
I don't mean that in a bad way.
What do you mean,
we were never in sync?
Okay, for one thing,
you never really moved in together.
You wanted to,
but you never did.
You were in two
different places.
Well, there was a
logistical thing.
And then,
when you found out you had a daughter,
you never told her.
That's not normal, Luke.
That's not how people in a
healthy relationship act.
It's like that
space-time-continuum thing.
You're on a plane over here,
and she's on this
plane over there,
and you were both never here
nor there at the same time.
It's like string theory.
String theory?
What do you know about string theory?
Don't underestimate me, Luke.
I read.
And I watch
"Battlestar Galactica."
Look, Lorelai and I
just did not work out.
You were on different planes.
It could have worked out
if there was a wormhole between
your plane and her plane.
We didn't need a wormhole.
It was like that
movie with, um,
Keanu Reeves and
Sandra Bullock.
- Exactly!
- Yeah.
Oh, yes! Exactly, exactly!
You're living in
the same house, man,
but you are a
couple years apart
In the space-time continuum.
What house? It was a bus.
Oh! I thought you were
talking about "Speed."
"Speed" applies, too.
Lorelai and I didn't break up
because we weren't on the same
place in a space-time continuum
or because there
weren't any wormholes.
We broke up because we
weren't right for each other.
Okay, it wasn't space.
It wasn't time.
It was us, okay?
We didn't belong together.
We never really...
belonged together.
We wanted to, but...
we never did.
That's it.
I am so excited.
It's cold.
The oven's cold.
The oven's broken.
Oh, man, still?
We forgot to fix the oven.
Oh, Luke, I am so sorry.
I really wanted to make
you a home-cooked meal.
I'll go the store.
I'll get something to make for us.
Oh, Luke.
That's okay, really.
I don't mind.
I'll get us some stuff and
make us a home-cooked meal.
Your burners work?
Yeah, they work.
Okay, good. Great.
At least you'll have
a home-cooked meal.
Okay, I'll be back in a bit.
Hey.
Well, I guess both of
us avoiding Doose's
didn't work out that well, huh?
Well, I wasn't
avoiding Doose's.
Just the closest market
to Liz and T.J.'s house.
Right. Because you're
not affected by this.
You're not mad. I forgot.
No, I...I was mad.
I was really mad.
Yeah, I kind of figured.
I know I was a jerk.
I was just... mad.
I was the jerk.
I was such a jerk.
I'm not mad anymore. Well...
That's not true, but...
I won't be,
you know, eventually.
Really.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Okay.
It's not your fault.
It's not my fault.
It's just,
we're not right together, you know?
You're you, I'm me.
I just want to stop pretending
we're something else.
You don't belong with me.
You belong with someone like
Christopher, and I just...
Let's just stop
fighting it, okay?
And you go back to
being Lorelai Gilmore.
And I'll go back to being the guy
in the diner who pours your coffee.
My hand's getting cold.
Okay.
www.tvsubtitles.net