This, boys and girls, is a story of true love.
A beautiful girl from one county,
a handsome boy from another.
They meet, and they fall in love.
Separated by distance and by parents
who did not approve of the union...
the young couple dreamed of the day
that they could be together.
They wrote each other beautiful letters,
letters of longing and passion...
letters full of promises
and plans for the future.
Soon the separation proved too much
for either one of them to bear.
So, one night, cold and black...
with no light to guide them,
they both snuck out of their homes...
and ran away as fast as they could.
It was so dark out
that they were both soon lost.
And it seemed as if
they would never find each other.
Finally, the girl dropped to her knees,
tears streaming down her lovely face.
'Oh, my love, where are you?
How will I find you?'
Suddenly, a band of stars
appeared in the sky.
These stars shone so brightly,
they lit up the entire countryside.
The girl jumped to her feet...
and followed the path of the stars,
until finally...
she found herself standing
right where the town gazebo is today.
And there waiting for her,
was her one true love...
who had also been led here
by the blanket of friendly stars.
And that, my friends, is the story
of how Stars Hollow came to be...
and why we celebrate that fateful night...
every year at about this time.
Now, we still have a little time left
in our story hour.
Who wants to hear about the time
I danced in a cage for Tito Puente?
Me.
It was the summer of '66.
So?
- It's depressing.
- It's beautiful.
- She throws herself under a train.
- But I bet she looked great doing it.
I don't know, I think maybe
Tolstoy's a little over my head.
No, that's not true. Tolstoy wrote
for the masses, the common man.
It's untrue that you have to be a genius
to read his stuff.
Yeah, but...
- I know it's big.
- Very big.
- And long.
- Very long.
Many Russian names tend to be spelled
very similarly, so it's confusing.
Every single person's name ends
with 'sky. ' Now how's that possible?
It's one of my favorite books.
I know if you just give it a try...
I'll try again.
- Really?
- Yeah.
You won't be sorry.
- Coffee?
- Please.
I thought Christmas was a big deal
around here.
This is a town that likes the celebrating.
Last year, we had a month-long carnival
when we got off the septic tank system.
- A month long? You're kidding.
- No.
There were rides, a petting zoo,
balloon animals, and a freak show.
Okay, you almost had me going there
for a second.
We did have a ribbon-cutting ceremony.
What are you doing Friday night?
I've got the usual
Friday night grandparents' dinner.
But I thought
if we get back early enough...
we should go watch the bonfire together.
I mean, it's kind of corny,
but it's really pretty.
And they sell star-shaped hot dogs.
How about if you get out of dinner
at your grandparents' this week?
- I don't think so.
- What if it's for a special occasion?
The occasion better include
my being relocated to a plastic bubble...
if my grandmother's gonna
let me out of dinner.
There must be another excuse
that you can use.
Like what?
Like it's your three-month anniversary
with your boyfriend.
- It is?
- Yeah.
Three months from your birthday.
That's when I gave you the bracelet...
and that's when I figure
this whole thing started.
Three months!
Actually, your birthday
was on a Saturday...
so it should be Saturday,
but I work Saturday...
and I planned this whole big thing.
So I thought we could do it Friday.
- What whole big thing?
- Just this once, miss dinner. Please.
Don't make me throw myself under a train.
I'll see what I can do.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- It's our three-month anniversary.
- Yeah, it is.
- I feel stupid I didn't even know about this.
- That's quite all right.
I feel really bad
that I missed our two-month anniversary.
- Quite all right, too.
- How was it?
- Pretty good.
- I'm glad.
- No. Put that away.
- I want to cook.
- You can make soup.
- No.
I want to really cook
like on the Food Channel.
I want to saute things, chop things,
do the 'bam!'
I want to arrange things on plates.
I want to be the iron chef.
- Fine.
- Really?
- Yeah, I'll help.
- Okay.
- I need a pan.
- And a fire extinguisher.
Funny girl.
Now, if I'd only bought some hamburger.
- You didn't buy hamburger?
- Yes, I bought hamburger.
I just like saying things like that
so you look at me like I'm crazy.
So tell me,
why the sudden need to be domestic?
- I don't know. I'm in a funky mood.
- Why?
Too many stars, too much love.
It makes me cranky.
- So you haven't heard from Mr. Medina.
- No, I haven't.
- Maybe that's why you are cranky.
- New subject, please.
- You have a phone also.
- How's it coming with that pan?
Cleopatra, queen of denial.
- The pan. Please.
- Okay, fine.
- New topic.
- Thank you.
I have this huge favor to ask you.
Something I can hold over your head.
Let's hear it.
Friday night is Dean's and my
three-month anniversary.
Three months? Wow!
Dean apparently has some
big, fancy evening planned for us.
- Very classy of him.
- Yes, it is.
But for me to actually partake
of the aforesaid fancy evening...
I have to get out of Friday night dinner.
- Good luck with that.
- Mom.
Do you know how much
Emily Gilmore will not care...
about your anniversary?
You could talk to her.
If there was a runoff between what
Emily Gilmore would care about less:
A two-for-one toilet paper sale
or your anniversary...
your anniversary would win. Hands down.
- You won't even try to help?
- I'm gonna try because I care.
- Emily Gilmore, however...
- Phone, please.
Okay.
What?
Nothing. It's just...
'Mom, Rory and Dean are having their
three-month anniversary on Friday. '
'Really, Lorelai?
Why, that's wonderful. I'm thrilled. '
Stop.
'Three months.
Hold on. I'm going to cartwheel. '
- Forget it.
- No way. She's telling my dad now.
- I think they're cabbage patching.
- That's it. Find your own pan.
- Hello?
- Mom?
- Lorelai?
- Yes.
Hi. How are you doing?
- I'm doing fine.
- That's good.
- I'm pleased.
- And how's Dad?
What do you want, Lorelai?
I was just calling to say hello.
- And now you have.
- Okay, good.
Was there anything else
you wanted to add to that hello?
As a matter of fact, there is.
- You know Rory?
- Yes, I believe I do.
She wanted to say hello, too.
I'm late for a meeting.
I'd love to know why.
Mom, just hear me out, okay?
And don't say anything.
Friday night is Rory and Dean's
three-month anniversary.
While that might not seem
a big deal to you, it is to them.
I'm gonna ask you to do something
you are not gonna wanna do.
I'm begging you to look at it
from her point of view and maybe...
let her, just this once,
not come to dinner on Friday.
All right.
What?
Since this is a special occasion, it would
be fine if Rory missed dinner on Friday.
- It would?
- Yes.
- Are you sure?
- I believe I am.
- No arguments?
- No.
- She won't be there.
- I understand.
- At all.
- I heard.
- All night long.
- I assumed as much.
- Okay.
- All right.
- Anything else?
She's gonna need some help
getting ready for the big night.
- So I should...
- We'll see you at 7:00.
Okay. Right. Bye.
So?
The world is officially coming to an end.
- And they're off.
- The bell just rang three seconds ago.
How did they get lip-locked so fast?
I want a boyfriend to make out with.
Ty Tallson likes you.
I want a different boyfriend
to make out with.
- I can't get to my locker.
- They'll move if you ask nice.
You know, dangle a hotel key
in front of their faces.
This is a school.
You don't do this in a school.
Not unless you've got
a boyfriend like Tristan.
Then you do it anywhere you can.
- Street corner.
- Shopping mall.
- Phone booth.
- Starbucks.
Thank you for the where-to-make-out list.
I just need to get my books.
Hell hath no fury.
Excuse me. You're in my way.
Spawn in front of
somebody else's locker, please.
I'm assuming your locker's in there
somewhere also.
Right behind Belle Watling.
- Have you tried to get their attention?
- Sure have.
- No luck?
- No.
God, look at that.
It's like he's eating her face.
Okay, that's it. I'm getting the fire hose.
Let me try first.
Could you move this whole thing
down to the left a little?
- What?
- You're standing in front of the lockers.
- Our lockers.
- Sorry.
- Just got a little carried away.
- Right.
- Hey, Paris.
- Hey.
You should get bangs.
Thanks for the tip.
You have a long forehead.
Bangs would hide that.
Party at my house Saturday.
Dress to impress, please.
- Come?
- I don't know.
- You could bring your boyfriend.
- I'll see.
- Meet me after Biology?
- And if I don't?
You will.
Yes, I will.
To be young and in love.
What a shame Elizabeth Barrett Browning
wasn't here to see this.
She'd put her head through a wall.
Now, people, this is a kitchen.
At least wear some hairnets.
- Hello. We were...
- Just discussing jam making.
Jackson's gonna start
making jam and preserves.
Maybe tomato sauce.
There's a whole world out there
beyond growing vegetables.
- No coffee?
- Sorry.
That's okay.
- Resume smooching.
- Thank you.
No, cherie. I can't wait either.
Very soon.
You are?
Don't tease me.
I promise all this waiting
will be worthwhile.
I'll see you then.
Goodbye, darling.
So how's Mom?
And while normally I would look forward
to a good verbal sparring match...
today I say no.
My heart is light, the world is fine,
and I have a date for Saturday night.
Your turn.
What I need now is lots and lots of coffee.
Heads up!
- You okay?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
Man!
- That has never happened before.
- Really?
How about that.
I was almost crushed
by a papier-mache star.
- How's your day?
- It's looking pretty good now.
Coffee, please, and a shot of cynicism.
- Why so cheery?
- I don't know. I'm just in a mood.
There's no particular reason
for this mood?
- No. You don't believe me?
- I believe you.
You say there's no reason for the mood,
there's no reason for the mood.
- Simply nuts.
- Or bipolar. That's very big nowadays.
No, Patty, you're wrong.
They built the fire
to throw themselves on it...
when their families found them.
Taylor, you're crazy. They built the fire...
so they could stay warm
their first night here.
Patty, I am the recording secretary
for the Stars Hollow City Council.
I think I know how my town was founded.
Can nobody talk about anything else
but this stupid festival?
That came out a lot louder
than it was supposed to, didn't it?
This festival is commemorating
the founding of our town, young lady.
- I know, Taylor. I'm sorry.
- She's bipolar.
Really? But you're so young.
- Can I get you two anything else?
- No, thank you, sweetheart.
I don't know what's wrong with me.
This is a beautiful festival.
People should be enjoying it.
It's a crazy festival based on a nutty myth
about two lunatics...
who in all probability did not even exist.
Even if they did, they probably
dropped dead of diphtheria before age 24.
The town of Stars Hollow
probably got its name...
from the local dance hall prostitute.
Two rich drunk guys...
who made up the story
to make it look good on a poster.
You're full of hate and loathing,
and I love it.
It's good to have someone
to share this hate with.
My pleasure.
- More coffee?
- Please.
Tomorrow, if you have time...
I'm planning on despising everyone
who says, 'Hey, how's it going?'
You're on.
- Hey, how's it going?
- No, that's just too easy.
Rachel.
Your Rachel?
- You're Rachel?
- I'm Rachel.
What are you...
I mean, I thought you were
in the Congo or Philadelphia or something.
Actually, though very similar
to both the Congo and Philadelphia...
I was in the Mideast.
Guess that postcard
must have gotten lost.
Yeah, things are pretty crazy over there.
Not a lot of writing time.
But I finished up my assignment,
I flew back to Chicago...
and I was walking through O'Hare,
and I look up...
and there's a plane leaving
for Hartford in, like, 20 minutes.
- All of a sudden, I'm on it.
- Nice story.
- I should have called.
- No, you... It's fine.
- You look good.
- Thanks.
You look...
- He thinks you look good, too. Right?
- Right.
- And you do.
- Thank you.
- I'm Lorelai.
- Yeah, she's Lorelai.
I'm Luke's friend.
Yeah, she works at the Independence Inn.
I run it, actually.
Sorry, she runs it.
I love that place.
That must be a pretty big job.
It is. It's crazy.
There's always something happening.
We put these coffeemakers in the rooms
and only half of them work.
They just shake and gurgle
like they're having a fit.
Why were you in the Mideast?
I was doing a photo story...
on how Palestinian and Israeli families
have been affected by the violence.
Well, so you understand
about the job pressure.
I'm gonna go.
- Please don't let me drive you away.
- That's okay, you're not.
I have to go sit in a closet or something.
- So, it was really nice to meet you.
- Yeah, you, too.
Okay. Bye.
'We got new coffeemakers. '
What was I thinking?
You spent a lot of time picking out
those coffeemakers.
Yeah, I'm Mrs. Coffee.
- Okay, I'm still attached to the head.
- Sorry, I'm a little worked up.
- Mom, it's just Luke's ex-girlfriend.
- I know.
I just hate that I made myself
look so stupid in front of...
- Luke?
- No, Rachel.
She was standing there, fresh off a plane.
She had no plane hair at all, might I add.
- What exactly is plane hair?
- You know. It's all big and all...
Got it.
He's looking at her
like she's Miss September.
She's looking at him
like he's Johnny Depp...
and I was just babbling like a moron.
What is wrong with me?
Okay, you are now officially off hair duty.
- I'm sorry. I just...
- No, it's okay.
It's a little early
for Dean to see me completely bald.
Right. That's more a six-month thing.
- What's going on with you?
- I don't know.
It's just all this love in the air, you know.
I miss Max.
There's been so much going on
with your dad coming home...
and family stuff
and your constant existence.
- Thanks for the love.
- Any time.
I haven't had a lot of time to focus on it,
and I miss Max.
I know.
- I had a dream about him the other night.
- Really? Dirty?
Absolutely not. When you're 21,
I'll tell you the real answer.
Anyway, it's put me in a funk since then.
- I'm sorry.
- Me, too.
We could talk about me for years,
and believe me, we will.
But let's focus on you,
the lady of the evening.
- No hooker reference intended.
- Glad to hear it.
- What are you gonna wear with that?
- You tell me.
- Where is he taking you?
- Why?
You don't want to clash with the decor.
A lady plans ahead.
If you must know,
he's taking me to Andeloro's.
- Isn't that romantic.
- I know.
It's gonna be just like Lady and the Tramp.
You'll share spaghetti,
but it'll just be one long strand.
You won't realize it
until you meet in the middle.
Then, he'll push a meatball
towards you with his nose...
and you'll push it back with your nose.
Then, you'll bring the meatball home
and save it for years.
- Mom?
- Neither. Just wear your coat.
But your flower's just a little smushed.
Rory?
There you go. You're all set.
Is anyone here?
- You all right?
- Yeah. You look beautiful. Go.
Lane?
My God!
- I just can't believe it!
- I know.
Three months!
That's like one sixty-fourth of your life!
I have to stop hanging out with you.
You're making my life seem too pathetic.
Join the club.
Are you going to the festival?
We could meet you there later.
That would be romantic.
I'm going to the festival,
and would you like to know why?
- My mother has set me up again.
- Another future doctor?
A future chiropractor.
She's losing confidence in my prospects.
- Maybe he'll be nice.
- It's not just him.
We're going with his parents,
his grandparents...
two sisters, three brothers,
and at least one maiden aunt.
That's Dean.
Remember,
you have to tell me everything.
Okay, you, too.
Yeah, after the walking, the silence,
the sitting, and the bye-bye...
then the fun will begin.
I want to know, anyhow.
- Bye, Mom.
- Bye, honey. Have fun.
Don't forget the meatball.
- The meatball?
- It's a mother-daughter thing.
So, think I could hang out with you
for a while?
Not unless you want to go to Hartford.
Besides, didn't anyone ever tell you...
it's not polite to keep
15 prospective Korean in-laws waiting.
You could run over me. Maybe my mother
wouldn't make me go if I was in hospital.
- I wouldn't count on it.
- You're right.
You're late.
- How did you do that?
- What?
Answer the door
before I even rang the bell?
I thought I heard something.
I came to the door. You were there.
Come in, please.
- You thought you heard something?
- Yes.
- Mom, that door is, like, 10 feet thick.
- So?
It wasn't like I was standing out there
with a band of jackals.
I was just drinking coffee.
Lorelai, what is it that you want to hear?
That I was standing by the window,
staring out at the driveway...
waiting to pounce
the moment you arrived?
Yes, because believe it or not,
that would be less creepy.
Get yourself a drink, please.
Hey, Dad.
- Lorelai.
- Sorry I'm late.
I was helping Rory get ready
for her big date...
and, well, you know girls.
- How's work?
- Work is fine.
Yeah? Good.
My work's fine, too.
Oh, God.
Mom has gone a little crazy
with the figurines here.
A little Kathy Bates?
You probably haven't seen Misery,
which is a good thing.
'Cause Rory couldn't sleep alone
for a week after we watched it.
That wouldn't be a problem for you.
You don't sleep alone.
I'm guessing. I don't know what
your and Mom's sleeping arrangement is.
Now I'm wishing I hadn't brought it up...
because it's a don't-want-to-go-there
subject for me.
Not for you, because you should
definitely go there if you...
Well, anyway...
What have you done now?
I'm putting the bunny back
with his little friends...
and I just sort of massacred them
a little bit.
- But, that's life in the jungle, isn't it?
- Just sit down, please.
Okay. Sorry.
- Just sit with your hands in your lap.
- Sorry.
And I'm trying to read.
So please, just be quiet,
and try not to break anything else.
We having a nice chat?
We're having a great conversation,
me and Morrie.
- Excuse me?
- Nothing.
Thanks for letting Rory out of dinner.
She really appreciated it.
She deserves to celebrate.
A three-month anniversary
is a landmark feat at her age.
Or at any age, for some people.
I was gonna get a drink.
I'm gonna get right on that.
I'll get that.
- Can I freshen up your drink, Dad?
- No, thank you.
One drink before dinner is quite enough.
Right. Sorry.
- I had no idea it was so close.
- Absolutely. Right around the corner.
What a small world.
Lorelai, I'd like you
to meet Chase Bradford.
He was telling me that he grew up
right around the corner from here.
- Really?
- Stone house on the corner.
- The one with the Dobermans.
- That's right. Leopold and Loeb.
I'm afraid they passed on a few years ago.
Postmen finally got organized?
Chase, this is my husband, Richard.
- How do you do?
- Fine, Richard. Just fine.
Please, sit down.
I didn't know we were having company
for dinner.
It was just a spur-of-the-moment thing.
Chase's mother and I
are in the DAR together...
and he's moved back to Hartford.
It seemed like a nice idea.
Yes, very nice.
Can I get you a drink?
A Scotch, neat.
- Glenfiddich?
- Fine.
Your mother's told me all about you.
- Really?
- Yes.
I'm just sorry your daughter couldn't
join us for dinner. I adore children.
Mom, could I talk to you for a minute?
- We have company.
- It'll just take a second, really.
- But...
- Come on, it'll be fun.
Excuse us. We're gonna have
a spur-of-the-moment conversation.
You're pushing me.
- Is this a setup?
- What?
Connecticut Ken in there.
Is he my invited escort for the evening?
- His mother is a friend of mine.
- And?
He just moved back here.
He doesn't know anyone.
And?
And I thought he might enjoy meeting you.
Put that finger down.
This is why the Miss Congeniality act
when Rory wanted to beg out of dinner.
It seemed like a good opportunity.
Mom, thank you for the thought,
but I can get my own men.
- Really?
- Yes, really.
- I must disagree.
- You must?
Chase is a quality man.
He has good breeding.
He comes from a nice family.
He makes a nice living.
- He's attractive.
- Mom, no.
Is it gonna kill you
to keep an open mind about him?
- He is not my type.
- Why not? Because I like him?
I don't know which one,
but there is a game show out there...
with your name on it.
That must be it.
You've hardly said two words to him.
You couldn't hate him already.
It's the game where the mole
keeps sticking his head out.
You have to pound him with the mallet.
You would be a master at that.
Chase may not be as controversial
as your usual brand of men.
They'd erect your statue of you
next to it with perfect hair...
pearls and a bronze mallet.
I want you to think about something.
Tonight, your daughter is celebrating
her three-month anniversary.
What was the last relationship you had
that lasted that long?
I thought so.
Here we are and very sorry.
I had a chance to tell Richard
what I do in the actuarial business.
Yes. It's fascinating.
Lorelai, may I fix you something to drink?
- Gin.
- And?
Gin.
Make that two.
What about
the one-drink-before-dinner rule?
We have guests. We're celebrating.
Chase, here. Let me help you with that.
That was really good.
- It was?
- Yes, it was.
- How was the salad?
- Great.
What about that cheese bread thing?
Too heavy?
- Just heavy enough.
- Really?
Everything was perfect.
Even the soda was good.
I don't know how they do it...
but the Coke here is superior
to the Coke anywhere else.
Okay. At what point during that
did you start making fun of me?
I would never make fun of you.
Not after you ordered three kinds of pasta
because I couldn't decide.
You shouldn't have to decide.
Tonight you should have everything
you want.
I just have to say that I am now
a big fan of the three-month anniversary.
- Yeah?
- Definitely.
They should have T-shirts and newsletters.
I'm glad.
You did all this for me?
It's not over yet.
This is just like that Christmas that
I got a full set of illustrated encyclopedias.
I wanted them.
Good.
One tiramisu, two forks...
- and one meatball to go.
- Thank you.
- You want to explain the meatball?
- It's a mother-daughter thing.
- Ladies first.
- Thank you.
Okay. Have I mentioned...
how much I'm loving
the three-month anniversary thing?
- Yeah, you did.
- Because this tiramisu is so good...
that if the anniversary were completely
sucking right now, this would save it.
- What?
- Nothing.
- Stop it.
- No, you look cute.
- I'm eating.
- You eat cute.
I do not eat cute. No one eats cute.
Bambi, maybe, but he's a cartoon.
After we finish here, we move on
to phase two of the anniversary evening.
Phase two. Sounds very official.
Are there spacesuits involved?
- With matching helmets.
- Impressive.
- Are you a member of the DAR?
- No, I'm not.
D- A-R-N.
It's, like, darn, 'cause it's a play on DAR.
Boy, these carrots sure are tiny.
Chase, I'm simply fascinated
about your work situation.
Tell us how you wound up
back here at home.
You move away to make your fortune,
you end up right back here.
- Isn't life funny?
- Hilarious.
It's a comedy for the masses.
I worked hard
and the company was very good to me.
You know a thing or two
about company loyalty, I assume, Richard.
The company offered me a choice
of East Coast locations.
Sort of a big vote of confidence
in the job I was doing.
Picking your locale.
It's a very coveted position to be in.
I would like to be picking
my locale right now.
So I sat down and made my wish list.
I looked for places that offered
location amenities as well as job growth.
Finally, after days of research...
checking into traffic conditions,
crime rates...
the best school systems,
my decision came down to two places.
One was in New York
and one was in Hartford.
- And you chose Hartford.
- I did at that.
- Is there any more roast?
- Hartford has all the...
cosmopolitan, big-city benefits
New York has...
without actually having to live
in New York.
It just seemed like a no-brainer.
- I'll get Dad some more roast.
- Lee will bring it.
But it's so much more personal this way.
Hurry back.
I just have to know what the allure
of this Stars Hollow is...
I've heard so much about.
Just miles and miles.
- What book did you bring?
- What?
You always bring a book,
and I was just wondering...
what's the three-month anniversary book?
I brought The New Yorker.
- A magazine. Really?
- It's the fiction issue.
People of Stars Hollow,
and our many friends.
It gives me great pleasure
to preside over...
our annual Founders Firelight Festival...
for the 32nd time.
Many a true love has had its start...
right on the spot where I stand.
And I don't mind telling you...
that at this very festival,
right by this gazebo...
is where I met my own true love...
Miss Dora Braithwaite.
We have been married for 43 years...
and it all started right here.
- Ask her to wave.
- I can't.
Why not?
She went to bingo in Bridgeport.
And now, my friends...
if you will join me in lighting the fire.
Okay, take me to the surprise now.
- But you said you want to see the bonfire.
- I do.
- Mayor Porter said...
- Trust me, it'll take a while before it's lit.
We'll have plenty of time
before they're ready.
No, I don't have them.
- Every damn year!
- It was Lenny's responsibility!
Oh, for Pete's sake!
Does anyone have any matches?
Oh, my God!
It's really fascinating stuff.
It sounds it. Tell us more.
We're building new statistical models
that let us do a better job...
of predicting death
than we've ever been able to do.
You might find this interesting.
I've never been one for sitting
at a computer building models.
I'm a client-contact man myself.
But these models give you
a better product to sell to those clients.
- That does sound interesting.
- It is.
If you answer a few simple questions...
I could practically pinpoint the day
you're going to die.
Goodness.
Go ahead. Ask her the questions.
I think I'll pass.
No, Lorelai...
I'd have to feed the information
into a computer to get the answer.
I'm no Kreskin.
Why don't you and Lorelai retire
to the living room for some brandy...
while I help Lee to clean up?
While you do what?
That sounds lovely. Shall we?
Sure. I'm just going...
to go and powder my something.
I'll be back soon.
I'll meet you in the living room.
- I'll be waiting.
- Super.
Lorelai, your mother wants to know if...
Hi, Daddy.
I know this is bad.
I know this brings back all the horrible
aspects of my childhood life for you.
I'm really sorry that we fought last week.
I'm sorry you're disappointed in me.
I wish there was some way I could fix that.
But there isn't, and I accept that
because I am an adult now...
and I am proud of who I have become.
But I am begging you, please
do not make me go back down there...
because that guy is boring.
Emily, she's not up here!
Thank you, Daddy.
- We're here.
- We're where?
- Come on.
- What is this?
- Okay, did you ever see Christine?
- Yes.
It's nothing like that. Come on.
- You brought me to Beirut?
- It's a salvage yard.
And yet it looks so much like Beirut.
Okay, here we are.
- It's a car.
- It is?
- It will be.
- When it grows up?
- When I fix it.
- What?
- It's yours.
- What do you mean it's mine?
I'm building it piece by piece for you.
- No.
- Yeah. I started with the frame.
The seats and the windshield
went in yesterday.
- You're building me a car?
- It's gonna take a while.
But when I'm done, it'll be great.
- You're building me a car?
- That's right.
I'm building you a car.
This is crazy. Why would you do this?
I don't know. You didn't have one.
You're completely insane.
I didn't want you wasting time
on the bus anymore.
That is valuable time we could be
arguing about your ongoing obsession...
with very confusing Russian authors.
I can't believe this.
Do you like it?
Do I like it? Are you kidding?
- I'll take that as a yes.
- Take it, mister.
Come on, get in.
- I'll fix that.
- Don't. I like it like that.
- This is amazing.
- I'm glad you like it.
I had no idea that three months
was the car anniversary.
Four months, you get a plane.
Boy, relationships sure have changed
since I was a kid.
I'm having
one of those moments right now.
What moments?
One of those moments when everything
is so perfect and so wonderful...
that you almost feel sad because
nothing can ever be this good again.
Basically, I'm depressing you?
Yup.
- You're very weird.
- And you're wonderful.
- Rory.
- Yeah?
I love you.
Did you hear me?
Say something.
I love the car.
- And that's it?
- No, I just...
I'm surprised. I didn't expect...
You don't love me?
No, I just have to think about it
for a minute.
Think about what?
Saying 'I love you'
is a really difficult thing.
- I just did it.
- And you did it really well.
What the hell does that mean?
I'm sorry. Please.
This totally came as a surprise.
With the dinner and the car
and then the...
- I need a minute to think about it.
- This is not something you think about.
This is something
that you either feel or you don't.
Please don't be mad.
Why? Because I say, 'I love you,'
and you want to think about it?
Go home and discuss it with your mother,
make one of your pro-con lists?
Not fair.
I'm sorry.
I'm an idiot.
I don't even know what I was thinking.
Please. It's just not that easy for me.
Saying 'I love you' means a lot.
Think about it from my point of view.
My mom and our life.
My mom said that she loved my dad...
You don't get pregnant
saying 'I love you. '
I know.
I'm just confused. I need to...
It's a really big deal.
- Fine, come on.
- Dean, please don't be mad.
I'll take you home.
Tonight was amazing. It was perfect.
- Please, I swear, I just need a minute...
- Whatever.
It doesn't matter, all right? Let's go.
- Sookie.
- Yes, Jackson?
You know what I'm thinking right now?
That time I roasted some red peppers
over the stove burner...
and singed off my eyebrows?
- No.
- Good.
I'm just thinking, this is really nice.
Me, too.
- You getting some good stuff?
- Yeah.
The firelight really changes people.
Makes them seem happier, freer,
all the troubles completely gone.
I don't think that's the firelight.
I think it's the Founders' Day party punch.
Yeah, that stuff is good.
At some point, are you gonna tell me
what you're doing here?
I'm putting more film in my camera.
What?
I told you, I was at the airport,
and now I'm here.
Sure, when you put it like that.
Correct me if I'm wrong,
but you don't sound happy to see me.
Correct me if I'm wrong, but you have
a tendency to show up and leave suddenly.
Not one of your more charming attributes.
So you're not happy to see me?
I don't know what I'm doing here, okay?
I just missed you.
I wanted to see you.
I don't know what else to say.
I missed you, too.
Since we're both being blunt...
what's the deal with Lorelai?
- What are you talking about?
- Lorelai...
the lady who runs the inn,
and you've told me nothing about.
Been very careful to leave out of any story,
anecdote, or gossip about the town.
- There is no deal with her. We're friends.
- For now.
- Yes.
- And in the future?
She's just...
At times, it seems like...
I don't know.
But I am happy to see you.
Good.
I'm gonna get some party punch.
You want some?
That stuff will kill you.
Some things never change.
Where's the fire department
when you need them?
Aren't you supposed to be in Hartford?
I climbed out the window.
- That's it? You're not curious why?
- No.
That's what I love about you.
- How long have you been here?
- A little while.
Did you see Taylor and Harry
get into a fistfight?
- How did I miss that? I'm so bummed.
- It was good.
Where is Rachel?
She's a Founders' Party punch junkie.
Even the nice girls aren't safe.
She's been running around here,
taking all kinds of pictures.
- She's having a good time.
- I guess so. I hope so.
What's the haps with you two?
The haps? Let's see.
What is the haps?
- I mean, like...
- I know what you meant by 'the haps. '
- You're repeating it a thousand times.
- I was pondering.
- You ponder so slowly.
- Lf I did it fast, it wouldn't be pondering.
Pondering by nature
has a slow connotation.
Okay, fine.
- Is she staying?
- I don't know.
- Do you want her to?
- She seems to really like you.
- Yeah, she does.
But she doesn't have
the greatest attention span.
- But she is here.
- Yes, she is.
You spend a lot of time debating things.
Is it right, is it wrong?
Should I do this, should I do that?
Sometimes you should just jump in,
and take a shot.
What's the worst that can happen?
She left before. I lived.
Maybe this time...
- I think that's really great.
- You do?
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
- I guess I'm gonna go check up on Rachel.
- That's nice.
What?
That you have somebody
you can go check up on. That's nice.
Yeah, it is, unless she's completely drunk
and throwing up.
Still nice.
- I'll see you tomorrow?
- Tomorrow.
Hi. You've reached Max Medina.
I'm not here now.
Leave a message at the beep...
and I'll get back to you. Thanks.
We just broke up.
www.tvsubtitles.net