Is there something long and sharp
sticking out of my head?
No.
I want there to be. There's an effect.
I need a cause.
The cause was 10 giant shots
of tequila, sweetie.
It makes me woozy just hearing that.
Well, that's the price you pay for
being the hit of Lane's wedding.
Hit? I was a raving lunatic.
And that toast-- Oh, my god!
Loudest sound ever.
Sorry.
Don't worry about the toast.
And you weren't a lunatic.
You were a character.
What is Stars Hollow if not a haven
for colorful characters?
You're not up there with Stevie
the pantsless Santa Claus
or Jojo the cow whisperer,
but you made some strides.
Is this supposed to be a consolation?
That's twice in 20 seconds, Fred.
Sorry.
I've seen you wasted before
but never like this.
We had you guzzling coffee, but coffee
was making you energetically wasted.
I should borrow the reception video to
see what a fool I made out of myself.
And check out your audition.
My what?
You want a piece of me, omelet boy?
Why don't you let the vegetables simmer
for a while? I'll look after them.
Sure, Sookie.
Sorry, Fred. I'm not myself this morning.
So, now,
what did I do in front of the camera?
When you spotted the videographer,
you got suddenly very excited
to film your audition tape for
"America's next top model."
- Oh, my god!
- Yeah.
- I thought that was a dream.
- It wasn't.
The posing, the strutting,
the inappropriate gyrating?
All caught on video and several of
Zach's buddies' camera phones.
Why didn't you stop me?
I tried. We all tried,
but you were on a mission.
You kept saying,
"I'm not here to make friends.
I want to win."
- And then after that--
- There's an "after that"?
You tried to start a limbo contest,
a poker game,
and a secret club for supercool
party people only.
None of those really took off,
especially the limbo,
considering your choice of limbo stick
was Zach's great-uncle's cane.
Oh, yeah, is he okay?
He stumbled, but we caught him. He's fine.
So, is that all?
Anything else I need to know about?
Nope, after you crowned yourself
arm-wrestling champion of the world,
Christopher and Rory scooped
you up and got you home.
He got you in bed okay?
Christopher? Yeah. He and Rory.
He's very "knight in shining
armor," very chivalrous.
That's him.
So, is there anything else I did that I need
to know about? I want to be fully informed.
- I told you everything.
- Good.
Now, if you'll excuse me, I'm gonna go
and be nauseous out front for a while.
Excellent. Supercool party people
bid you supercool adieu!
That's how you were saying goodbye
to people at the wedding.
Super.
Excuse me, I'm looking for Logan Huntzberger.
Excuse me, can you help me find Logan--
Sorry, this isn't my floor.
Excuse me, can someone here help
me find Logan Huntzberger?
He was just transferred out of the I.C.U.,
room 713.
How is he?
- Are you family?
- I'm his girlfriend.
All I can tell you is that he's
not conscious right now
and that he's in serious
but stable condition.
What does that mean, "serious but stable"?
Just what it says.
But is it more serious or stable? I mean,
which way is it leaning?
I'm sorry, I can only release more
information to family members.
But I'm his girlfriend. I mean,
we've been together a long time.
It's not a casual thing. We live together.
Sorry.
How is he? Is he okay?
Scuttlebutt is he's not dead.
The man is indestructible.
Dives headfirst off the cliffs of Caldera,
instantly spins out of control.
Gets totally disoriented,
barely gets his chute open.
Bounces off every rock and crag in the park.
Yet still manages to stick the landing.
We gave him a 9.7.
Had to deduct.
3 for all the screaming and bleeding.
What about his family? Did you talk to them?
Honor is on her honeymoon in Mykonos,
trying to get a flight back,
and Logan's mom checked herself into some
sort of spa in Arizona the moment she heard.
When the going gets tough,
the tough get hot-rock massages.
What about Mitchum?
The Dark lord?
We left word but haven't heard anything back.
But we've come up with a plan to get around
the whole "family only gets
information" thing.
We're adopting him.
What?
Logan will make a fine son.
Of course, first we must be married.
Naturally, darling. I'm very old-fashioned.
And even then,
adopting as a gay couple is never easy.
We just want to give love.
- Oh, Finn.
- Oh, buttercup.
What the hell is wrong with you two?
Your best friend is lying unconscious in
a hospital, and you don't even care.
Rory...
Why the hell aren't you two lying
unconscious in there, huh?
Come on.
You don't care, because if you did,
you wouldn't be like this. You couldn't.
You're supposed to have his back,
you're supposed to watch out
for each other on these
stupid trips of yours.
But no, everything's a big joke.
Everything's hilarious.
You're useless. Just go home. Both of you,
go home.
I can't stand to look at you.
- Hi.
- Hello.
I'm Rory Gilmore. I'm his girlfriend.
I'm Dr. Schultz.
How is he? Is he gonna be okay?
I'm sorry,
but I really can't get into the specifics.
Well, he's out of the I.C.U.,
so that's good, right?
They wouldn't have moved him up
here unless he was recovering.
Sorry, really.
But he's had surgery, right?
Does he need more surgery?
Does he have broken bones?
Because I can donate blood if you want.
Miss.
You really...
You can't tell me anything about what he has
or what you've done or what's
wrong-- anything?
I'm sorry. It's hospital policy.
We're doing everything we can.
Okay.
# A million hearts, a million minds #
# Have lived and died in 40 years #
# Prayed for yourself and for your memories #
# Be thankful we've had 40 years #
# We've had 40 years #
I will get that for you in
two shakes of a lambstick.
Caesar, why am I still finding
bananas in the fridge?
Oh, you wanted me to take all the
bananas out of the fridge?
Yes. When I said, "remove the bananas,"
I was referring to all the bananas.
Otherwise, I would have said "banana,
or some of the bananas."
What?
It's just that while I was running the place,
that was one of my innovations--
cold bananas. People really love them.
I highly doubt that.
And get rid of those scones.
You know, that's something else I wanted
to talk to you about, Luke.
- What?
- Your attitude.
See, while I was running the place,
people really responded to my sunny demeanor.
Customers find you cold and distant.
Service with a smile-- it's
a cliché for a reason.
Look, Caesar, I don't want to improve things,
and I don't want to stop
being cold to customers.
I just want you to keep my damn
bananas out of the damn fridge,
and I want to keep my damn doughnuts
in the damn doughnut case.
- Can you do that for me?
- Of course, Luke.
Thank you.
Customers don't care for gratuitous
profanity, either.
Thank god, someone sane.
Hello, weary traveler.
It's good to be back.
You look older, wiser.
Well, I did spend a lot of time squinting
at historical documents.
That's what it is-- constitution face.
Hi, Patty.
I brought you something.
Oh, did you steal me the constitution?
'Cause that could be the start
of a really dumb movie.
It's from Amish country.
These little Amish girls handmake them.
Oh, it's adorable.
Look, Patty, an Amish voodoo doll.
I love it.
Hey, Luke,
I'm still waiting on my cold banana.
We don't serve cold bananas.
It's not a voodoo doll. It's just a doll.
The Amish don't put faces on
their dolls or pins in them.
Oh, well, it's my doll now.
What the Amish don't know won't hurt them.
Unless, of course, I want to hurt them.
It's yours to do with what you will.
So, you seem surprisingly rested
after all you've been through.
Yeah, the kids were okay.
They seemed to like me,
unless they were all lying.
Kids never lie.
And April and I finally
got into a good rhythm.
She was tolerating me pretty good at the end.
Good.
And guess what? It's her birthday tomorrow,
and I'm throwing her a party.
You're kidding. How did that happen?
Well, I was dropping her off this morning,
and her mom mentioned to me
that she was taking her to her
grandmother's to celebrate,
and she couldn't swing a party
here with her friends,
so I figured I know her friends now.
I got a great place to hold a party.
Yeah, where?
Here.
So, anyhow, there you go.
Look at you, diving into fatherhood.
I'm doing my best.
So, tomorrow, huh? You prepared for all that?
Sure. Why?
Well, if you need a consultant, I have thrown
some rockin' preteen parties in my time.
Of course, I didn't have a deep fryer.
I think I can handle it.
I'll put up some decorations.
I've ordered some balloons.
I got a great cake place. It'll be presents.
All good. I'm just saying that Rory's
birthday scavenger hunt of 1998
is still talked about in hushed,
reverent tones.
Is that the one where all the kids ended
up at Taylor's at 11:00 at night
stealing stuff out of his fridge?
Shh! Hushed, reverent tones.
Yeah, I've got it all under control.
Excuse me.
What can I get you, Kirk?
How about a steaming cup of chicory coffee?
It's not on the menu, Kirk.
I know. It's on the sign.
That's a mistake.
Well, now all I can think about is chicory
coffee. I'm very susceptible to signage.
Well, come back when you're susceptible
to ordering off the menu.
You want anything?
How about a nice plate of chicken fingers?
Why don't I start you off
with some coffee, hmm?
Uh, no, thanks. I'm kind of coffee'd out.
Oh, right. Battling the hangover.
Oh. Did I mention my hangover?
No, Patty filled me in, you know.
The tequila shots, you taking the mike.
Taking the mike. Uh, yeah.
I, um-- I really didn't know
what I was saying--
just empty,
meaningless words tumbling out of my mouth.
I hear you really belted it out.
Belted it out?
"Endless Love."
The song, honey.
Ohh... yeah.
Oh, yes. I really belted it out.
Is there any other way to
sing "Endless Love"?
You know,
if you're not gonna really belt it out,
you might as well stay in your seat.
She sang it beautifully.
Everybody does embarrassing
stuff at weddings.
Yeah, right, true.
Be right back.
Okay, I've already gotten to the whole town,
and they're all telling the "Endless
Love" story. He'll never know.
Oh, thanks. I owe you, Patty.
Honey, please. I've given more drunken
toasts than Colin Farrell.
You owe me nothing.
Thanks, Patty.
That Luke.
It may take a mule team,
but you're getting him to the altar someday.
Yeah, someday.
What?
Paris?
Larry Summers is right, Rory.
Our university system is crumbling,
did you know that?
Paris...
I just found out my microbiology
final is an open-book exam.
Can you believe that?
I mean, why have us take the test at all?
Why not just have our professors
take it for us?
Or better yet,
they can just hand us our diplomas
the moment we step on campus freshman year,
along with some government cheese, a bong,
and a t-shirt that says "hard
work is for suckers."
Paris, I'm at the hospital with Logan.
Why? What happened?
He and his buddies went on some stupide
Life and Death Brigade trip,
and they parachuted off
a cliff in Costa Rica,
and he had a really bad fall.
- Is he okay?
- I don't know.
He's out of the I.C.U.,
so I guess that's a good thing.
They said he's in serious
but stable condition,
but they won't tell me anything
else because I'm not family.
Is he breathing on his own?
Yeah-- I mean, I think so.
What's his pallor? Is he peaked?
Was there internal bleeding?
I have no idea. I quickly scribbled
down some things off his chart.
You're pre-med, can I read it to you?
Maybe you can make some sense of it.
Forget it.
I don't know how to read charts yet.
I can tell you everything you wanna
know about the difference
between recessive and dominant eye-color
genes in fruit flies,
but god forbid I learn how to read a chart
before I'm a fourth-year surgical resident.
Great.
What hospital is he in?
Columbia-Presbyterian, Manhattan.
Who's the attending?
Paris, it doesn't matter. They're not gonna
release information to nonfamily.
Just give me the name.
Dr. Schultz.
I'll call you right back.
Paris.
Please!
That language is certainly not necessary!
Hold on.
It's about Logan Huntzberger.
This is Dr. Schultz.
No, that's not possible.
Well, you wouldn't do that.
Listen, miss-- fine.
Hello?
Here is the deal. He was bleeding internally
when they brought him in,
and they were worried about the
oxygen levels in his blood,
but he's stabilized now,
and they're back up to normal,
so that's no longer a concern.
He was also running a high fever,
so they put him on mondo doses
of intravenous antibiotics.
He has a partially collapsed lung...
Oh, my god!
...Six broken ribs, a broken ankle,
torn cartilage in both knees,
and a severe concussion.
He had surgery for the lung,
and that went well.
They did a thoracoscopy, which is a couple
of small incisions in the chest.
Then they put a tube into the lung
to drain the fluid from the poral
space so the lung can re-expand.
That's way less invasive than a thoracotomy
which is a similar operation.
But for that one,
they have to butterfly you like a shrimp.
And that's it.
So, what does this mean?
It means he's out of immediate danger.
He's young and healthy,
and they expect him to make a full recovery.
Really? Like a full recovery,
like he's going to recover fully?
That's what the doctor told me.
He'll need some rehab,
he won't be running, dancing,
or jumping off a cliff anytime soon,
but, yeah, he should be fine.
He's a very lucky guy. He could have died.
Those guys are idiots.
- Wow.
- Yeah.
Thank you so much for this. Really, Paris,
thank you.
It was fun. Anything else?
No, I feel a lot better.
Call me if you need anything else.
I will.
So, you all shopped out?
I got a couple more stores in me.
You would make the best
sherpa and the hottest.
You could move to Nepal,
open your own hot-sherpa shop,
and make a fortune.
This is fun for me. Besides, I like to think
I have some influence on what you buy.
- You do?
- I don't?
- No.
- Yes, I do.
No, you don't.
- I do.
- You don't.
But you're always asking my opinion.
Yeah, but it's the way I ask.
"Isn't this adorable?"
Or "this isn't right, right?"
You know, I put your answer right
there in the question.
I will say, I do always like to buy one
thing that you like that I don't
'cause I know it makes you happy,
like that blouse.
You know, I thought you liked that.
Not really,
but I liked how much you liked it,
so I bought it.
And I will wear it because I
know that every time I do,
you'll notice and appreciate it,
and that will make me feel so good.
And then because I feel so good,
I'll start wearing it more and more,
and I'll eventually really grow to like it,
and I'll forget that I didn't really
like it in the first place.
Holy crap,
you've picked out all my favorite clothes.
I knew it.
Hey, what do you think of that?
- What?
- The toiletry kit.
What? And throw away the 5-year-old dixie cup
you use to hold your toothbrush?
It's historical.
I mean as a birthday present for April.
- April who?
- Come on, it's cute.
Um, yeah. I don't think it's quite right.
It's girly. It's got cats on it.
- Oh, well, if it's got cats on it--
- April likes cats.
Yeah, but it's a toiletry kit.
It's so hygienic.
I saw her use soap on the trip.
Yeah, did you see her tie her shoelaces?
'Cause you could get her shoelaces.
I think she'll like it.
Luke, it's weird. It says,
"happy birthday-- now go clean yourself up."
If she doesn't like it,
I'll get her a follow-up gift.
Why not just get her the perfect
gift right up front?
Why couldn't that be the perfect gift?
You don't know.
I know girls. It's not the right gift.
Hey, you know, there's a store a few
blocks down that has great stuff.
I could take you there and show you
50 things I know she'd like.
Some of them may even have cats on them.
I think I'm gonna get that.
Come on, Luke, I can really help you here.
I'm not saying you can't,
I know you're an expert,
but I need to do this.
Then do it. I'm just saying,
let me be part of it.
No.
Why?
Because it's too soon.
Why is it too soon?
Because the minute you get involved in
her life, it'll be all over for me.
What? That's ridiculous.
No, it's not ridiculous.
You're colorful and funny.
You're practically a cartoon character.
Kids love you.
I wouldn't hang out with me
either after meeting you.
Luke--
She'll like you better. That is just a fact.
No, you're her dad.
Yes, I am her dad,
and this is the way I want it to be.
Okay.
I'll be a couple of minutes.
I'll be right here.
So you have my cellphone
if there's any problems?
I've got your cell number, your store number,
your store fax number,
your home number. You are 100% reachable.
Good.
And, hey,
thanks again for letting me do this.
Oh, please. She's excited about this.
Plus, your chaperoning got rave reviews.
Really?
April said you were by far the
least-embarrassing parent on the trip.
Good. That's good, right?
It's a rave.
Her friends call you Hagrid.
Really? Hagrid. Wow.
I don't know what that means.
He's a character from "Harry Potter"--
very big, very hairy, very lovable.
It's a huge compliment.
I will take your word for it.
So, I'm gonna go now.
Have fun, and I'll talk to you later tonight.
Will do.
- I'm going, April.
- Yeah, yeah, bye, mom.
- That was from the heart.
- Totally.
Bye again.
And the diner looks really great.
I was here when you opened it, remember?
I remember.
Bye.
Okay, can I get everyone's attention
for a moment here?
Just go ahead and pull your chairs
around so everyone can see me.
Is this a game?
No, no games right now. Just gather.
All right, I'm Luke. Some of you know me.
I'm April's dad.
So, um, before we get the party started,
I just wanted to lay down some ground rules--
some simple dos and don'ts--
so that everybody has a good time
and goes home in one piece.
Okay.
So, this is the party area.
You are to remain in the
party area at all times.
The kitchen is strictly off limits.
Under no circumstances are
you to enter the kitchen.
It's incredibly dangerous back there.
One turn of the wrong dial,
you could burn your face off.
And I've got so many knives back there,
you so much as trip,
you could lose an arm,
you could chop off fingers,
you could poke out an eye.
And do not go upstairs.
That is not part of the party area.
Everyone must remain in the
party area at all times.
And finally, do not go outside.
I will not give anybody permission
to go outside, okay?
Are we clear?
- All right.
- Yes, sir.
Well, good, then that's all I've got.
So have fun.
Is he serious?
Is that our website?
It is.
What happened to it?
I made some modifications.
It's just a big picture of you.
Well, I figured since I'm the one
who put the website together
and I'm the one continuously
updating the website,
then I should be featured prominently
on the website.
Featured? Sure. But where's the Inn?
All I see is your face.
Aha! If you want to hear about the Inn,
you click on my mouth.
See? And if you want pictures of the Inn,
you click on my eyes.
And if you want to post something about
the Inn, you click on my ears.
Clever, no?
You want to argue about this now or later?
Later. I'm having too much fun.
Hello.
It's me.
Hey, how is he?
Well, I'm told he's going to be fine,
but he looks awful,
and he's been unconscious the whole time
I've been here. It's really scary.
What happened?
He basically jumped off a cliff,
and his parachute barely opened.
Oh my god!
Yeah, he has six broken ribs,
a collapsed lung,
a broken ankle,
contusions over 1/3 of his body,
and a concussion.
Wow. Who else is there? What other family?
Colin and Finn were here for a while,
but none of his family's here.
How did you get all that information? I
thought they only allowed family members to--
- Paris.
- God love her.
I'm sorry I didn't call sooner.
I got your messages.
I've just been so overwhelmed.
I'm just glad to hear from you.
Is there anything I can do,
anything you need?
It's been a while since I've
sent out a care package.
You could be up to your eyeballs in mad libs,
silly string, malted milk balls.
No, I'm good.
Colin and Finn went back to New
Haven to get some stuff for me.
I'm just gonna hang out here for a while.
Logan is awake if you want to see him.
Mom, Logan's awake.
Okay. Call me if there's anything you need.
- Thanks, bye.
- Bye.
- Hey.
You're awake.
Or hallucinating-- pretty good hallucination.
Oh, you're awake.
I must look like crap.
Now I know why you never let
me see you without makeup.
I guess maybe base jumping with very little
preparation wasn't the hottest idea.
You're gonna be fine.
You're gonna make a full recovery.
Hey, Robocop made a full recovery.
Look where that led him.
This is the best hospital in the city,
and the best hospital in New York City is
basically the best hospital in the country,
and that's basically the best
hospital in the world,
so all in all,
you're in the best place you could be,
all things considered.
Hey, what do you think you're doing?
Lay down.
I'm really sorry about this.
- It's okay.
- No, it's not okay.
I was showing off.
I knew it wasn't safe from that cliff.
I was so drunk,
I was lucky I pulled my chute at all.
You're going to be fine, and I will be
here as long as you want me to be.
I've located the gift shop
and the good cafeteria--
"good" being a relative term--
and the maternity ward, in case I want
to play a little practical joke,
swap the newborns around.
What about the paper, school?
I have my laptop.
I can stay on top of my schoolwork.
And Bill can run the paper for a while.
I don't want you to miss too many classes.
You've already got more than enough
to do without having to sit here
Shh. Logan, just relax.
Get some rest. I'll be here.
I'm glad.
So, how we doing? We having fun?
Marcia, you have to discard.
I know, but you only need one card,
and I don't want to give it to you.
What makes you think I only need one card?
Oh, please. You pick up a card and discard
like every half-second. It's so obvious.
Well, it's my birthday. Why don't you
just give me the stupid card I want?
Hey, how do you think the temperature is?
It's fine, I guess.
Are you cold? Maybe it's too cold in here.
How many people are cold, huh?
Anyone too warm?
Okay, well, good to know.
Luke, can I go to the bathroom?
Of course. You don't have to ask permission
to go to the bathroom.
But it's in the restricted area.
I could lose a finger.
Well, the bathroom is not part
of the restricted area.
I didn't mean to include that.
Does anyone else have to go to the bathroom?
Oh, well, all right.
Well, let's line up, okay?
You can use the bathroom one at a time.
Laura, you first.
Thank you.
Uh, I'll be right out. I just have
to check on something in the back.
Dragonfly Inn.
It's a disaster.
What?
The party-- it's a total disaster.
A disaster? Why?
Nothing happened.
It's like a funeral hall in there.
I didn't know 13-year-old girls
could be so unhappy.
Where are you? I don't hear anything.
I'm in the storage room.
I come in here and hide a lot.
And leaving them unsupervised?
Well, there's a peephole
here I can see out of.
You're peeping at the girls
from the storage room?
I do not have time for any weird jokes.
Okay, what are they doing?
Well, April was playing cards. Some of the
others were reading and playing video games.
At the moment,
they're all just standing in line,
waiting to go to the bathroom.
You didn't plan any activities?
It's a birthday party.
I thought that was the activity.
Oh, Luke.
Is it normal for kids to fall
asleep at a birthday party?
Luke, listen. Are you listening?
Yes.
Go upstairs and get your clock radio.
Why, so we can watch the minutes
of the world's worst birthday
party tick off one by one?
No. Go, get it, bring it downstairs and put
on some music-- KC101. I'll be right over.
You're coming here?
Just stall for time,
I have some things to finish up,
and then I'll come over, if it's okay?
What?
Is it okay that I come over?
Yes, Lorelai, come! Hurry!
Okay, I'll hurry.
Hurry faster.
They might start leaving or something.
Okay, bye.
Hey.
So, it got worse after we hung up.
We got the radio?
I forgot the radio part was broken,
and the buzzer alarm went off at one point.
But that didn't last long,
I think it's too late.
It's not too late.
I swear I heard the word "mutiny"
bandied around in there.
It's not too late. Let's get in there.
But where's the stuff?
- What stuff?
- The party stuff.
Oh, my god,
I left the circus elephants in my car,
and I didn't crack a window.
But seriously, where's the party stuff?
Come on, follow my lead.
Hey, everybody. I'm Lorelai Gilmore.
Thank you so much for your patience.
I'm really glad you guys waited to
start the party until I got here.
Oh, um, that's okay, Lorelai.
We didn't mind, right, girls?
Great. Okay, let's get this party started.
Where's the birthday girl?
Here.
April Nardini, front and center.
You know, I met you briefly.
You were filling salt and pepper shakers.
I remember you.
You were dressed in all black,
and you had really blue eyes.
They aren't quite as blue today but I
think that's just the light though.
These irises are all natural, baby.
All right, everybody,
line up single file behind us.
We already went to the bathroom.
Oh, I know, this is gonna be so much better.
Now, take the hand of the person in front
of you and the person in back of you.
Luke, you pull up the rear.
I'll take the lead.
Sure. What is this?
Just follow me, everybody.
No matter what, do not let go of either hand.
We're not allowed to go outside.
Or in the kitchen.
Or anywhere else.
What?
You are now, girls. We got new rules.
Should we bring our stuff?
No, leave it. We'll be back.
Everybody try to walk at the same pace.
You step on somebody's heels,
you could break an ankle.
And watch out for the traffic-- not
just cars, but bikes.
People in this town ride their
bikes like maniacs.
- Luke!
- Sorry.
Oh, check for traffic. Always check. And go!
- Where are we going?
- No idea!
Serpentine, girls, serpentine.
Is this wise to serpentine?
No!
- Hi, Lorelai.
- Hi.
Hey, girls.
All right,
I'd like you to meet the birthday girl.
Hi, April.
- Happy birthday.
- Hello.
You are adorable.
All right, girls. I want you each
to take a basket and fill it up.
I want you to pick anything you want because
today we're getting makeovers.
These two ladies are here to help
you in any way you need.
That's Alison and Leslie.
On your mark, get set, and shop!
You're a genius.
13-year-old girls and makeup-- it's
like betting on secretariat.
Never in a million years would I have
thought of something like this.
That's why I'm the yin to your yang,
the emack to your bolio.
Hey, who wants hot-pink highlights?
I hate that you're cutting
your honeymoon short.
That's okay. With mom flaking out,
I don't want to be here anymore.
We've got seats on a flight tonight,
but it's got a 5-hour layover in Ankara,
so we're trying to find
something more direct.
Either way,
we should be there sometime tomorrow night.
Okay. So, have you heard anything
more from your dad?
Yeah, I just talked to him.
So is he coming down here?
Nope.
He's out of town, too?
No, he's home. He's just not coming.
What?
It's the Life and Death Brigade thing.
He's very against it.
But he was in the Life and Death Brigade.
Yes, but he feels that he knew when to
grow up and accept responsibility
and that Logan doesn't.
He wanted his precious boy done with
that by now, so he's boycotting.
He's boycotting his injured son?
Logan had emergency surgery.
Hypocrisy runs very deep in
the Huntzberger family.
Anyhow, forget it.
I'm sure Logan isn't expecting him.
Okay, so, I'll call later when I
have more flight information.
Okay, bye.
Mitchum Huntzberger?
Yes, it's Rory Gilmore.
I just thought I'd call and remind you
that Logan is lying in a hospital bed
with a partially collapsed lung
and a whole host of other potentially
life-threatening injuries.
And I'm figuring a guy like you,
surrounded by nothing
but a bunch of terrified sycophants might
not have have someone in his life
with the guts to tell him what an incredibly
selfish, narcissistic ass he's being,
so I thought I'd jump on in.
Swallow your pride, get in your car,
and come down here and see your son-- now!
That looks excellent.
Marcia, fabulous. You look like Sophia Loren.
I was going for Vanessa Minnillo on MTV.
Ah, I love her music.
She's a V.J.
No, well, you didn't let me finish,
I love her music-video introductions.
You know, she's so smooth and classy.
- Luke, more chips here.
- Coming.
Lorelai, check this out.
Ooh, cool. Your eyes have eyes.
- Freaky, right?
- Yes.
You could fall asleep in class,
and no one would know.
Lorelai.
Oh, April, you look beautiful.
Leslie says I have excellent bone structure.
Yes, well, I agree with her.
So it's not weird when someone
compliments your skull?
A woman takes any compliment
that comes her way.
Got it. Hey, did you do that
glitter heart on your cheek?
Happens to be my handiwork.
Yeah, you want one?
- Yes.
- All right, sit, sit.
What color would you like-- pink,
blue, purple, florescent green?
Purple. I'm obsessed with purple,
probably because I'm obsessed with
"Harold and the purple crayon."
I know I'm too old, but it's still
one of my all-time-favorite books.
That's okay. I'm too old for us weekly.
It never stopped me.
So, you have a daughter, right?
Yes-- Rory.
That's good. You'd be wasted on a son.
I'm gonna take that as a compliment.
It is. You know, you remind me of my mom.
Is she handy with the glitter?
She painted a mural on my wall
in nail polish one night.
That's cool.
I think you'd like her.
All right, you're all done.
Thanks.
Oh my god, that is so cool. I love it.
Thanks, Marcia.
- She's loving her presents.
- I know.
Okay, how about this one?
It's from your dad.
You know, you don't have to open
up all your presents right away.
You could maybe save a few
and open them tomorrow,
sort of extend the experience.
Bad idea, Hagrid.
I don't want to extend the experience.
Wait, is that my gift?
It says it's from Luke.
The new "way things work."
I was gonna get this.
And a gift certificate to the discovery
store. Thanks, Luke!
I love it!
- Thank you so much!
- You're welcome.
- Thank you.
- My pleasure.
You know what would really push
this party over the top?
If we made it into a sleepover.
Yeah, you've got sleeping bags and blankets.
Plus, I still got Jess' bed.
We could stick a couple of them on that.
Why don't you ask the birthday
girl if she wants to do that?
April, come here a sec.
What's up?
How would you feel about making
this a slumber party?
- Really?
- Really.
Do you guys want to sleep over?
That would be really cool.
Great. First off, we got to call all your
parents to see if it's okay with them. Okay?
So, with that in mind,
why don't we form a single-file
line behind here to the phone?
Or you could use your own, I guess.
So, I think I'm gonna take off.
What? No, stay. You got to stay.
- You're sure?
- It's a slumber party.
You're the slumber-party expert.
What does Hagrid know about slumber parties?
Would it be weird,
the two of us sleeping together?
You and the girls can sleep upstairs.
I'll figure something out.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah, absolutely.
You have to stay. April would want that.
Okay, I'll stay.
The movie's all ready to go.
Okay, thanks, Kirk.
I just need it back for the
Weinstein retirement party.
Mel Weinstein's a nut for John Hughes movies.
Okay.
All right, girls, um, you're about to
meet someone very special to me.
Her name is Molly Ringwald.
Now, I know you don't know who that is,
but suffice it to say,
she is my generation's Audrey Hepburn.
And I know you don't know who that
is, either, but trust me,
you're gonna love her.
And yes,
that is the guy from "Two and a half men."
All right, enjoy.
Light as a feather, stiff as a board.
Light as a feather, stiff as a board...
I forgot how much fun it could
be just to put makeup on.
It's become so pragmatic, such drudgery.
It's like all we use it for
now is to look better.
And why would the two of us
ever need to look better?
Exactly. Whatever happened to the
questionably attractive glories
of wet 'n' wild blue eye shadow
or crimping irons?
Remember sun-in and aqua net
and bonne bell lip smackers?
I used to love bonne bell lip smackers.
Who doesn't love a lip gloss
that doubles as a necklace?
And they smelled so great.
Except once,
I had the chocolate-fudge-flavored one,
and in study hall,
Trevor Fink ate the whole thing,
and then he threw it up all over my
copy of "The red badge of courage."
We all had a Trevor Fink in our lives.
So, it sounds like the party was great.
It was a great party and
a major breakthrough.
April's awesome. I think she liked me.
I bet she loved you.
We bonded. Hopefully, this means things
will change and I won't have to hide.
- Good.
- Yeah.
Luke just needed that time and space,
you know?
And in hindsight,
I think it was good for him,
and I'm really glad I let him have it.
You were incredibly patient.
I was-- incredibly patient,
while at the same time incredibly impatient.
You're a complicated woman.
I am, yes. I try to deny it, but there it is.
I'm kind of sad I wasn't at the party.
I feel like I missed out.
I thought you might feel that way,
so I brought you some leftovers.
Bonne bell lip smackers, anyone?
- No!
- Yes.
I've got original, glitter gloss,
grape crush, and Dr. Pepper.
I feel like I'm 15 again.
Jackson's so getting under my bra tonight.
Oh, my god!
Luke, there's some glitter on my pancakes.
Sorry about that. Let me fix that up for you.
Wasn't any glitter in the food
when I was running the place.
And cut up one of those cold bananas,
will you?
Excuse me, is Luke around?
Yeah, he's here. He's always here.
Hey, Anna, how are you?
Can we talk in private?
Uh, sure. This way.
Caesar, I'm gonna take a couple minutes.
Whatever.
So, what's up?
- I can't believe you did this.
- Did what?
You said you wanted to throw her a party,
Luke-- you.
I know. I did.
No.
You had your girlfriend throw her a party--
a girlfriend I don't even know,
a girlfriend I've never even met.
This is not our agreement.
Wait a minute. I did throw the party.
Lorelai was just helping out.
- Helping out?
- Yes.
April said you spent the night downstairs.
Well, I spent the night in the storage room.
I thought it were a little weird if--
So when you were in the storage room,
your girlfriend was upstairs with the girls.
Yeah.
How am I supposed to explain that
to the other girls' parents?
How am I supposed to tell them
that I left their kids
all alone with a woman I've never even met?
Who does that?
I'm sorry.
I didn't think that it was gonna cause--
If I can't trust you, Luke,
this arrangement is not gonna work.
April is not a sweater that you're borrowing.
She's my kid. I have to know where
she is and who she's with always.
I know. I'm sorry. You can trust me, I swear.
You know what?
I am too mad. I can't even look at you.
Anna.
Hello!
Kitchen!
Thank god. I am so nutrition-deprived.
All I've eaten in the last two
days is cake, candy, cookies,
and about 10 pounds of flavored lip gloss.
Well, then, let's eat.
Good.
Now, do you want to be civilized and eat off
plates or just right out of the containers?
I know you don't approve, but I think
there is some sort of origami thing
happening with these containers that
makes the food taste better in them.
It's like feng shui for noodles.
I'm not just saying that because I'm
lazy and I don't want any cleanup.
That's only part of it.
Out of the containers is fine.
Righteous.
You okay?
Anna came by the diner.
Why? What's up?
She's mad. She's really mad.
- What about?
- The party.
Well, the party was a smash.
About you being at the party.
She says she feels betrayed
because I let you throw
April a birthday party
even though she's never met you.
But you were there the whole time.
We both threw the party.
I know, I told her that,
but I left you alone with them all night
and didn't clear it with her first.
She's really mad about that.
It's not your fault.
I should have seen this coming.
I was stupid. I didn't think it through.
I'm sorry.
Yeah, me too.
I brought some beer,
but I left it in the truck.
Be right back.
Hey.
So, my dad just left.
I saw.
I still can't believe it.
He actually visited.
He was only moderately hostile,
slightly condescending,
and no more self-centered than usual.
It's good that he came. Good for him.
Are you feeling any better?
I am.
Of course, It could have something to do
with the 27 medications they
have me jacked up on.
I checked with the doctor.
It's mostly cough syrup and baby aspirin.
What's wrong? I'm feeling better.
What?
I'm sorry.
About what?
About letting you go on this trip.
I should have stopped you.
I was just so busy being mad at you.
I didn't think I was trying to punish you,
but I was trying to punish you.
No, Rory.
I should have stopped you.
Hey, you couldn't have stopped me.
A team of psychiatrists with tranquilizer
guns couldn't have stopped me.
I was going no matter what. It's my fault.
Do not feel guilty about this.
I just sent you out that door.
I didn't even care.
I was so cold.
I just-- I could have lost you.
- You didn't lose me.
- But I could have, though.
Look, I'm the one screwing things
up with us here, not you.
I'm sorry you're in the hospital right now.
I'm sorry about all of this.
I don't what's going on with me,
but I'll get better, okay?
Things will calm down.
I just need you to bear with me, okay?
Okay?
Okay.
You okay there?
Sorry.
Spreadsheets-- the bane of my existence.
Combines my hatred of math with
my fear of little, tiny boxes.
Well, little, tiny boxes can be scary.
Unless, of course,
they contain big diamond earrings.
I hear you.
- Feel free to look around.
- Thanks.
Have you been in here before?
No, first time. It's lovely-- great stuff.
Thank you.
All the hanging clothes over
there are 20% off--
some of my favorite stuff,
but come march 1st,
I can't sell a sweater to save my life.
Okay, I'll check it out.
You looking for anything in particular?
Uh, yeah-- you, actually.
I'm Lorelai Gilmore. I'm Luke's fiancé.
I wanted to apologize for the party.
It was my fault.
It just wasn't exactly what I was expecting.
I know, and I'm to blame for that, not Luke.
It wasn't his idea.
He was having a little trouble
getting the party going,
and I may have thrown myself
into it a little too much.
I just thought that we should
meet so you could see
you really have nothing to worry about.
She's a 13-year-old girl.
I always have something to worry about.
Well, yeah, of course,
but I meant in regards to me.
Look, I'm sure you're a great person.
I am. I have references.
But I'm a single mom here.
I can't play fast and loose with
the people in my kid's life.
I completely understand.
I'm a single mom myself.
Okay, then you get it. I mean,
what if April decided she likes you?
What if she becomes attached to you?
What if you become her best
friend in the entire world,
and then one day, you just disappear?
Well, that's not gonna happen.
You don't know that.
You can't guarantee that,
and I can't take that chance.
When it comes to my daughter,
I have to have rules--
hard and fast rules.
I would never dream of violating
any of those rules. Believe me.
April never meets any man I date
unless I've dated him for years.
I totally get that.
So basically,
until I'm ready to get married again,
she doesn't meet any of the men I date.
Right.
For all she knows, I'm a nun.
Yeah, I went through a sister
Wendy phase myself once.
I want her to have stability.
Right. But Luke and I-- we are engaged.
We are stable.
Engaged isn't married.
People get engaged all the time.
Look, this is not something casual,
Luke and me.
This is not something we're rushing into,
by any means.
This has been a long time
coming-- a long time.
This is real.
That's wonderful. I'm really happy for you,
but that doesn't change anything.
Luke just came into April's life.
I'm still nervous about that.
He's not a kid guy, never has been,
and she's getting very attached.
I need to know he's sticking around first.
And then, when you're married,
we'll deal with that then.
I'm not trying to be a hardass here.
April's my world.
I don't know if my way is the right way.
I just have to go with my gut.
This is how I want to do it.
You said you're a single mom.
I have a daughter, just like you.
You get where I'm coming from at all?
I really do.
Anyway, thank you for hearing me out.
Sure.
It's no problem.
Okay.
Hey.
If it makes you feel better,
she had a really great time at that party.
I'm glad.
öwww.tvsubtitles.netö