- Ah, Moon pies.
- What?
Well, it's the wonderful part of a
road-trip. Stopping for Moon pies.
Mom, I want to go. I can't.
I know. I know.
End of semester -- lots of work.
Not lots -- tons. I'm sorry.
Yeah, yeah.
- It's just --
- What "it's just"?
Well, it's just, you know, a shame
to miss the wedding of a woman
who meant so much to you.
Mom, I talked to Mia.
I apologized profusely.
I told her that it was simply impossible
for me to drop everything now
and go to North Carolina.
No, right?
- No.
- Yeah.
- She totally understood.
- Of course, she understood.
She understood when I was 17
and I arrived at the Inn,
holding a little,
tiny baby in my arms,
and rain was pouring down.
As long as you're
not milking this.
And she understood when you broke that
teacup of hers, the english rose pattern
- when you were 4.
- Okay, mom.
Yeah, I think that was an antique,
wasn't it? But, oh, she understood.
Hello. Statute of limitations.
You know why? Because she is an
understanding, kind, and loving woman
who loves you.
That's cute.
Yeah?
Yeah.
I don't know if "cute" is what I'm going
for on an interview for a newspaper, but...
Worked for Brenda Starr.
Worked for Lois Lane.
So if I get a job as a journalist
in a comic strip, this is the one.
Oh, do you remember when we used to
do road trips when you were little,
- and we'd play "I spy"?
- Yeah.
And you'd say,
"I spy something with four wheels."
And I'd be like, "is it a cow?"
'Cause that's funny and fun.
- Mom.
- Road trips are so fun.
They are fun,
but I don't feel like I can go,
especially with Logan
freaking out on me right now.
He's running off to Vegas,
coming home drunk, giving me attitude,
- not calling his dad back.
- Still?
Yes, and while I'm mad at him,
because he's acting this way,
I just feel like he's going through
something and I should be there for him.
Oh, honey, I get it.
I really do.
You know, I want to take back the
"cute." That's really growing on me.
- It's very you.
- Really?
Yeah, it's very grown-up.
It reeks of gravitas.
It screams New York Times.
Well, I need it to say more than that.
I'm hoping to hear
from the San Francisco Chronicle, the
Seattle Times, the Detroit Free Press.
Well, honey,
you can't ask one suit to say so much.
Why don't you just get the suit
that says something local?
'Cause those other cities are
so far away, so expensive,
- so tiring.
- I know.
And plus, you know you can get a
good cup of coffee in New York.
I don't know about those other cities.
They have crappy coffee.
You mean like Seattle?
Oh! Waffle Ranch.
Missing the connection.
Gosh, I drove through
North Carolina once,
and they have the most wonderful
chain called "Waffle Ranch."
Mom, it's not so much
about the road-trip food.
Waffle Ranch kicks Ihop's butt.
How come you weren't so
desperate to have me come along
when we got the invitation
two months ago?
Because two months ago,
I knew you would play the homework card,
so I planned to do this road-trip
with your dad -- just him and me.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Are you sorry enough to make
it up to me by going with me?
I really wish I could.
- Hey, that's a winner.
- Really?
Yeah, I think you could stun
them in any newspaper interview.
- It is a stunning suit, isn't it?
- Yep. It sure is.
They might like you so much
that they take your picture
and put it in the insert
for the macy's one day sale.
- You really like it?
- I really do.
But you shouldn't take my word for it.
You need a group. A consensus.
There would be a great
group at Mia's wedding.
- Nice try.
- Oh, god.
Hey, you're up.
The shower woke me.
Sorry. I'm heading
over to the library.
I have a ton of reading to catch up on.
So I thought I'd get an early start.
- Cool.
- You doing some work?
No, just looking for
something on Youtube.
You got to see this. Finn posted
a video he shot on his cellphone
when we were in Vegas.
It's pretty outrageous.
You going in to
the office today?
I doubt it.
Colin and Finn are coming over.
What are you guys gonna do?
Hang, probably.
You know, Logan,
I think after the library,
I'm gonna catch a train
back to New Haven.
Good enough.
- Oh, hi.
- Rory.
Um, Logan's...
So, it does work.
And I can assume you can get cellphone
reception wherever the hell you've been.
I was gonna call.
I was just waiting until I
figured out my next move.
Next move. I'm fascinated, Logan.
What is this next move?
And where were you figuring it out --
by the pool, the slot machines?
- You've been spying on me?
- After what you pulled,
you can bet I'm gonna be spying
on you for the rest of your life.
- I need some time.
- You know what you need, Logan?
You need to get dressed, get cleaned up,
and get your ass down to the office
so you can hear what's
been figured out for you!
I'm not just another
one of your employees.
Damn right you're not.
If you were just another one of my
employees, you'd be fired by now.
Steven, Barry and Legal
are gonna sit you down,
try and sort out
the mess you made.
Can you be there in an hour?
And there you have it, ladies and gentlemen.
Mitchum Huntzberger, class-A jerk.
Can you believe him?
No.
I mean...
- What?
- He was a jerk. He is a jerk.
But?
Uh, well, Logan, far be it for
me to agree with your father,
but you have been kind
of irresponsible.
Okay, you know what?
This is really weird.
What -- that I'm being honest?
No, that you're on his side. I kind
of expected a little support here.
Logan, I love you,
but I'm not gonna support
every stupid thing
that you do, okay?
If you go rob a bank,
what do you expect me to do?
Say, "oh, that's okay, honey.
I support you, darling"?
I screwed up. I admit it. What do you
people want -- a freaking pound of flesh?
What -- "you people"?
Logan, for me, it's not that your
business deal got messed up, okay?
It's what you've
done since then.
- What have I done?
- Nothing.
That's exactly my point.
You've not been facing the problem.
- You've been running from it.
- I was going crazy, Rory.
I had to blow off steam.
I'm trying to get my bearings here.
I don't see you trying to get your
bearings. I see you hiding out,
and people are counting on you,
your dad included.
And you're not facing your
responsibilities. You're --
- You are being a jerk.
- Well, maybe that's who I am.
Maybe I'm a jerk like my dad.
You ever think of that?
I'm starting to.
I highly recommend the
cream of wheat today, ma'am.
I don't know what it's spiked with,
but it's insane.
We got a truckload of that cream of wheat
back there, so I'm pushing it like crazy.
You're one sly waiter, Zach.
Not so fast.
Got a little snafu with my order.
I don't see a snafu.
And that is why Lane is
the pro at this job,
and you will always
be the amateur.
Dude, I don't have a problem with that.
What's wrong with the order?
Grilled-cheese platter comes
with french fries and pickles.
- Which I'm looking at.
- Look a little closer, my friend,
and you'll see that the
juice from the pickles
has leached over to
the grilled cheese,
rendering it sodden
and inedible.
I don't recall ordering
grilled cheese au jus.
Pickles have juice, dude.
It's like a main law of nature.
Ah, but that's where Lane knew how to
prevent this culinary catastrophe.
Prior to serving the dish, she would use
the french fries to build a tiny dam --
Dude, I get it.
It's all going to
the same place
inside that dark,
strange body of yours, Kirk.
Now eat it.
Lane's right.
You rock as a boss.
Yeah. How's she doing?
Dude, she is about
ready to burst.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah, she's like a giant piñata,
just waiting for some kid
to take a mallet to her stomach
and free the goodies inside.
I'm thinking a doctor might
be a better way to go.
Oh, hey, I almost forgot.
Lane and I would like to
have you over for dinner.
Oh, yeah, that sounds great.
We should do that.
Great. So,
how's tomorrow, 8:30?
- Tomorrow? I don't know.
- Here's the thing --
Lane asked me to ask you about tomorrow
a long time ago, and I kind of forgot,
so she'd be mad if you
canceled last minute.
I'm not canceling --
I haven't accepted.
Let's not get into semantics.
It would be a bummer if you bailed.
'Cause she's been cooking
for like two days.
Okay, yeah, tomorrow night --
that sounds fine.
Great! And I hope you like curry,
'cause Lane's gone curry crazy.
I'm not big on curry.
Oh, well,
maybe you can pick around it.
See, it's the same program as the
one we used for that corporate stuff
but a different application.
It's personal. It's simple.
For you, maybe. I couldn't figure it out.
And your father was absolutely no help.
All we need to do is --
mom, you're doing it again.
I'm looking at the screen.
I know, but you're,
like, hovering.
I'm not hovering, Lorelai. "Hovering"
means you're elevated off the ground.
Do I look like I'm elevating?
- You seem awful tense, mom.
- Of course I'm tense.
Having your father around the house
all the time is extremely difficult.
He's just there, wandering about,
like a man of leisure.
Did he go through any of this stuff?
Did he at least sign the 1040?
I don't know.
Mom, he has to sign some of this
stuff before we can send it out.
He refuses to deal
with anything.
All he does is watch golf,
pad around in his sweatsuit,
and annoy me with questions
about things he's misplaced.
He's getting to be a serious
pain in the you-know-what.
The nose? The ear?
Would it give you that much
pleasure to hear me say "ass"?
I wasn't sure,
but, yes, it did.
Emily!
Have you seen my --
Oh, hello, Lorelai.
Hi, dad. Nice threads.
Having lunch with Tony Soprano?
Don't encourage him.
You like it?
I realized that, since I was housebound,
I might as well wear whatever I like.
These are so comfy.
Have either of you
seen my putter?
No, but we have seen this 1040 tax form.
Sign it.
Did your mother tell you that I've
installed a putting green in the backyard?
It's great fun.
You are not going out to putt.
You'll catch your death.
And, Richard,
would you please sign this form?
Just leave the form.
I'll sign it later.
What are you doing down there?
The putter's not down there.
No, but your tax form's here.
Come on, dad. Sign it.
Fine, fine, fine,
fine, fine, fine.
And, yes! There it is.
Hallelujah, we
found the putter.
We have a few more things we
need to go over with you.
Later today, dear.
You always say that, but you never do.
And wear a hat!
Yes, mother.
Well, mom, he was watching golf.
Now he's playing golf.
That's progress.
- Hey, kid.
- I'm in.
You're robbing a bank?
The road trip --
I'm going with you to Mia's wedding.
Wow, that's great!
Are you sure?
Yes, I so need to get away.
I just had a huge
fight with Logan.
Oh, sweetie, why?
Because he's being a complete jerk.
He won't deal with anything.
And Mitchum just showed
up at the apartment.
- Mitchum came?
- I opened the door,
and there he was in a really
expensive coat and all this cologne.
And he yelled at Logan,
and Logan yelled back at him.
And, yes, Mitchum is a jerk, but I
agreed with him, and I told Logan that.
Wow, you agreed with the
boyfriend's dad? That's brave.
I couldn't help it, mom.
Logan is being immature.
And I can't focus on my work, and I
just really need to get out of here.
Honey, it sounds like a trip
like this is just what you need.
- A trip like what?
- Nothing, mom.
- Are you with grandma?
- Yes, it's our thursday computer lesson.
And it's no
"Tuesdays With Morrie."
Where are you
going on this trip?
Mia Halloway's wedding --
Charlotte, North Carolina.
- I have to be back by monday.
- That'll be no problem.
- This is gonna be a blast!
- Charlotte.
Mia wanted me to do a toast,
and I thought I could do a poem,
like you used to do for her when you
were a kid, so you have to help me.
Kiki Saltberry just came back
from a spa in Charlotte.
It's the Valentine resort, I think she
said, and she came back looking radiant.
What is grandma
saying about a spa?
We're staying at a Best Western, mom.
No spa facilities there.
So, okay, I'll pick you up at the crack
of dawn. We'll cram everything in the jeep.
No bathroom breaks
along the way, okay?
- Does grandma want to come?
- No. I mean, yes, but, no.
I'd have to rearrange my schedule,
but that can be done.
Mom, you really can't
leave dad all alone.
Alone, yes, completely alone,
with two maids, a cook,
and a nurse who comes daily.
Yes, grandma should come, too.
It'll be a hoot.
It would be fun, honey,
but grandma's real busy.
- Rory wants me to come?
- Well...
Well, she'll be graduating soon,
and I won't have many more opportunities
to spend time with her.
This is perfect.
I'm gonna start packing.
Oh, mom.
Oh, and we'll take my car.
I have no intention
of driving 800 miles
in an army vehicle.
Shotgun?
Mom, if you're gonna go this slowly,
you should really put your hazards on.
Excuse me, but after I almost
got that ridiculous DWI,
I can ill afford
a speeding ticket.
And a Jaguar is an invitation
to be pulled over.
Right, if you're speeding.
You're driving like you're in a parade.
Oh, hush.
Mom, seriously, by the time we get
there, the wedding will be over.
The guests will have gone home.
North Carolina will be under a sea
of water from melting ice caps.
- "See ya."
- Huh?
You could rhyme
"Mia" with "see ya."
Oh, that's good. Or "be ya."
Yeah.
You were such a peach,
dear Mia,
when Rory grew up,
she wanted to be ya.
Good. But do you think it
owes too much to yeats?
Well, it needs some work,
but you try finding something
to rhyme with "Howard"
besides "coward."
Howard? She's marrying
a man named Howard?
What's wrong with Howard?
It's just, for me, it would be very
difficult if my husband was named Howard.
Why?
It's just not a noble name.
I like noble male names, strong --
John, Peter.
Richard.
Exactly. Richard
the lion-heart.
Well, I guess name nobility
wasn't high on Mia's list.
Howard the lion-heart.
What are you doing?
It's stuffy.
It's too cold to have
the window open.
Mom, just let me have it down --
oh, my god.
Lorelai, stop playing
with the window.
I'm not playing. I just want it down.
And you're making it go --
Are you kidding me?
Plea-- mother, I'm putting it --
I'm putting it --
Wha-- uh -- mom!
It's called a child lock,
appropriately enough.
So, Rory, what do you have
lined up postgraduation?
Oh, I'm setting up interviews
at different newspapers --
the Seattle Times, the Detroit Free
Press, San Francisco Chronicle.
Well, I'm not sure about the Seattle
paper, and the Chronicle is dreadful,
but the Detroit paper
is quite reputable.
You know what else a reputable paper is?
The New York Times,
the Boston Globe,
the Hartford Courant.
Yes, and only a short drive
away from Stars Hollow.
Oh, well, that never occurred to me,
but now that you mention it, yeah.
So, how does Logan feel about the
possibility of your moving far away?
I'm not sure.
You're not sure?
No. Things with Logan are...
Are what?
Uh, we're kind of going
through something.
Aw, that's a shame.
Such a nice young man.
He was so thoughtful when your
grandfather was in the hospital.
Yeah.
Oh, hey, the skirf.
- Oh, the skirf.
- What's a skirf?
When Rory was really little, my first sewing
project was trying to make her a skirt.
- It was a desaster.
- It was terrible.
But Mia made me feel better by
putting it on Rory's head and saying
I created something new,
called a skirf.
Yeah.
So, do we all like show tunes?
I found this marvelous CD when
I took the car to be washed.
And I was put on bed rest so the babies
wouldn't come out before my due date.
And I look at the calendar, and I say
to Zach, "Zach, it's my due date."
And I'm like, "so?"
And I say,
"so now I want them to come out."
And I go, "duh,
let's get out of bed."
They can come out whenever they want,
as long as we've finished our meal...
...which, by the way,
was terrific, Lane.
- Thanks.
- Yeah, she had no problem
switching to a different meal when
I told her about your curry issues.
It's -- I just --
it's not really an issue.
Again, look, sorry about the wine.
I totally spaced.
I should have brought you something
sparkling, a fruity kind of a thing.
No, it's okay. Besides, they say one of
the things you can do to help induce labor
is have a glass of wine.
That or sex.
Well, I can only help
you with the wine.
So I should get going. I got to
get up early and open the diner.
Are you sure you don't wanna stay
for dessert? Homemade peach pie.
You made a peach pie?
Well, actually,
you made it at the diner,
which is technically your home,
but I paid for it, I swear.
- I'll have one quick piece.
- Yes!
This is really
nice of you guys.
What do you expect, man?
- You mean a lot to Lane and me.
- You do.
We feel really close to you,
and not just, you know, employees.
Yeah, uh, me too.
When it comes to extended family,
Zach and I don't have much.
I've got my mom,
but she's not so much a family member
as she is a probation officer.
Yeah, and my old man ran off when
I was like 10. No note. No nothing.
So I got the feeling he
didn't want me to follow him.
So, you guys need
money or something?
Lane and I would like you to
be godfather to our twins.
Oh, really? Godfather?
We just want to make sure we have a
strong parental person for our boys.
Well...
- There's no paperwork involved.
- Right. I just --
- No notary public.
- No, I know. It's just...
Yeah, okay, sure.
Oh, man. That is so great.
Up high.
Come on.
All right. Okay. There you go.
No, are you listening? I've already
booked a swedish massage for 1:00.
I want to know what
I can do at 2:30.
Good lord, no. A watsu?
Why would I want to
re-experience my own birth?
I'll be back to
take your orders.
- Big menus.
- Yeah, that's a good sign.
Oh, I love when they show
pictures of the food.
I would be upset if I was
that fried chicken, though.
That picture makes
her look fat.
Fine. Book me a salt scrub at 2:30.
Thank you.
Where on earth are we?
Well, mom, since you wouldn't let
us take you to a drive-through,
we've come here to Winky's,
a fine eatery just off I-85.
- Very down home.
- We ready here?
Oh, uh, I'm only halfway through.
Don't tell me how it turns out.
I smell cigarette smoke.
This is one of those places that
still allows cigarettes, isn't it?
Mom, if you'd prefer to wait in the car,
we can bring food to you there.
That would be foolish. The reason why
I refused to go to the drive-through
is because I won't
allow eating in my car.
- Hey, they have lobster.
- Lobster for $12.95.
How could you go wrong?
I'll have the lobster.
See, you'll have lobster. I'll have
shrimp. We'll make it a seafood night.
Seafood in a place like this --
very risky.
And a hot dog.
A hot dog for the table.
You'll go in on that with us,
won't you, mom?
I'll have a turkey sandwich on
wheat and a glass of Chardonnay.
That's the clear one.
My name is Charlene.
Holler if you need something.
Wow, huge case of
cakes behind you there.
Ooh, yeah.
Winky's got a trophy case full of cakes.
Hey, I bet Mia makes her triple-layered
german chocolate cake for her wedding,
- don't you think?
- Probably.
Mmm. Aromatherapy --
that's what I want.
Are you sure you two won't join
me for something at the spa --
facial, moroccan mud wrap?
My treat.
Mother, we came here because we made
a commitment to go to a wedding,
so that's what we're gonna do.
Suit yourself.
I need to use the facilities.
Wish me luck.
I love it here.
And I'm totally gonna score a panda
in that crane machine
on the way out.
Mom, do you think we should dial back
the talk about Mia in front of grandma?
I don't think she's thrilled to hear
about our surrogate mother/grandmother.
She knew that Mia is
the reason for the trip.
I think it's okay if
we talk about her.
I know, but it seems to bother her.
And I thought, during this trip,
we could do more mother/daughter,
daughter/daughter bonding.
10 hours in the car not
enough bonding for you?
I'm just worried about you guys.
What's gonna happen after I graduate?
After you graduate?
That's when the party gets started.
Yeah, I just --
I want you guys to remain close.
- Close?
- Ish.
Honey, your grandma and I have
a very complicated relationship,
but we'll be fine.
I don't want you to worry.
You go off and do your own thing.
I'm a grown-up.
A grown-up who wears a bib.
Thank you.
All righty. Looks like our choices
are "Hitch" or "The lake house."
- I could use a laugh.
- All right, "The lake house" it is.
Oh, my dress got wrinkled.
Honey, just put it in
the shower with the steam
if mom ever finishes
shellacking her face.
I heard that, Lorelai.
I'm simply washing up.
Mom, the resort is 20 minutes away.
Why do you have to wash up here?
I can't very well arrive
at a luxurious resort
smelling of bad shellfish and
covered with the grime of the road.
"The road." Who are you --
Willie Nelson?
Hello.
Mia, how is the
blushing bride-to-be?
Surprisingly calm,
but I've had two glasses of wine,
So we'll see tomorrow
when the buzz wears off.
- Oh, you'll do great.
- Hi, Mia.
Oh, hi, Rory. I just wanted to
see if you got here all right.
How's the motel?
Not too terrible, I hope.
Oh, no, it's great.
We have two beds, sanitized cups,
Keanu Reeves in his most touching
role to date. What could be better?
Oh, grandma, hold on.
Oh, Emily's with you?
Oh, um, yeah, we picked her up
hitchhiking on her way to a rock festival.
She's going to the
Valentine resort.
Well, if Emily's here,
then she has to come to the wedding.
No, that's okay. She's spending tomorrow
getting rubbed, wrapped, and scrubbed.
Oh, no,
she's asking me to the wedding?
No, no. It's okay.
So the ceremony's at noon.
We'll be there around 11:30.
Oh, please ask Emily to come.
We have plenty of food.
Howard and I would be
thrilled to have her join us.
In fact, I insist.
That is so thoughtful of you, Mia,
and I am sure she would love to come.
- Great. Now I have to go.
- No, you don't.
It would be rude not to. Damn!
She says she's delighted and
flattered that you asked.
Oh, that's wonderful.
I look forward to seeing
all three of you tomorrow.
- Sleep well.
- You, too, Mia.
- Bye.
Well, I hope the resort will
let me change my times.
I'll pick the two of you up at
11:00 sharp tomorrow. Be out front.
Of course, I didn't bring a
thing to wear to a wedding.
Luckily, they're going bohemian,
so it won't really matter.
We're bonding.
Oh, this could be a good thing.
No, the only good thing is that
mom is gonna get to the resort
still smelling like bad lobster,
'cause I left my doggie bag in her car.
Hey. Everything okay?
Great. Everything's --
Yeah. Great.
You know I don't open
for another hour.
Oh, no, I know, but last night when
you said you had to get up early,
I realized it's time, maybe,
I come and help crank up the place.
Okay.
I actually love this time of day,
you know, real quiet.
You know what's, like, amazing?
How peaceful Stars Hollow
is at this time of day.
It's, like, spooky peaceful.
You ever notice that?
I'm sorry. I really don't enjoy
talking this early in the morning.
Oh, hey, copy that.
I'm right there with you.
Now, Lane --
she loves to talk in the morning.
Lots of morning chin music
with that one. Not me.
I take not talking
over talking any day.
- Ooh, awesome catch.
- Thanks.
- Pretty obvious you played some ball.
- A little.
I didn't really get
into sports much.
My dad didn't do sports with me when I
was little, and then he, you know, split.
Yeah, you said. That's too bad.
Yeah.
- What kind of music you into?
- I don't really listen to much music.
If I'm driving around in my truck, I'll,
you know, maybe put on an oldies station.
I like some motown.
Oh dude, I know the perfect band for
you. You would so get off on them.
They're young, but their sound is way
borrowed from those old guys from the '70s.
Listen, I got to
fire up the stoves.
Yeah, go, go. Fire 'em up.
You know, I can't pay you any
extra 'cause you came in early.
Oh, yeah, I know.
I just figure it's part of my job,
and it's a chance
for us to hang out.
Plus, you know... the quiet.
Right.
Lorelai, you didn't even knock.
Well, that's okay.
Mia leaves the door open.
She likes people to
just come on in.
She's probably too busy to
greet everybody, grandma.
Well, of course she is. She should
have someone greet people for her.
Oh, look at all
these great pictures.
Not everyone has a maid,
you know, mom.
How hard is it to hire
a maid for the day?
Well, last I checked, they didn't
have them at bed bath & beyond.
Oh, this must be Howard.
Look. Here we are.
So cute. That's the rug where you used
to spin around at the Independence Inn.
I bet you threw up just seconds
after that picture was taken.
Are we going in, or are we going to
watch the ceremony from the entryway?
- Oh, you're here!
- Hi!
Did you find it all right?
Yeah, mom's got the GPS. Apparently,
it's great if you know how to use it.
Yeah, we saw a lot of your
neighborhood -- very nice.
Oh, those damn GPS
drive me crazy.
Whatever happened to asking
the guy at the gas station?
Good question.
Hello, Mia. Thank you so much for
inviting me to this special occasion.
Emily, I'm so glad
you could be here.
Well, let's go in.
Let's not just stand here.
I know a wedding wasn't what you
had in mind when you came down here.
What I had in mind was spending time with
my daughter and granddaughter, wherever.
- Will you sign my guest book, please?
- Oh, certainly.
I just feel so lucky to have all
the Gilmore ladies under one roof.
Speaking of roofs,
you have a charming home.
Oh, thank you.
I'm always amazed at what good
taste can do with a small space.
Oh, it is beautiful.
Yeah, so many personal
touches everywhere.
Thank you. I agree with Emily.
It's a small house,
And it's made even smaller by Howard's
junk. But you know what they say --
you marry a man,
you marry his junk. Howard.
- Mia --
- Howard, Howard.
This is Emily Gilmore,
the mother and grandmother
of the famous Lorelai and Rory.
Hi.
- Nice to meet you.
- How do you do?
I thought you weren't supposed
to see the bride in her gown
before you got married.
Yeah, and if the bride sees a lizard
crossing the road, that's bad news, too.
Oh, well, haven't seen a lizard,
but too late for the dress,
- 'cause Howard zipped me up.
- Oh no.
Where's the zip-up on
the bad-luck-o-meter?
Not sure, but I'd throw some salt
over your shoulders. Just in case.
I don't have any salt.
I might have some splenda.
You are exactly as Mia described you --
you both are.
And believe me,
she described you a lot.
Well, I hope she left
out the bad stuff.
There's no bad stuff.
Lucky you.
The sooner we get married,
the sooner we eat cake.
Oh, honey, you're so romantic.
Emily, could I just borrow the girls
for a quick touch-up in the powder room?
- They're all yours.
- Oh, thanks.
Okay, guys,
let's get me beautiful.
Oh, thank you.
Mia adores them.
Yes, I know.
Well, come in. Find a seat.
The sofa will be fine.
And so, a toast to you,
dear Mia.
It makes us all so
glad to see ya...
blissfully joined with dear,
good Howard.
May your love last long,
like it's battery-powered.
Rory and I wanted to do a poem for you,
because when Rory was little,
she used to love
making up poems,
and we would perform them for you,
and that was such a fun time.
Uh, so, what I've realized
now is that you can get away
with a lot of bad rhymes
when you're cute and 5.
But we do want to say...
Excuse-me, would you mind terribly
getting me a glass of water?
...the best things in life are worth waiting
for, even if they take a long time...
She keeps her house very dry.
So, let's...
A toast to you.
We love you so much. Cheers.
- Cheers.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
That was wonderful.
Are you Rory?
There's someone
here to see you.
...that you are here today.
And thank you for those of
you who came from so far away.
Thank you again for the toast.
I'll thank my sister for
all the wonderful help...
Hey.
What the hell are
you doing here?
I'm sorry. I don't mean to crash this.
I just need to talk to you.
- How did you know where I was?
- I called Paris.
She found the invitation. I kept trying
your cell, but you didn't pick up.
Well, that's the
advantage of caller I.D.
- I get it. You're still mad.
- No kidding.
I'm here, so you have to talk to me --
the advantage of showing up in person.
Wow, I can't believe you're still doing
this. This is so last year's Logan.
What?
You think you can just fly
anywhere I am and overwhelm me
by just showing up and --
I'm just not impressed anymore
by your grand gestures.
I'm not trying to impress you. I just
want to tell you what I've been thinking.
- I don't care --
- And I wanted to see you.
I'm in the middle of a wedding
celebration of a close friend.
I don't have time to stand
here and listen to you explain
your stupid immature behavior.
If you would just
hear me out --
No, you go blow
off steam in Vegas,
you gamble away thousands of dollars,
you drink all night,
and do god knows what else.
This is me blowing off steam.
I'm sorry to interrupt, Rory,
but Mia wanted me to tell you
- we're about to cut the cake.
- Okay.
- Will your friend join us?
- Um, no, he can't stay.
Yeah, I was just stopping by.
Thanks, anyway.
Oh, okay.
- Hey, girls.
- Hey, there.
Talk to me, Zach.
What do you got?
Okay, bowl of chili, two dogs,
one BLT, shepherd's pie,
and a mushroom soup.
And those guys in the corner were asking
me if I had a pack of lucky strikes
or a burger to spare.
What's that about?
Bowling humor -- strikes, spares.
Never gets old, guys.
Oh, I totally missed it.
- Oh, man!
- What's wrong?
Last night, I made this mix of tunes
that I thought would be right up your alley.
Okay.
Well, you know, new stuff that
sounds kind of classic rock-y --
my morning jacket,
who are like Neil Young reborn,
if Neil would have,
you know, died.
Wolfmother -- definitely
channeling Zeppelin -- modern,
but not so much that it would
freak out somebody of your taste.
- The point?
- The point is,
- I totally forgot to bring it.
- Oh, don't worry about it.
- Yeah, but I spent all night on it.
- That's nice.
Gave me something to do
instead of sitting around,
waiting for Lane to
pop out the babies.
It'll happen.
Yeah, don't I know it?
Denver omelet, steak sandwich.
Two cheeseburgers --
medium and well.
- Question -- circumcision, yes or no?
- Pardon?
We have to make a decision as
soon as the boys are born,
and I'm really on
the fence about it.
I thought about having Mrs.
Kim weigh in, but her opinion would be
kind of hypothetical 'cause she doesn't
have the goods, as far as I know.
Right, so, you being a guy, I figured
I could use your input on this.
You know, something like this -- it's
kind of personal between you and Lane,
- so go with your gut.
- Yeah, okay. Cool.
Bill, refill?
Let's say your kid falls out of a
tree and majorly gashes his head.
Do you run to him right away or
just let him kind of shake it off?
I don't want to be a wussy dad,
but --
Probably not the right time to be talking
about gashed heads and circumcisions.
Right. Right.
I totally get that.
Maybe we could, uh, go over to
Casey's after work and grab a beer
- and talk about some stuff.
- Look, I-I can't be --
- Please.
- Okay.
Listen, I know what's
going on, okay?
You're about to become a father,
so you're panicking.
I am, dude, big-time.
Promise you you'll
get through this.
I don't know how to
throw a damn frisbee.
Don't worry about it, okay?
I really could use your help
on all this father stuff
- that I know nothing about.
- Zach --
What the hell are they supposed to
call me -- "dad," "pop," "papa"?
- Do I look like a papa to you?
- It'll come to you eventually.
Papa is a big, cuddly guy from
Italy with all this dark hair.
That's so not me.
Listen, the first time
April turned up in my life,
I didn't know squat about being a
father, but eventually, it came to me.
I found my dad mode,
and you will, too.
- Dude, I hope so.
- Yeah. Don't sweat it.
Go ahead and deliver these to the clowns
in the corner over there. You will be fine.
I -- Okay, all right.
- Guy's a real goofball, huh?
- Yeah, watch it, Bill.
- I'm not finished with that pie.
- Yeah, you are.
And I drove through
Connecticut once -- beautiful.
In fact, Cathy and I considered moving
to New England 'cause we love the foliage.
Well, we got a lot of that.
It practically grows on trees.
But the cold -- no thank you.
I can barely handle it here in Charlotte
when it drops below 40.
Cathy says it's a
circulation thing.
I think it's a matter of not having
the fat layer that you women do.
You should be glad
you don't have it.
If you did, you couldn't wear
such an amazing sweater.
Hey, Mia put out some of her famous
mini cream puffs. They're delicious.
Uh-oh, may have to get
me one of those. Scusie.
- God bless you.
- No problem.
- You looked a little trapped there.
- No, no.
I was riveted by stories
of foliage and fat.
- Where'd you go off to?
- Logan showed up.
- What?!
- Yeah.
- Where is he?
- Outside, leaning against a car.
Why? You wouldn't
let him come in?
No.
Really? Look at you,
all tough love.
I'm still mad at him. I'm not gonna melt
just because he flies here to see me.
If we're gonna do this,
it's gonna be on my terms.
Wow.
It doesn't look like grandma's
having a good time, is she?
No, grandma's staging a sit-in,
as only grandma could do,
in the middle of a hoopla.
Some people would call it a shindig.
I'm here to tell
you it's a hoopla.
I have so much to
learn from you still.
Ladies, I'm striking out left and right
in my attempts to coax someone to dance.
Would either of you
salvage my pride?
Howard, I'll dance with you.
Thank you.
Talk to grandma.
Hi, mom. How are you doing?
Oh, fine. I'm just going through
my schedule for the week.
So, did Howard
ask you to dance?
He did, yes -- very thoughtful.
Why didn't you dance with him?
I don't feel like
dancing right now.
Besides, I have no idea how
one dances to cowboy music.
You want to dance with me? We could
slap our knees, shout "yee-haw."
No thank you. I think I'll just
wait for the appropriate moment
to excuse myself gracefully.
Mom, I told you I didn't think
you were gonna want to come.
So, Lorelai, gal,
we have got to do some catching up.
How have you been, sweetie?
Good, Donna. Good.
Mia says you have you own inn.
That is so far out.
It is great.
Um, mom, this is Donna.
This is my mother,
Emily Gilmore.
- How do you do?
- Really well, thank you.
Donna and I were maids together
at the Independence Inn.
A few hundred lives ago, huh?
Hey, listen,
your toast was so great.
Thanks. I didn't know I
was gonna be the only one.
Oh, but you were
the perfect choice.
I mean, for god's sake,
Mia was like a mother to you.
Um, so, how are you?
You look good.
- I do, don't I?
- Yeah.
I tell you, six years ago, when I
first started the raw-foods thing --
Do you know if they
put the coffee out yet?
- Mother.
- What?
I'm sorry, but you're talking about
something between the two of you,
and I could really
use a cup of coffee.
You know what? I am having a
serious craving for herbal tea.
Let's get something
together, Emily.
All right.
- Hey.
- Everything okay?
- Yeah. It's fine.
I just always seem to forget my
mother doesn't play well with others.
Oh, I think she's doing
all right, considering.
Considering...
I mean, in terms of you and
me and Rory and our history.
Yeah, so? We have a history.
Seeing me with both of you must
bring back very painful memories.
Imagine how difficult it must have
been for your mother to lose you.
She didn't lose me.
I embarrassed her, so I had to leave.
But Lorelai,
even in the best of circumstances,
you never want to think that your
child doesn't need you anymore.
She just wanted me out of the
house so she didn't have to explain
why my school uniform
didn't fit anymore.
That's not the impression I
got when she came to see me.
What? When did she
come to see you?
Oh, must have been five years ago,
when I came back
for that visit to Stars Hollow.
She came and found
me at the inn.
- Why?
- I think she wanted to meet me.
And she asked me to send
her photos of you and Rory
from those years when
you were staying with me.
She never told you?
No, she definitely
never told me.
Well, my dear,
my dancing feet are all warmed up.
- Your turn.
- Oh, goody, the dance.
Now we find out if we're
really meant to be together.
You didn't have
to bring me cake.
I didn't.
You wanted to talk, so talk.
All I wanted to do
was say I'm sorry,
so... I'm sorry. You were right.
I was being immature.
Okay.
When the whole
deal fell apart...
I knew I was in so much trouble,
I just -- I totally lost it.
I couldn't face anything.
I had so much invested in it in every
way that, when it all collapsed,
it was like I fell into this hole
I couldn't pull myself out of.
And I also realized that my dad was right.
He had every reason to be pissed at me.
I mean,
I would have fired me for what I did.
So, I decided the only way to fix this
is to not be my dad's employee anymore.
What?
I went to him, and I just --
I said --
I was calm, apologetic,
no shouting, no threats.
I just said I didn't want to be a pawn
in whatever game he had in mind for me.
Really?
I am officially not working for
the Huntzberger Group anymore.
Oh, my god.
Yeah, and it feels really good.
I mean, it felt great finally
standing up to my dad.
How did he take it?
He tried to put up this cool,
detached front,
but I think I actually saw
steam coming out of his ears.
Basically, he told
me to hit the road.
And you took him literally.
I just needed to see you.
The thing is,
even though he was mad, I swear I saw
the slightest glimmer of pride
in his eyes, just for a second.
I mean,
no one walks out on Mitchum Huntzberger.
I'm proud of you, too.
I almost wish I'd saved
you a bite of cake.
Boyfriend?
Yes.
He came with you?
No, I guess he flew
down to see Rory.
It's hard for me to think of
little Rory with a boyfriend.
- She's not so little anymore.
- No.
I just hope she doesn't
get her heart broken.
I can assure you, if anyone does
any heartbreaking, it will be Rory.
- Probably.
- Definitely.
She's such a smart, confident young
woman. She's really amazing --
witty, charming,
valedictorian in high school,
editor of the college paper.
Sounds like she'll have her pick of jobs
at newspapers all over the country.
Rory will be fine.
Well, you would know.
Hey.
Here you go.
Well, we should probably get going,
let Mia and Howard do
whatever it is they're gonna
do the rest of the night.
- Lorelai.
- What? That could mean anything.
Well, she's right.
The bride and groom have wild plans
to take off all their clothes,
jump into their pajamas,
and listen to "A
prairie home companion."
See? Dirty mind -- you.
I can't tell you how much it meant
for me to have you here. Thank you.
Oh, you kidding?
I wouldn't have missed it.
Mia, best wishes to you.
It was a lovely wedding.
Thank you...
For everything.
It was my pleasure.
Bill is asking for
seconds on his pie --
something about how you
owe him from earlier.
Sure, give it to him.
Look, man, I'm really sorry
about the way I've been acting --
leaning on you for
all this father stuff.
Don't worry about it.
No, I was just all bent out of shape
about being a perfect father --
like there is such a thing.
And I was so freaking nervous,
I'm like, "hey,
maybe Luke can take up the slack."
Hey, if I can help out, I will.
No, but I dig what you
said about the dad mode --
makes perfect sense.
I'm really psyched to feel it kick in.
- Okay, good.
- Totally.
Oh, I almost forgot.
This is the CD.
Oh, great.
Yeah, I listed the band names on the
back. You don't have to listen to it.
No, I want to hear it.
Luke's diner.
Who knows,
maybe I'll really get into Wolfmother.
Okay, okay. Do not move.
I'll be right there.
Don't move.
I have to go.
Lane's water broke.
I need my... coat.
I-I don't --
I don't need my coat.
My keys are in my coat.
That's it. We're closed, folks.
I'm driving.
- No, no, no, man. I can do this.
- Zach, Zach, Zach, Zach.
Dad mode doesn't have to
kick in right now. Let's go.
Last one out, lock the door,
turn off the lights.
What about my --
Just take the whole
damn pie, Bill.
So, he's really not
working for his dad?
No, he's out of there.
Well, it's probably
the best thing for him.
How did he feel about you
sending him back to New York?
Um, I think he was okay with it. I told
him it was an all-girls road trip.
Exactly. No boys allowed,
except for that male stripper we hired.
Well, good night.
Oh, grandma,
aren't you coming in?
No, I just wanted to
walk you to your room,
seeing as this isn't the
safest of neighborhoods.
Mom, now I feel like I should
walk you back to the car
and then you're gonna walk me back and
then we'll be stuck in a terrible loop
and neither of us is
wearing the shoes for that.
Oh, grandma, you should stay.
We're gonna get junk food from the
vending machine, and watch a movie.
Come on. Don't you like dots?
Hey, get some Little Debbie.
Seriously, Rory, I can't stay.
Too late, grandma.
I'm already getting you a little debbie.
Oh, I bought her a suit.
Did you?
Yeah. It was so fun.
It was weird, you know,
but we found something really great,
and it just felt like
a rite of passage.
I'm sure.
Made me imagine, you know,
what it's gonna be like
after she leaves.
Of course.
It's gonna be hard
to be without her.
Well, I'm sure you'll
get through it.
What I mean to say is, mom,
I know that it was hard for you.
Have you seen "The
pursuit of happyness"?
Is that the one
with Will Smith?
He's so attractive.
Mmm! Mom has a thing
for Will Smith.
I don't have a thing for him.
Is it on now?
Yeah.
Oh, my god!
Lane had her babies.
Zach just sent me
a photo. Here.
- Oh, cute!
- Aren't they cute?
I'm sure that little camera
distorts their faces.
What do you mean, mom?
They're cute.
Here's another one.
Oh, sweet.
Why did they
misspell "happyness"?
we'll find out.
There's your boyfriend, mom.
- Who?
- He's not my boyfriend.
- Will Smith. Mom has a thing for him.
- You like Will Smith?
- I think that he's very charming.
- That's all right.
Transcript : Raceman
Subtitles : Willow's Team
www.forom.com
www.tvsubtitles.net