Hey.
What?
Make an occasional noise so I know
you didn't pull an Elvis.
Just putting the finishing
touches on the face.
You're an infant. Hit yourself with a
giant powder puff and get out here.
I love this bathroom.
Uh, too much! I need the sink.
You need my sink? What about the other sink?
Oh! I forgot I had two sinks!
Well, you do.
Look at this. Two sinks. I'm so decadent.
I could brush my teeth over this
one and spit into that one.
This is now my official favorite
room in the whole world.
Besides the Reading Room
at the British Museum.
But add a dome ceiling and ten million books
and you've got yourself a horse race.
Paul Anka loves this room too.
You ever hear that tape of him chewing
out his band after a show?
'When I move, I slice like a hammer!
The guys get shirts!'
That's the human Paul Anka.
I don't believe the canine version exists.
He is just laying low until he figures out
you're not going to break his heart
or eat his pig's ears or something.
Well, the chicken's got to show
his face so I can prove myself.
So, what all do you have going on today?
Oh, she's already got a list going.
Follow up calls to Yale to make sure
I'm all set up for spring semester,
four hours of community service -
I'm going to try to stretch it to five
because I am tantalizingly
close to being done -
my engine light was on,
but I already took care of that -
This morning?
Got to Gypsy's shop before it opened.
There was only one other annoying
early bird ahead of me,
but I bribed Gypsy with a pack of
Rolo's and she took me first.
She is such a Rolo whore.
I've got tons of e-mails to return, and, oh,
I've got to get the Eagle-Gazette
a bunch of stuff I've written.
Okay. Don't forget to sleep,
daughter of mine.
And, uh, I've got to unpack and organize
everything and that's it, for now.
Okay, but you will have to leave
the bathroom to do all that.
Mm, reluctantly. See you downstairs.
Okay.
Hey, you have time to eat and
hang out with me, don't you?
Is that on your microscopic
little list there?
I've timed out the rest
of the morning for you.
Good girl!
Oh! Oh, my God!
What?
Come down here!
I'm coming!
What?
He has emerged.
I'm assuming that's Paul Anka.
Well, it ain't Louis Prima.
Shoo! Shoo!
What are you doing?
He shouldn't be on the table.
That's his favorite spot.
What are you going to do next,
tell him he can't drink
out of my water glass?
Sorry. How should I approach him?
Follow me.
'Kay.
Okay, stop.
Now go in the kitchen and
put sugar on your toes.
What?
And quickly! Because first impressions are
crucial and you're blowing it big time.
Sugar on my toes?
Yes, he loves sugar,
so the first time you come close to him,
if you've got sugar on your toes that
he can lick and enjoy, you're in.
He's going to lick it?
- Go, quick!
- Okay.
Wet your toes first so it sticks!
What?
Dry sugar on a dry toe isn't going to work!
Oh, jeez.
I'm making a mess.
Don't worry about the mess!
We're going to have ants!
Hurry!
I'm coming!
Okay, my toes are all sugared.
Okay, good! Now do the hokey-pokey
and turn yourself around.
What?
All you have to do is pet him and you're in!
You're evil.
Yes, I am.
Hey, there, boy!
Oh, that tickles!
Well, he's glad you're here!
Wait a minute, you're here!
I know!
Wait right there.
Is this another trick?
No, I'm just getting something.
You're pulling out the Bop-it?
You're already that bored of me?
No. I just accidentally hit the Bop-it
while I was getting this.
You bought me a hat?
No, it's a hat box, filled with these.
These are notes, written on whatever
I had on hand at the time.
Any time I had a topic I
wanted to share with you
or a random thought during that
crappy time apart of ours,
I jotted it down and threw it in the
hat box so I wouldn't forget.
Really?
I missed you, kid.
Missed you too.
So, hit me with 'em!
While we walk to Luke's. Come on.
Some of these are pretty cryptic.
Um, Lenny Kravitz - where did Lenny Kravitz -
Get all his money? Yes!
One hit and he's buying
a Fifth Avenue mansion.
Maybe he went through Nicole Kidman's
wallet when she wasn't looking.
That's got to be it.
Computer MP down
- oh. I want to download music.
There's so much out there.
Can you help me figure that out? MP3 players?
I can do that. Next?
Eh, Kirk skeet shooting.
That's a bad combination.
Yeah, it's the first time the town church has
taken gunfire since the eighteenth century.
I missed so much so quickly!
Okay. Babette - cats.
- Death?
- No.
- Adopted another one?
What?
Recorded their meows, did some editing and
cut a record of them singing Ring of Fire.
Well, that goes straight
to the top of my charts.
Oh, I started reading Beowulf,
that new translation you recommended.
The Seamus Heaney? Good for you.
Yeah. And stopped reading Beowulf,
jotted on the same slip three minutes later.
Well, you gave it the old college try.
Oh, this is a new one!
Kirk's got a new hobby. He's doing -
Doing Tai Chi?
How'd you know that?
Because he's doing it right there.
Is it possible for him to do something
without looking a little silly?
He wouldn't be Kirk then.
Bendleshnitz?
That's not English.
I know. I'll add it to the ones
that I can't make out.
And - brazzlefrat.
Another unreadable one.
They're stacking up! Okay.
Now wait out here.
Why?
It's a thing. A moment thing. Just wait here.
Okay.
Hey!
- You ready?
- For what?
For this!
The moment you've all been waiting for!
Brrrr!
- What's that?
- It's a drum roll.
It sounded more like a helicopter.
Well, it's a drum roll, go with it, okay?
Ladies and gentlemen, Rory Gilmore!
Hi Luke!
Hey, Rory, you're back!
I'm back!
You look good. Healthy, happy.
Huh, here with your mom, both of you here.
Yeah, it's great, you know!
Yay!
I don't think I've ever said 'yay' before.
Sounded weird.
A little.
Come, sit, sit.
What was that sound you were making?
A drum roll!
It sounded like a helicopter or something.
That's what I said.
Has no one heard a drum roll before?
Hey, I saved you the best table
in case you showed up.
In case? It was mandatory.
What can I get you? Ah, never mind.
I'm going to bring you everything you like.
I know what you like.
Sounds good.
Oh, hey! You were with me when I wrote this.
Uh, what does it say?
Oh, this is from that stupid Mexican
restaurant we went to.
Right. I wrote something on the other side.
Man, this place stunk!
I know, but read the back, there.
I've got to know what it says.
Look what we paid! Unbelievable.
Downright usurious!
Now look at the other side, there.
The brazzelfrat?
They did charge me for that second beer!
I never got it.
Scandalous. But the other side.
Six bucks for guacamole.
Oh, just bring me what she's having.
Coming right up.
So, Luke, wait!
You haven't told me anything about yourself.
What's new with you?
With me? Uh, nothing.
We're engaged, your mom and me.
I know that, but anything else?
No. No, why?
Just wondering.
What have you heard?
Nothing. That's why I'm asking.
Well, there's your answer. Nothing.
Nothing's new.
I'm going to go put in your order, okay?
Sure.
We'll be waiting hungrily!
Did I inadvertently step
into something there?
No idea.
Mother and daughter, together again,
and all is right with the world.
- Hi, Lorelai.
- Hi, Lane.
So. Next Wednesday night, I need you.
Tell me you're not busy.
I'm not sure, why?
We're doing a showcase. Me and the band.
Not a gig, a showcase.
And a label's going to be there.
I'm shaking! I shouldn't shake,
I'm a drummer! It'll mess up the beat.
But, my God, we're playing for a label.
Wow! Lane, I'm absolutely there. This is big!
Very big. Unless it's a 'Waiting for Guffman'
thing and the label guys don't show up.
Did I just jinx it?
I don't know.
Let's do that un-jinxing thing we used to do,
just in case.
Good.
Jinx back, double pinkie, round the side,
double pinkie, jinx back.
Hey, I want to do that!
It's a serious thing, Mom!
You don't just do it.
Sorry.
Well, Lane,
you guys are so prepared for this.
That tape you gave me of your
new stuff was awesome!
Hey, what if I jinx it!
Do I get to do the un-jinxing thing then?
If we jinx-back a second time within the
hour, it cancels out the first jinx-back.
Sorry.
So, what were your favorites on the tape?
Well, 'Melissa' was catchy,
and 'Colleen Francine'.
But that other one - 'Rebecca in the
morning'? That was my favorite.
Mine too!
Zach's into songs with girl's names, huh?
He thinks that's our best shot at radio play.
Worked for the Police, the Knack,
Franz Ferdinand.
Good thinking.
Hey. Do you want to be our DA Pennebaker?
We're borrowing a video camera, and we need
someone sober to do the photography.
I could set my crack pipe aside
for the night and do that.
Thanks!
You plus one, right?
Plus one?
You plus Logan?
No. Just me.
Oh, okay. How about you, Lorelai?
Working that night, sweetie, but break a leg.
Does that get me a hand thingy?
No.
Rats.
See you guys.
So, just you, huh?
Just me.
Okay!
As long as you're prying -
I wasn't.
Briefly, succinctly,
Logan and I are not talking right now.
Ah.
We had a fight. A big one, in public.
Oops.
I think we just needed a little break,
a least I did.
It's more like a hiatus.
Well, sometimes a break is good.
Sometimes.
Food. First wave only.
Second wave, five minutes.
Let's dig in.
I hope it's not cold.
Oops, I think I jinxed it!
Jinx back, double pinkie, round the side,
double pinkie, jinx back.
Woo!
Okay, where's the onions for my sauce?
Who's my onion man?
Right here, Sookie.
Okay, right here, Carl.
I need them right there. Okay?
Get the shallots in it. It's time. It's time!
Okay. Needs more garlic. Come on.
Godfather it up for me.
Good! Good, good, good. Good, good.
Okay. If you can travel back
in time and make me not make
the veal and ham pate, I'd appreciate it.
Talk me out of these things
in the future, guys.
- Hello!
Could you step away from the pan, please?
Honey, do you see a joystick?
This is not a game. Okay?
It's a heche sauce and it's for keeps!
Put it down!
Okay! What?
Okay!
Oh, my God!
Hi Sookie!
You're here!
You're with us! Oh, look, I missed you!
I missed you!
This means you can set a wedding date.
No impediments!
Yeah. I already told Luke.
Hyperventilating!
I was just working on my list of
what to make for Thanksgiving
and I was wishing you were going
to be here and now you are!
Oh my God! What if what I'm wishing
for is actually coming true?
Quick! Wish for a Sephora to be
built within walking distance.
Do you need a paper bag?
I'm good, I'm good. Just happy.
Rory!
Oh, hi! Wow, Michel.
Hi.
Boy, that was weird.
She just surprised me, that's all.
It's kind of okay that you are here.
It's kind of okay with me too.
- Lunch!
- What?
Lunch! I'm making you lunch!
- But we just -
- Don't fight it.
It just came to me. Kebabs.
Okay, drop everything, boys!
We're making kebabs for Rory,
and pot stickers!
Okay, throw everything out.
This is a celebration! Woo!
Let's get to higher ground.
Okay, we're opening with Melissa,
closing with Dear Maureen.
Those are great bookends,
it's the middle part that's screwing us up.
Aw, man, I wish we had one more ballad.
I'm half finished with one,
but it's not going to be ready in time.
# I saw her, in the mist she came walking by,
Stella #
# Now a blur,
made a list of what I like about her,
Stella #
Cool!
Yeah! It's got a nice Fountains
of Wayne meets the Shins
crossed with Odyssey-era Zombies,
and a mix of early Who and mid-to-late-era
Replacements vibe to it.
Well, that's what I was going for.
Still hunting for that middle eight,
you know?
So, um, it's called Stella?
Yeah, I guess. Didn't you like it?
No, it's good. It's just
- it's another girl's name.
So?
If he were singing about dudes, I'd be out
the door before you could say 'See ya'!
Look, Lane, you know how I write.
I think about people that I've known
and I draw inspiration from that.
I know, it's just, no big deal or anything,
but have you ever thought to write one about,
I don't know, a girl named Lane?
Well, Lane just isn't that great
of a name for a song.
But you've already got one called Lorraine.
Lorraine is pretty much Lane with
an extra syllable thrown in.
True, but nothing rhymes with Lane.
I'm sorry,
but a million things rhyme with Lane.
Yeah, rain. Pain. All cliché stuff.
You're not a writer.
I think you could come up with non-cliché
stuff to rhyme with Lane.
Wait, maybe I could write one about your
Korean name. What was that again?
Hyung-hyung?
O for two.
Look, it's not your fault.
You didn't pick your name, your mom did.
Right. I didn't pick it.
Okay, so. Where were we?
Oh. Lorraine. Where should Lorraine go?
Try it after Rebecca.
It's not as good a transition as going
from Rebecca to Linda Marie.
True is true.
Man. I wish Stella was ready.
Three days.
Three days he had the hiccups.
Poor Paul Anka.
And by sneaking up on him
to scare them out of him,
he jumped so high, his head split my lip.
See the red? My blood.
Yuck.
Oh. Um, here's a non-fun one.
Just to mix it up a little.
What?
Your dad called.
Wow. It's been, like a year, hasn't it?
When did he call?
The very worst possible time.
He's got a knack for that.
I didn't talk to him. He left a message,
some of which Luke overheard
and it freaked him out.
That's understandable.
And we argued, see? Arguing's not
just for the younger demographic.
Nice to know.
But then we made up and we had a good talk
and then I listened to the rest of
Christopher's message and he wants to see me.
Why?
He didn't say. He sounded very chipper.
He said he had something very important to
discuss with me, and that it wasn't a trick,
and that it was an absolute one hundred
percent positive thing for me and for you.
For both of us.
Meaning there's a ninety-nine and ninety-nine
one hundredths percent
chance that it won't be.
I guess so.
So what should I do?
You could ignore him.
That's dangerous, too.
It's a slippery slope with Dad.
What could it be about?
I mean, he wouldn't dare be in cahoots with
Emily and Richard on something, would he?
He's not that dumb.
Yeah, but he's vulnerable.
They prey on the weak.
But he said it's something positive.
It couldn't involve them.
Maybe he's getting back
together with his wife.
Well, that's not technically good
news for us, it's just news.
Maybe it's about Gigi.
Maybe he's discovered she's a prodigy.
Maybe he's calling to invite us to
her premiere at Carnegie Hall.
Playing what instrument?
The flugle horn.
She's three. We would have read
about it in the paper by now.
'Freakishly talented three-year-old
flugle horn prodigy discovered'.
It would be very positive news.
Hm. Well, I'm out.
Me too.
Oh. I guess there's only one way to find out.
Guess so.
Brazzlefrat.
Bendleschnitz.
Thank you so much, big brother.
What a godsend you are.
Yeah.
God sent me to help you and now he must pay.
You know, I've never made dinner
for twelve people before.
Actually I've never made dinner before.
See, I'm making rolls for my thanksgiving
dinner tomorrow,
and I just don't have the oven space.
Or the oven.
Just hurry, Liz.
See, I've got a convection
oven and a microwave,
and that's going to take
care of everything else.
See, I'm a student of Martha.
You know Martha Stewart?
She's a genius.
Don't bother the customers, Liz.
You know, they're all Renaissance Fair
people coming to this thing, Luke.
You know some of them.
Goody.
Larry with the 'Kill 'em
all' tattoo on his face,
and Freddy, the guy who doesn't have thumbs.
Don't tell me, he's hitch hiking in.
You're funny.
Really, Luke,
I'm calling you Yakov from now on!
Just try not to be too intrusive,
please, Liz?
Yes, sir!
Hey, that's fun!
Okay.
This is not what I call not being intrusive.
Okay, I know this.
Two 'not's is a double negative which
makes it a positive, and -
you know what, this is where I always
lose my train of thought.
You're intruding.
Is this one roll? It's crazy!
You separate 'em.
Oh, boy. My carpal tunnel.
That's going to make doing this impossible.
Hey, do you mind giving me a hand?
No, you don't have to do that!
Yes, I do.
If you insist.
I'll, uh, grab me a cup of coffee.
So, Sophie, you've done, like,
big show gigs before playing the piano.
Any advice?
Don't wear a clown suit.
Thanks.
Still got my eye on this beauty.
Just don't put your hand on it.
Maybe I'll splurge and get it.
You take MasterCard?
Why, you got one?
Just waiting to hear back on the application.
Keep moving.
Oh! Cool! We should all get these.
Wireless mikes?
Isn't that too Gwen Stefani?
Not if we wear 'em.
It'll be totally Peter Gabriel.
Hey, dude. That doesn't sound too bad.
What is it?
Oh, just a song I've been working on.
I don't know if it's any good or not.
Chords are good. Any lyrics?
Some. It's called Lane.
It's called Lane?
Who, me, Lane?
Yeah. We were talking about songs and Lane
yesterday and I just got inspired.
Inspired, huh?
That's nice! Thanks, Brian!
Doesn't make me want to be violently ill.
High praise.
Yeah! Thanks, Sophie!
We can learn it next week.
Look, we came to get picks.
Let's get picks, okay?
Lorelai. Over here.
I snagged the best table in the house.
You slip the guy a buck?
I had to get my fifty cents change. Hey.
Hey, Chris.
I don't know how you do it, I mean,
you always look -
Yeah, well, I get the girls from
the Wash & Brush Up company
from the Wizard of Oz working for me now.
Good deal.
So, uh, how's our Rory?
Oh, she's good. She's, um, you know. Great.
Very busy.
As per usual.
She took a little time off Yale.
And the Apocalypse is this week? Next week?
She's back there and she's thriving.
She'll be running the world one day.
You sure?
She's doing great. Trust me.
I do.
So?
So.
What's going on?
Wouldn't you like to know?
Christopher.
This is the funnest thing I've got to
do in years. Years! All right?
Let me, let me savor it.
Come on! Tell me. What?
My grandfather died.
Um, that's fun how?
Well, that's not the fun part.
The old man was ninety eight, long life,
great life.
His last words were an inappropriate
pass at the nurse tending to him.
Pretty good one, too.
I made a mental note of it.
So your grandfather died.
Well, the old guy was actually pretty cool,
and for some reason he always liked me.
And he was the Hayden with the purse strings.
Long story short,
I'm rich.
You're rich!
Ridiculously. I mean,
I'm not Bill Gates by a long shot,
but I've got money!
Can you stand it?
Good, Chris. That's good.
And I want to share it.
I've set Gigi up with funds for private
nursery school and prep school
and college and grad school and post-grad
school and PhD school
and a wedding and a divorce if she wants it,
and another wedding or she
can buy a bunch of cats
and a lifetime supply of Twizzlers
and popcorn if that's her choice.
But she's all set, and...
now I want to take care of you. You and Rory.
Oh. Oh, Chris, I don't know what to say.
What do you want? A car? How about a Bentley?
They're pretty sweet.
Or a new house?
Or a tract of land to build a new house?
I can do that. I can buy you a tract.
Christopher -
Or is there someone you hate that you'd like
to say 'I can buy and sell you' to?
Because you can have the funds
to make that happen.
You can crush people with money.
You want some people-crushing money?
Oh, Chris, slow down, here.
Come on, everybody needs something!
Including you. Don't forget yourself.
Ah, I bought a new bike,
I bought a giant audio system. I'm done.
What else do I want? Nothing.
Buy yourself a tract of land.
Come on. Let me give you something.
A castle in Ireland? A Civil War cannon.
A brewery. Yeah! Buy a brewery!
That would be cool!
You could brew your own beer!
You know, I had a brewery for a while,
but I couldn't stand the smell of hops.
Pay off something. Your house.
Outstanding bills. Your bookie. Something.
Pay off Yale. Pay off your back taxes.
I don't owe any back taxes.
Oh, right, that's me.
Look, Chris, you're very nice to offer,
and I love that you're so excited about it.
It's great to see you like this.
But I'm fine.
You're too un-materialistic. You know,
I've always thought that.
If it makes you feel any better,
I'll talk to Rory.
See if she wants a brewery or a Bentley.
Or a castle! Don't forget the castle.
I'll mention the castle.
And it doesn't have to be in Ireland.
It can be in Germany,
Czech Republic, Scotland, Narnia.
I'll leave nothing out.
Okay. So, you hungry?
A little.
Eh, let's eat.
I'm paying for lunch!
This is the first club I ever went to.
I was underage and snuck in and saw
Granddaddy in one of their first concerts.
Cool.
I remember once throwing up in that corner,
and some dude slipped in and
had to go to the hospital,
and I stole the chick he was with and shacked
up with her for like a week and a half.
Another fun memory.
How about it, guys?
You about ready to do this?
Just a few more minutes, Gary.
Where's Zach?
I don't know. He's coming separately.
Here he is.
Where you been, man?
What? Are we punching time cards now?
You almost missed sound check!
Well, almost means I didn't miss it.
Just set up your amp, okay?
Whatever.
But not there. I'm not liking the setup here.
This is how we always set up.
That's why it looks stale.
Do you want it to look stale?
No, we don't want that!
We're going to need room
for the new guy, too.
New guy?
What new guy?
Hey, Joel! Come over here, buddy.
This is Joel.
He's going to sit in on tambourine.
How you doing?
Good, Joel. Um, we added a new guy?
On tambourine?
He's going to fill out our sound.
But the only reason to have a tambourine
is if it's being played by a hot chick.
No offense, Joel, but you're not a hot chick.
Yo! Gary! See this? Remember it. It's mine.
I don't want it sucked into the club's
gear when I'm not looking.
What, the Gwen Stefani mike?
It's not a Gwen Stefani mike.
And don't take it.
You bought that mike?
It means I can crowd surf.
The audience loves that.
They do. They love crowd surfing. Dig.
Figure I'll stage side right
after our guitar solo.
Hey, can I talk to you for a second?
What is wrong with you?
Nothing. Why?
You added a band member without telling us?
Well, it's my band, right?
Uh, no, actually,
we're supposed to be a democracy.
Is this coming from Brian?
No, it's coming from me! I'm just
- concerned.
Well don't be.
And don't be a huge mega bummer before
our big show. That's not cool.
Okay, I'm sorry.
Hello?
Hey, it's me.
Who's me?
Oh my God.
You don't recognize your best friend's voice.
Sorry, Paris. There's noise here.
So, I'm returning your call.
Thanks! I just wanted to tell you something.
Brrrr! I'm coming back to Yale!
What was that sound?
That was a drum roll.
You really had to drum roll that?
Of course you're coming back.
What are you going to do without a
college degree? Drive a forklift?
Well, I was calling to ask you if you
could keep your eyes and ears open
for a place for me to live.
Mid-year like this, it's going to be tough.
I'm not picky. Plus I want to come back
to the Yale Daily News. That's a given.
Where are you right now, by the way?
I'm here. At the Daily News.
By yourself?
No, everyone's here.
I just like a super-quiet atmosphere.
No extraneous talking, and I've even
had the computer keyboards deadened.
So they're getting no break for Thanksgiving?
I put up a fold-out paper turkey
and I laid out some Oscar Meyer.
Nice.
Well, keep an eye out for
a place for me, okay?
Will do. See you.
Thanks. Bye.
So?
No sign of crying or hair being pulled out.
The thing with Dad went okay?
It was fine. He was telling the truth.
There was nothing too horrible.
Except for the frings.
The what?
Oh, the combo basket of fries and onion
rings. Good in theory, but -
So what did he want to talk to you about?
Well, his grandfather died.
Oh.
Apparently it was one of those un-sad deaths.
Like Buddy Hackett.
No-one was sad about Buddy Hackett?
No one I saw on the news.
Anyway, he left Chris money. A lot of money.
And now he's offering to shower us with it.
You want a Bentley?
I don't think so.
How about a castle?
What would I do with a castle?
I'm simply relaying the offer.
Dad should keep the money for himself.
Are you sure there's nothing you want?
A brewery, a Faberge egg,
or let's see, what else did he mention?
Um, paying for Yale through a PhD,
uh, vacations,
a cannon from the Civil War - functioning,
by the way, so it's not just show.
It seemed like the sky was the limit,
although he didn't mention the Hoover Dam,
so maybe there is a cap of some sort.
Actually, I think maybe there
is something I'd want.
Really? Okay, what?
I would maybe let him pay for Yale.
Seriously?
Yeah.
Wow.
Unless it's too much.
I think it was the cheapest of
all the things he mentioned.
It's just that there would
be residual benefits.
It would get me out from under
Grandma and Grandpa's thumb,
which sounds really good to me right now.
Well. I can't say I don't relate.
I don't want them to be holding anything over
my head. I don't want to owe them anything.
There's too much pressure. Too much expected.
There are too many strings with these people.
Okay. I'm getting very uncomfortable
with the Freaky Friday moment
we've got going on here,
'cause it means I have to go to Yale,
you have to run the inn,
and oh, God, I don't even like thinking
about what it would mean for Luke.
It's feeling better by the second, this idea.
You do understand,
you'd basically be cutting Mom and Dad off.
You don't know what it was
like to be living there.
Hello, oppressed one, class of eighty-five!
But you got out.
No, no. You were only there for three months.
You're not in my league.
We can't swap war stories yet.
They had their Reverend come over
to talk me out of having sex.
They never did that to you.
Five times they did that to me!
The last time they triple-teamed me with a
priest, a rabbi and a Mormon missionary.
I made so many jokes that night,
I should have had a microphone
and a brick wall behind me.
And I never got a forty thousand
dollar sex house.
A what?
You don't want to know.
Look. I know it's a slippery slope.
Dad is Dad.
Yes, he is.
But I'm pretty sure I want to do this.
Well, if you're sure, you're sure.
We'll call him.
He's going to be happy!
Not as happy as me.
Good.
Hey. Hey!
Wow! You look almost intimidatingly cool.
Thanks.
Everyone ready?
Pretty much,
although sound check was a little weird.
Well, you know what they say.
Weird sound check, good gig.
Who says that?
Well, just me. But I'm hoping it'll catch on.
See those two guys?
Those are the label guys.
Oh. I'll be careful not to hurt them
when I start violently slam-dancing.
You're going to be great.
Thanks. I should get back there.
We have this pre-show thing we always do.
Good luck!
Test. Test. Test.
Monitor check! Monitor check!
Test! Test! Test! Test!
Where'd they get these monitors, the Kremlin?
Test! Test!
It's your wireless mic, dude.
It's not working.
Well, did somebody touch it?
Because it was working before.
One minute, guys.
Who says one minute? We go on when we go on!
No-one tells Axl Rose when he goes on,
he goes on when he feels like it.
You're comparing yourself to Axl Rose?
- Don't get in my face, Brian.
- I'm not.
Go write some more songs
if you've got a problem.
All right! Welcome to the New Deck!
Listen, we're throwing out the set list.
What?
Keep up. I'm going to be calling
out tunes like Jack White.
But we rehearsed in this order.
We've got transitions.
Yeah! REO Speedwagon had transitions, too!
You want to be REO Speedwagon?
We should have brought the smoke machine!
We've got a special showcase for you tonight.
Give it up for Connecticut's own Hep Alien!
Wait, wait,
we didn't do our lucky pre-show thing!
Lane, count it down!
What are we playing?
Yeah, what are we playing?
Check, one, two, check, check!
Dude, what are we playing?
I need to be hotter in the monitor, Gary!
Wake up, dude!
Come on, let's start!
Hey, I know that guy.
We'll start when I'm ready. This is my stage.
Come on, let's do Rebecca.
Just hang on,
it's worth waiting around to see the band
that's going to get the biggest
record deal in history.
This is pathetic.
You guys suck!
Freebird!
Hey! Knock it off.
Knock what off?
You know what you're doing!
Get back to your mike.
- Get back!
- Zach!
Don't kick him.
Get off my stage if you've got a problem!
Nobody's going to tell me what to
do on my stage with my band!
Dude, you need to find another place to
stand. I'm not going to tell you again.
If he moves, he's going to block Lane.
Oh, yeah, you don't want Lane blocked,
do you?
Come on!
This is a song called Stella.
We haven't learned that song!
Let's go back to the set list!
No, we're not going to do that. I'm here to
destroy the system so stay out of my way!
Hey!
And you don't need to -
Dude broke my wireless mike.
Zach. What is wrong with you?
Nothing.
Nothing?
This was a disaster.
The guys from the label were there!
They showed up! It was our shot!
We worked so hard to get to this point,
and we blew our big shot!
What the hell is wrong with you?
You let me down tonight. You let down Gil,
you let down Brian -
I don't want to hear about Brian!
Zach!
This is what it is, okay?
Maybe this is why people
in bands shouldn't date.
Yeah.
I guess so.
Hey, guys!
Happy Thanksgiving!
Hey, Dad!
Come here, you.
God, I've missed you!
Have you grown? She's grown!
Only in my estimation.
I, I cannot tell you how jazzed I
am to see you on Thanksgiving!
You know,
we've never seen each other on Thanksgiving.
- Oh, God, is that true?
- I think so.
I know so.
So, uh, what's this about?
I filled Rory in. I mentioned the brewery,
and the castle.
- The Oompa Loompas?
- Those too.
And, um - well, you want to take it?
Sure.
Dad, I - I thought about it,
and Mom and I talked about it,
and I think it would be really great
if you could pay for Yale.
Absolutely, absolutely!
Nothing would make me happier.
Good. Thank you.
I am there, I am so there.
That's great.
Let me pay for Chilton too.
Well, that's already taken care of.
You know, Yale's kind of expensive.
But I'm loaded
- didn't you tell her? I'm loaded!
I told her.
So, how do I do this? Do I give you the cash,
or do I pay Yale?
Do they take checks or does it
have to be a money order?
What is a money order anyway? I mean,
how is it different from a check?
Isn't a check a piece of paper forwarding
money? What's the difference?
Whoa, Chris, slow down.
This makes me so happy,
I can't tell you, Rory.
It means a lot to me, Dad.
This was excellent timing, believe me.
Well, it means more to me.
This is the paper in Stamford. Excuse me.
Hey, try to steal a pie on the way out.
Okay.
Thanks for making this happen, Lor.
Hey, it wasn't me. It's what she wanted.
Well, thanks for giving her the choice.
My pleasure.
So can I ask you something?
Sure.
It involves the E word and the R word.
Please, let's not discuss evolution or
recycling. They're just too hot-button.
Weren't Emily and Richard paying for Yale?
Yes, they were.
Something going on there?
Everything's fine.
Why'd she take time off? What happened there?
It's - it's a long story.
Listen, Chris, just so we're clear -
We're clear. I'm providing. That's it.
I'm just doing what I should
have done years ago.
Good.
And it will remain good. Honest.
Okay.
So how long have you been engaged?
Who told you?
Your finger.
Oh. Blabbermouth.
It's a good thing. I want you happy,
I always have.
I know, thank you.
But, this isn't going to be a weird thing
with you and him, is it? My paying for Yale.
No, it's not going to be.
Well, cool.
You're getting a Rolls for a wedding present,
you know.
Cool, I should register for
a driver to go with it.
Well, yeah,
they're too big to drive by yourself.
No, God,
you've got to have somebody drive you.
Bye, now. Have a nice -
Thanksgiving. Huh?
My rolls exploded!
What do you mean, they exploded?
They turned black and they exploded!
- Well, clean them up. I'm not going to -
- My turkey!
Liz?
Oh, boy, oh, boy!
It's like Motley Crue's been here.
Good, that red button thingy
hasn't popped up yet.
Look, you're way over-cooking
your stuffing, here.
Hey, how do you turn on your oven light?
Never mind, I'll check my Martha.
How to turn on my oven light is not going
to be in your Martha Stewart book.
Hey, that red pop-up thingy. Are turkeys born
with that or is that something they put in?
I don't know, why don't you ask Martha?
Oh, she knows. She knows everything.
Hey, you're going to have to get
some canned cranberry sauce.
Your homemade
- well, it's not red. It should be red.
I know, I don't know how that happened.
Well, everything seems kind
of under control here.
Thanks, Luke. I'm so sorry, TJ thought the
microwave was working but I guess not.
It's okay.
Liz -
Look at Martha's hands! They're so white!
Liz, you got a minute?
Yeah, big brother, I got a minute.
Um, this is hard, I -
I feel like this giant weight's
been sitting on me, I just - I
just need someone to talk to.
Well, then talk.
I've got a kid.
A kid? You've got a kid?
A girl. A little girl. She's twelve.
I am her father.
Oh, boy, oh boy!
She came to the diner out of the blue and she
was testing to see who her father was.
Not for money or anything,
it was for this science fair she was in.
She's smart.
Oh, boy, oh, boy!
So I went down to the fair and there she was.
You know, and there I was.
My picture, the DNA test.
She's mine.
- Twelve, huh?
- Twelve.
That's Anna Nardini, isn't it?
How'd you know?
Luke, you're not Warren Beatty. I mean,
you could have been, girls like you,
but you're a serial monogamist.
That's why you're you.
I remember Anna, I liked her!
I don't know what to do.
I'm just so confused.
Well, what did Lorelai say?
You haven't told her.
We're engaged, we're on track here,
her and me.
And Rory's back, so that's settled now.
We're in a good place!
You know, this could wreck it.
It won't wreck it. Not unless you let it.
She's been out there twelve years,
this little girl!
What does Anna want from you?
That's the thing. Nothing.
She hasn't contacted me.
I mean, why hasn't she?
She could have called me.
What? Does she think I'd be a deadbeat?
Oh! No one would think that.
April doesn't want anything either.
That's her name. April.
You know,
it's all just very scientific with her.
I couldn't even get her to
go for ice cream with me.
Whoa.
Did you offer cake?
No.
Maybe she wanted cake. Or pie. You offer pie?
Maybe she wanted pie. Or fudge.
It's not about what I offered her, Liz.
She didn't have any interest.
You know, that's the thing.
Why should I feel burdened?
I mean, they're not reaching out.
Neither one of them. So why should I?
I don't know -
I mean, the girl's got her life.
She seems very adjusted, a little weird,
but thriving.
Anna's got her life, I've got my life,
you know.
I shouldn't worry about this. I mean,
why should I? There's no reason to.
I guess not.
Good. Good.
I'm not going to worry.
I'm going to let it go.
Yeah, this has been good.
Thanks for listening, Liz. I feel better.
Well, you should get back
to your food, there.
This is settled.
Okay.
All right.
There's your Martha.
Thanks.
Everyone's here, everyone's hungry!
Perfect timing, 'cause Tree,
Chuck and Bob here are ready to be consumed.
Please, don't name the food we eat.
Sorry.
So are you ready to carve?
We're ready to carve.
I could use some help, though.
Maybe send Luke in.
He loves to carve.
There's enough food, right?
Did I make enough food?
There's plenty,
even considering the extra guests.
Good. Go tell them it'll be five minutes.
Will do.
Huzzah!
You're so good at that, Stu! Really.
Too bad you didn't put all that effort
into something you can make money at.
Thanks, Liz.
So, when are you coming back out on the
Renaissance Fair circuit with us, Luke?
I think sometime after I'm
drugged and lobotomized.
You're the funniest,
smartest guy I know, Luke.
I'm calling him Yakov from now on.
Please don't judge me by this.
I won't. Yakov.
We're just minutes away
from eating, everybody!
Oh, I can't wait to see this meal!
My dinner didn't turn out
like Martha's picture.
Who knew a turkey could melt like that?
I didn't.
Hey, guys, when'd you sneak in?
Oh, just a couple minutes ago.
How'd you like to carve for us?
I'll carve if you want.
Bless you. Um, let me talk to you
over here for a second first.
Oh, okay.
- So.
- Yeah?
Um. That Christopher call from before,
the famous one?
The infamous one.
Oh, you remember that?
I remember it.
Well, I never filled you in on the content.
He said he wanted to talk and he said it
was important, so I met up with him.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah. And he's come into a lot of money,
family money.
And he offered Rory and me lots of
things we didn't want or need,
but Rory took him up on his
offer to pay for Yale.
It was her idea and I support it. That's it.
So he's going to be financing her
tuition this year and next year
and, um, we got together today at a diner
to finalize it, and that's it.
I think that's great.
Really?
Yes. I think that's absolutely great.
You heard the part about how I
got together with Christopher?
Absolutely. You had to, to talk about this.
He's her dad. He's her dad.
If he's got something,
he should be sharing it, good for him.
He's been gone most of the time,
so he owes you. I'm glad he's doing it.
He's doing what a dad is supposed to do.
He's taking care of his kid. Good. Good.
Yeah, good. So you're good with this.
I am.
And so we're good.
We're great.
Thank you for understanding.
I'm going to go carve.
Okay.
Oh, Rory, have you met Freddy?
He has no thumbs.
No, I haven't. Hi, Freddy.
Hi!
Excuse me.
Hello?
Rory, hi! It's Honor Huntzberger.
Oh, hi, Honor. How are you doing?
I've been exiled.
My parent's house is eleven
thousand square feet
and smoking is banned from every
nook and cranny of it.
Only because Mom stopped smoking again.
So, here I am, freezing my ass off.
Bummer.
So, I thought I'd call and tell you what a
drag it is, this thing with you and Logan.
Oh, yeah?
When Logan said you two broke up,
I almost threw a lamp at him.
Moron. He's his own worst enemy.
He told you that we broke up?
Well, I was wondering where
you were for Thanksgiving,
and at first young Seacrest hemmed and hawed,
which wasn't sufficient,
so he finally told me.
Idiot. Him, not you.
Right.
I'm so sorry.
But you and I can still go shopping,
you know.
Bergdorf's is calling.
Yeah. Sure.
Good. Well, I have to get back inside
before I turn into an ice cube.
Are you at least having a nice Thanksgiving?
Yeah. It's really nice.
I'll be in touch.
Sure.
Thanks, Honor.
- Bye.
Okay, that's too thin, too thin!
I'm just getting started, give me some room.
Okay, that's too thick, too thick, too thick!
Hang on, Sookie.
You’re crooked. Crooked.
Okay.
Good idea.
Information, listing please?
Yeah, uh, Nardini?
- City?
- Woodbridge.
- Please hold.
- Thanks.
Press one to be connected to area code -
Hello. You've reached the Nardini residence.
We're not home, or else we're too distracted
to answer right now, so -
- She kick you out?
- What? Who?
- Sookie.
- Oh, yeah.
Predictable.
Yeah, predictable.
Hey! You okay?
- Kind of.
- You sure?
I'm just hungry.
Dinner is served!
öwww.tvsubtitles.netö