Okay, I got a meeting in half an hour,
so I better run.
Okay, well, have a great day.
- Thanks again for breakfast.
- My pleasure.
You make a hell of a frittata.
Well, it's ma specialty.
What time will you be home?
Around 6:00-ish.
All right,
I might make a frittata for dinner.
Ooh, sounds good.
- Have a great day, honey.
- Bye, hon.
- So what'd you think?
- Frittata?
- Felt pretty good, huh?
- No, it did.
It's homey.
Home-ish. Home-like.
Margaret, what did you think?
You seemed like real
people in a real house.
Wow. What about the lighting?
Well, you can see there's lots of
windows, lots of natural sunlight.
- But how do we look?
- Excuse me?
In the lighting,
how do we look?
Oh, right.
At least 10 years younger.
- Than...
- Hmm?
Well, if you think we're 60 and
the lighting makes us look 50,
then this room is aging us,
and that's not good.
- You look 20.
- Very good!
This house was
originally built in 1790
but obviously has been
completely remodeled.
All new appliances.
three fireplaces.
Proximity to an excellent
school district.
The large backyard.
Great tree-house-building trees.
Ooh, fun.
So I'm gonna make a quick call.
Take your time. Look around.
Make yourselves at home.
Well, I don't have to
tell you two that.
I'll be right outside, so just
holler if you have any questions.
Thank you. We will.
- So...
- So?
- I told you it was a really cool house.
- It is.
- And that yard?
- Oh, love the yard.
And I know it's not Stars Hollow,
but it's a really cool town.
And bigger.
Lots of places to eat and shop.
Three bookstores?
I mean, this is a well-read community.
We might be the
dumbest people in town.
Yeah, we could be the town dunces.
We'll buy caps.
We'll put "The Dunces"
on our mailbox.
That mailbox!
What is that,
a hollowed-out birch tree or something?
The second-floor bedroom --
that's perfect for G.G.
And the third-floor room,
the one with the really cool windows --
that could be Rory's room.
Honey, I can't imagine
a better house.
Big front yard.
Could be our front yard.
- Yeah.
What's with the face?
Face? What face? It's my face.
You don't like my face?
- Lor.
- Hmm?
You want to stay
in Stars Hollow.
Yeah.
You want to stay in your house.
You don't want to move at all.
Yeah.
Okay.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- It's a hell of a mailbox, though.
- Sure is.
- You're here.
- I'm here!
You're 37 minutes late,
but you're here.
Uh, traffic.
It's sunday morning, Lorelai.
The roads are empty.
Will you let me finish, mom?
Traffic cones everywhere.
I mean, you wouldn't believe it. It's
like a crazy obstacle course out there.
It's a miracle I survived.
Maybe we should do
this another day
when I'm less stressed from
the traffic-cone dodging.
I have the most exciting news.
You're  canceling
my wedding party?
I got Randall Farber
as your party planner.
He's canceling my
wedding party?
He spent the last 15 years
as designer-in-residence
at the Connecticut Opera House.
Boss.
This is a real coup, Lorelai.
Your father and I have been
fans of his work for years,
and he's only just
begun designing parties.
Two months ago, we went to Abigail
Hirschfeld's granddaughter's bar mitzvah,
and it was the most
spectacular event.
The whole decor was inspired by
Britten's "A Midsummer Night's Dream."
I swear I felt like I was in an
enchanted forest the entire night,
except for the children
running around with braces.
Randall, this is my
daughter, Lorelai.
Lorelai, Randall Farber.
- Hello.
- Ah, the star of our show.
Oh, well...
I apologize for her tardiness.
It's rather habitual.
Oh, stop.
You're talking to an opera man.
I've worked with Renée Fleming.
The personality of a pit bull,
that one,
but all is forgiven when she sings,
am I right?
Well, heads-up, I'm not much of
an outside-the-shower singer.
I hope you realize how lucky you
are to have Randall, Lorelai.
- He's a genius.
- Oh, stop.
Shall we?
Please.
The first order of business
is deciding on a theme
around which I can
design the evening.
How about "Man's
inhumanity to man"?
It always worked well for my
term papers in high school.
Why don't you show us
what you're thinking?
I've done a few mock-up tables.
Just tell me which one
- jumps out at you.
- Um, they all jump out at me.
- Kind of aggressively.
- Lorelai.
Well, I just don't want it
to be a big production, mom.
It's just a party.
My dear,
every party's a production.
If it's a lousy production,
it's a lousy party
and everyone leaves by 8:30.
What about that as a theme?
"Everyone leaves by 8:30."
Tell me about this one.
You've got your stoking plant,
your festive ornament collage,
your snowman trio,
your peekaboo Santa.
Well, it's lovely, Kirk,
but I already bought my wrapping paper
from the kids from the
Stars Hollow middle school.
- Well, then, you got ripped off.
- What?
Those kids are gouging you.
I'm selling the same
wrapping paper for 20% less.
Aren't the kids selling
the wrapping paper
to help raise money
for a new gymnasium?
- Yeah.
- Well, why are you?
To raise money for myself.
I'm not a school, Luke.
No one's raising money for me.
I saw the opportunity to enter
the market at a lower price point
- and I took it.
- Ho, ho, ho.
What, schoolchildren are the only
ones allowed to sell wrapping paper?
It's a free country.
Hey, Jacob! Beat it.
This is my territory.
Fathead.
Yeah, keep walking.
- Look who's here.
- Oh, my god!
She's precious.
Oh, those eyes, that skin --
she's gorgeous.
That's what everyone says.
- Hey, Liz.
- Hi, Luke.
Oh, she's bigger.
- 11 pounds, 4 ounces.
- She looks great.
I know.
She's really strong, too.
She can practically
hold her head up.
Most kids don't do that
until they're two months.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Come on over and sit down.
- Oh, sure.
She's really strong, too.
She takes after T.J.
He's really strong, you know.
We've been watching "Survivor"
sometimes, you know,
and he does the challenges,
you know,
like standing on one leg or
dragging the sandbags around,
and he lasts longer than
the guys on the show.
Wow.
You know,
baby's first Christmas is approaching.
Have you given thought to what baby's
first Christmas gift will be wrapped in?
No.
I have baby Santa,
cuddly reindeers, Frosty's world --
Kirk.
Yeah, okay.
So is April excited
about being a cousin?
Yeah. I showed her
the pictures you sent
and she's gonna frame the one
of her in the orange jumper.
Oh, that is such a good one!
She looks like a
little creamsicle.
- She's very photogenic, huh?
- Yeah.
And how are things with Anna?
We're trading calls.
It'll work out.
I mean, I've calmed down
a little since the fight.
It'll all work itself out.
I'm sure.
Actually, I made a list.
I think it's pretty reasonable.
I was thinking I could have April
either Thanksgiving or Christmas --
Anna can choose.
One month of the summer.
And I think I would like
April to come to Stars Hollow
one weekend every other month.
In between,
I can travel to New Mexico.
That sounds fair, right?
Very reasonable.
But I definitely think
you need to get a lawyer.
No lawyers.
Anna and I are gonna work
this out on our own.
That's what you think now,
big brother, but trust me --
custody issues are tough.
Well, I don't like lawyers.
Well, nobody does.
Wait. She's staring at you.
She is!
She's staring at you,
and she's falling asleep.
Great. I'm gonna
leave her with you,
and I'll be back in an hour.
- What?
- Oh, I'm going crazy.
- I just need a minute to myself.
- Liz...
She's been attached to
my boob for two weeks,
and T.J.'s decided to
finally get a "work ethic."
You can't just leave her here.
I can't watch her.
I fed her. She'll be fine.
She'll sleep the whole time.
- Wait, Liz --
- I'll be back in an hour,
maybe an hour and a half.
So why don't we take
our inspiration from
the world of "La Bohème,"
fin de siècle Paris?
A little birdie told me you had quite
the romantic parisian adventure.
Tweet, tweet.
I must confess --
this is my personal favorite.
I must admit I
have a soft spot,
for it was while I was doing "La
Bohème" at the Staatsoper in Vienna
that I met the incomparable
Franco Zeffirelli,
whose meticulous
attention to detail
has been a yardstick for
which I measure all my work.
Your details are simply
astounding, Randall.
What about instead of "La Bohème," we
took our inspiration from "Rent" --
East Village, 1985,
rickety tables,
chipped glassware...
- Lorelai.
- Excuse me.
Hello?
How goes the party planning?
What? What happened?
- That good, huh?
- Is he okay?
I'm not participating in this.
Oh, my god. What can I do?
What do you need?
You're not using this phone call
to get out of party-planning hell.
Oh, I'll be right there.
Mom!
I can hear Rory on the
other end, Lorelai.
You're not as clever
as you think you are.
You rat.
- Hi, grandma.
- Hello, Rory.
That's my granddaughter, Rory.
Delightful girl.
- She's a senior at Yale.
- Fantastic theater program --
Meryl, Jodie.
- Uh, I thought we had a deal.
- We had no deal.
No, a deal for life.
You've got my back. I've got yours.
I plan on having a good
time at your wedding party.
More importantly,
I plan on making sure
that you have a good time
at your wedding party.
Therefore, I think it's important
that you be involved in the planning
of your wedding party,
so in the big picture,
I do very much have your back.
Yeah, whatever.
Okay. Bad news.
I'm afraid I have to bail on
you and dad for dinner tonight.
Mm-hmm. Logan?
Yeah, he's coming to stay
with me for a couple days.
He's been so busy with the start-up,
I've hardly gotten to see him lately.
Okay. Can't see you through the phone,
but I'm pouting.
- I'll make it up to you.
- Is he coming to the party?
I'm trying to pat the guest list.
If he's coming, I'm in the double digits.
- He'll be there.
- Awesome.
So okay,
I'll call you later, okay?
The stairs are rickety,
and you think you might fall down them?
M om.
The pool is empty,
and you've hit your head?
- Goodbye.
- Okay, bye.
Lorelai, come look at
these invitations.
Can we just send an evite?
No? Okay.
Two hours we spent
picking out invitations.
- Two hours.
- Wow.
Not counting the one hour we spent
picking out the calligraphy -- for
a party.
This is gonna be some shindig.
"Would you like the brown card
with the cream-colored detail
and  the parchment insert, or
would you like the cream-colored card
with the silk lining and
the clear paper insert?"
How about I'd like some cyanide
and a 30-story building
to jump off of?
No, we said one sugar cereal.
You're gonna deny
me the captain?
We've got a whole box
of Froot Loops at home.
With my fragile state,you're gonna
deny me peanut butter Cap'n Crunch?
- It rips your gums...
- In a delightful, sugary way.
Look, it's got 5% real
peanut-butter-flavored chemicals.
- No.
- Oh, fine. Corn flakes.
Which one do we get again?
Avoid the words "made
with real vegetables."
I cannot take another
day of Emily and Randall,
and I have nine
more days of it.
That's nine more days
than I can take.
Oh, you're doing great.
I'm not doing great.
I'm going nuts.
Tomorrow we have the food-and-wine
tasting at the Mildred Manor ballroom.
No. Fancy people make
you spit out the wine.
That's what fancy people do.
But not me.
I'm gonna drink them
under the ballroom.
- What time's the tasting?
- 3:30 till the end of never.
I've got a meeting in Hartford at 2:00,
but I can meet you there afterward.
- Really?
- Yes.
Honey, that would be so great.
I will never eat peanut butter Cap'n
Crunch again. Yes, I will. That's a lie.
But together,
we can defeat them.
This is serious. I don't want to get
the wrong-colored parchment insert.
The guys at the gym would
never let me live it down.
- We got everything?
- Yeah, we're good.
- Oh, no.
- What?
- Bonnie.
- Who?
Taylor's niece, Bonnie,
working the register.
She couldn't be slower or
care less about her job.
I thought life in a small town
was supposed to be leisurely.
There's leisurely,
and then there's Bonnie.
We're never gonna
get out of here.
Go wait outside.
- Really?
- Go.
Honey, buy me Tic Tacs.
Hi, Bonnie.
What's up, Lorelai?
That's cabbage, hon.
I'm gonna need a void here.
- Hi.
- Hey.
- Who's -- who's this?
- That's Liz's baby.
Oh, wow. Congratulations.
You're an uncle again, huh?
Yeah, thanks.
Oh. Well, she's cute.
She looks just like T.J.
Hopefully she will
grow out of that.
Oh, she's adorable.
She's sweet.
- So what's her name?
- Doula.
- What?
- Oh, is that...
- A weird name.
Weird name. A little bit.
But, no, it's special.
It's one-of-a-kind, distinctive.
Can I?
Oh, sure, of course.
Hi. Hi, bubby.
Hi. Oh, precious.
- How old is she? Two weeks?
- 11 days.
Oh, wow. And how's Liz?
Oh, they're great.
They're both doing great.
They're gonna make very strange parents
but, you know, good ones, I know.
Nothing wrong with a strange
but loving household.
Yeah, I guess.
Look at her long fingers.
Yeah, I noticed that, too.
What are you gonna be --
a pianist when you grow up?
Is that what you're gonna be,
pretty girl?
Or a pickpocket.
Well, yes, you might.
You might be a
pickpocketing pianist.
Oh, look what she did.
- Pretty.
- She's trying to take my finger.
Hey.
Hey. Look. It's Liz's new baby.
- Cute.
- Yeah.
Well, thanks, um,
for letting me hold her.
And tell Liz congratulations
for me, okay?
- Will do.
- All right.
-  See you.
- See you.
- Want me to --
- I got it.
Okay.
We don't have to eat here.
Oh, yes, we do.
You're on my turf now.
- Your turf.
- My turf.
You know,
I did go to school here.
Yeah, you graduated from Yale.
You can eat from their
cafeteria at least once.
I stopped by for the
occasional bowl of cereal.
Yeah, cereal does
not count, okay?
You need to get something hot,
mushy, and meaty.
You're not making it
sound too appetizing.
Oh, it's not. I have an extra
family pass from parents' weekend.
Oh, so when your parents came to visit,
they got to eat real food?
I'm gonna tell them
that you're my brother
and that you're gonna
get your meal comped.
I don't mind paying
for my mushy meat.
No, that's not the issue.
I mean, I know how to work the system.
Oh, you do.
Yeah, you know me --
I can be crafty.
Yeah, you can be crafty,
you can make a necklace out of macaroni,
but this is
high-stakes deception.
What's my middle name?
Rory "high-stakes deception" Gilmore.
- Card.
- There you go.
And this is my family
pass for my brother here.
Logan!
What's up, brother?
What the hell are you doing here?
I thought you moved to
London to run the world or something.
Just back for a visit.
My brother went here, too.
Is this your girlfriend, Rory?
I don't know. Is it?
I'm a terrible liar.
Apparently so.
- Hi. I'm Rory.
- Brandon. Nice to meet you.
You too.
So, Dennis,
how much is a lunch pass?
$9.75.
So you're still with Nicole?
Yeah, till I die
or she kills me.
- Well, give her my best.
- Will do, buddy.
- Good to see you, Logan.
- You, too.
- Nice to meet you, Rory.
- You too. Bye.
- Smooth.
- Shut up.
- Man, you worked the system.
- You totally left me hanging there.
What could I do?
You were working the system.
In fact, you were working the system so
well, I think the system needs a day off.
I'll have the chicken, and he'll
have the meat loaf with extra gravy.
- Nice.
- Mm-hmm.
Oh, hey, there's Lucy. Lucy!
Hi!
You must be Rory's
imaginary boyfriend, Logan.
- Hi, Lucy.
- Hi.
I would give you a proper hug,
but my pockets are full of Apple Jacks.
I have art history
in a few minutes,
and my professor sounds like
Garrison Keillor on quaaludes,
so I need a constant intake
of sugar just to stay awake.
I was just treating Logan to his
first branford dining hall meat loaf.
Oh, you're in for a
treat and a stomachache.
I can tell.
So, congratulations on buying
the internet or something.
Thank you, although Al Gore
and I are still negotiating.
So it's not a done deal yet.
It's too bad that you have class.
You could have eaten with us.
Sad. Hey,
why don't we have dinner?
I have a lecture tonight,
but what about tomorrow night?
- Sure.
- Sounds good.
Fun! We'll have to
go to Panchali's.
It's this new indian
restaurant right off campus.
It's awesome, and I swear,
no matter how much food you order,
you cannot spend
more than 7 bucks.
Sounds like
stomachache number two.
- Hey, babe. Come on.
- Boyfriend!
Boyfriend, this is Rory's
imaginary boyfriend, Logan.
I know Marty.
How you doing, man?
Hey.
How do you two know each other?
We met when I was bartending
one of Logan's parties.
What a coinkydink.
- Yeah.
- More than one.
He did a couple blowouts for me,
and if I'm not mistaken,
at the last one,
cops were called.
That sounds familiar.
You know, you probably met Marty, too,
and you just didn't even know it.
We should go. I need to stop
by the library before class.
Right. Okay, bye, guys.
We will see you tomorrow
for basmati and vindaloo.
- Okay. Bye.
- Later.
Okay. Come on.
- Is this okay?
- Fine.
So, what's with that? What's with
the whole "you must have met Marty"?
Oh, I meant to tell you.
Tell me what?
It's kind of embarrassing.
It's so juvenile and lame.
It's like high school --
not even high school.
- It's junior high.
- I'm listening.
Well, I've been hanging
out with Lucy and Olivia
and I keep hearing
about Lucy's boyfriend,
and they never actually
said his name.
And then when I finally met him,
it was Marty.
And before I could even say anything,
he just pretended like we've never met.
And I just didn't know what to do,
so I went along with it,
but now Lucy still doesn't
know that we know each other.
It's just kind of
weird and awkward.
And did I mention juvenile?
Why did you go along with it?
I don't know. It just happened so fast.
I was caught off guard.
So why would he pretend
not to know you?
I don't know.
I mean, maybe because he used to like
me, and maybe he still does a little.
But that's stupid, because he's
with Lucy now, and she's amazing.
They're great together.
And it's all so annoying.
I mean, they don't call people by name.
They don't call anyone by name.
French-fry guy -- I don't know
who that is. That could be you.
- So what happened?
- What do you mean?
He must have said or
done something, right?
To make you think
he's still into you.
I don't know.
He said I was beautiful.
To me, he said it.
Can't blame the guy for that.
You are beautiful.
- The way he said it.
- Right.
Yeah.
So what?
You guys have been hanging out?
No. No, I mean,
just when he's around with Lucy.
So you have been hanging out.
Just with Lucy.
So why the secrecy?
I told you,
I was caught off guard.
No, with me.
Why did you never mention
that you and Marty were
hanging out again?
I just didn't
think it mattered.
You're not the
secret-keeping type.
Of course, that is before I knew you were
Rory "high-stakes deception" Gilmore.
No, it wasn't a secret.
I mean, I didn't tell you.
That's it. I swear.
I mean, I didn't not tell you.
I just didn't think there
was anything to tell.
Well, you have to tell Lucy.
I know.
I will.
Just, I need to figure out the
right time and way to do it.
I just don't want to
screw anything up.
A little brotherly advice --
tell her sooner rather than later.
Yeah, I will.
I'll figure something out.
We don't have to go to dinner with them,
though. I can cancel that.
No, it's fine.
We can go to dinner.
Unless there's
something on your end.
No.
Logan, god, no.
Good. Then let's go to dinner.
Okay.
Really, they charge
10 bucks for this?
Let's make a baby.
- What do you mean?
- Seriously.
- Christopher.
- What?
- What are you talking about?
- Why not?
What?
Why not?
Because we haven't talked
about it at all -- ever.
Okay, well,
let's talk about it.
Okay.
You want another kid,
don't you?
Oh, god.
Uh, I don't know. I, um...
- Sure, maybe.
- Me too.
And, you know, last one
turned out pretty good, so...
Last one didn't turn
out pretty good.
Last one came out
and a lot of work went into
getting her to pretty good.
You're right. You're right.
I'm -- I'm sorry.
It's okay.
No, you're right.
You're absolutely right.
But, um, it's different now.
We're adults. We're married.
It'd be easier.
Yeah.
I guess. I don't know.
I think...
I want another kid.
Okay, well,
we're on the same page.
Let's go for it.
Honey... Chris... honey...
Seriously -- seriously,
I don't want to go for it right now.
Why not?
Why not? We just got married.
I mean,
G.G.'s not even back from France.
So you don't want
to because of G.G.?
No, I mean,
it's not because of G.G.
Because financially, we're good.
We're set.
We could have a thousand kids,
feed them,
send them to Harvard undergrad,
law school.
No, I know.
Do you not think we'll work?
What?
Because if that's what you're thinking,
it's a little late.
Oh, my god, no.
That's not what I'm thinking.
That's not what I'm
thinking at all.
What are you thinking?
I just -- What is this?
What is the rush? Why right now?
Chris.
Yeah. No, it's fine.
- Honey...
- No, you're right.
We should wait.
We should. You're right.
- Cesar, what time you got?
- 10 after 2:00.
All right. Well, as soon as April
gets here, we're gonna have to run,
'cause we're gonna
miss the movie.
- I'm feeling you.
- Stop feeling me.
So business has been
going like gangbusters.
Congratulations.
Yeah, I'm destroying those
Stars Hollow middle school kids.
Destroying --
outselling them by three or four times.
I think it's safe to say they won't be
getting their new gym anytime soon.
You must be very proud.
I am.
Sure there's been an increase in
prank phone calls, but so what?
I can answer the
phone all day long.
I'm sure.
And so they've ordered pizzas
to my house day and night.
You know what? I love pizza.
Bring it on.
They think they're intimidating me,
but I'm not scared.
12-year-olds don't scare you.
Not at all.
Kirk!
I thought I told
you to get lost.
We want to talk.
So talk.
Not here. Outside.
All right. Let's go.
But I'm warning you -- if it gets
physical, I will show no mercy.
Hello?
Hey, Anna, it's Luke.
Yeah?
Yeah, I was just wondering
if April took off.
She's not here yet,
and she's never late.
I'm just getting
a little worried.
- April's fine.
- Is she on her way?
No, she's not coming.
What does that mean?
Luke, you can't just come to my house,
threaten me,
and then expect me to send
April off to see you.
Look, things got a little
heated the other night.
Yes, they certainly did,
and frankly,
I'm not comfortable with April
being with you right now.
Anna, wait.
No, Luke, I won't,
because this is my decision.
Goodbye.
So we moved away from a literal
theme as per our star's request.
- Star -- that's me.
- Yeah, I got it.
We did manage to squeeze some favorite
colors out of her, didn't we?
Yellow, like my
sunny disposition.
Eh, eh, eh. Not yellow.
Buttercup and buttercream.
Do you like buttercream
and buttermilk, honey?
Or would you like
a nondairy color?
Please say you like them.
I've coordinated everything.
It's fine.
So of course this area will be
for the tables, as discussed.
The orchestra -- excuse me --
band will be over there.
And obviously,
the dance floor is right here.
Actually, I'm morally
opposed to dancing,
so that's not
gonna work for me.
She's just kidding.
I'm so glad you're here. Maybe you can
help keep Lorelai's snarkiness in check.
Let's see what
he's got planned.
So we still have to
decide on the score.
Have you made a list of
your favorite music?
No list necessary. It's going to be
Burt Bacharach. And nothing but.
Really?
- We'll make a list.
- Wonderful.
- Hey, you okay?
- Yeah. I'm fine.
Now, for the fish course, I believe
we have either a Pouilly Fuissé
or a Muscat,
if you go with the salmon,
and I do think you should
go with the salmon.
Agreed.
Now, as far as the vows go --
I'm sorry. The vows?
Wedding vows.
What are you talking about?
They can be traditional,
or you can write your own,
which seems to be the style, nowadays,
although if you ask me, it's rather garish.
Cecily Pendelem's daughter
actually promised
to cook her husband
lasagna once a month.
Who wants to hear the word
"lasagna" at a wedding?
Well, you make a good point, but this
is not a wedding. It's just a party.
A party to celebrate
a marriage,
which is why a simple exchange
of vows is entirely appropriate.
Mom, we agreed to a party, okay?
Just a party.
A wedding is a party.
Yes, but we are
already married.
Yes, and no one
got to witness it.
Did it ever occur to you
that your father and I
might like to see our
only child get married?
- Christopher?
- I don't think it's such a bad idea.
- What?
- Might be kind of nice.
Wait a minute. Is this an ambush?
Are you guys ambushing me?
No one is ambushing
you, Lorelai.
The idea of your exchanging vows in
front of your family and friends
isn't so outrageous.
Mom, the whole reason we eloped
is to avoid the wedding thing.
No, that's not the reason we eloped.
We eloped because
we love each other and we
wanted to get married.
- You know what I mean.
- No, I don't.
- Chris.
- What is the big deal?
The big deal is I don't want to
do it and we're already married.
- So that's it.
- Well...
I don't even know why I'm here.
It's not like my opinion really matters.
Of course it does.
You're gonna do what
you want to do.
House, wedding, kids --
it's all your call, right?
Are you talking about
having more children?
Thank you.
- Wait! Are you pregnant?
- No
- That's nice.
- What?
You don't have to act like it's the
most horrible thing in the world.
Can we not talk about this now?
Why? You don't want to be spur-
of-the-moment? Let's discuss things.
Randall, perhaps we should
give them some privacy.
Of course.
- What is wrong with you?
- What's wrong with you?
You're airing all our business in
front of my mother of all people.
What is your problem
with a wedding?
We're already married.
Exactly, so what's the big deal? You
planned a huge wedding with that diner guy.
"That diner guy"?
Oh, I'm sorry,
should I be more respectful
to the guy who punched
me in the face?
- Is that what this is about?
- No, this is about us.
At least, that's what I thought,
but apparently it's about you.
What is that supposed to mean?
You know what?
I'm going back to work.
No, no. Christopher, hey.
So you want to sue for custody.
No, I don't want to sue her.
I just want...
this or something like this.
- So you want partial custody.
- Is that what that is?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, fine.
Then I want partial custody.
Then you have to sue for it.
- Really?
- Really.
But you're not gonna get this.
Why not?
From everything you've just told me,
this is a best-case scenario,
and I'm not really in the
best-case-scenario business.
What does that mean?
It means you haven't been in
April's life for the past 12 years.
But that wasn't my fault.
I didn't know she existed.
- Doesn't matter.
- How can it not matter?
Because she has a
history with her mother.
This is not about
what you want, Luke.
what Anna wants.
The court only cares
what's best for April,
and in these types of cases,
they almost always
side with the mother.
So what can I do?
You can fight.
You can make your case.
- Okay.
What about Anna's history?
- Anna's?
- Any police records? Incidents?
Uh, no.
Erratic behavior?
Drugs? Alcohol?
I don't think so.
So you don't know.
We'll look into it.
What about you?
Any record?
No.
Well, yes, actually.
I beat up this guy's car this --
this one time.
It was no big deal.
Did you attend
anger-management classes?
No.
Would you be willing to?
I don't need to.
You might.
Look...
I don't want this to get ugly.
I just want what's fair.
Custody battles get ugly, Luke,
and they're not
about what's fair.
The truth is this will be long,
it will be expensive,
it will be unpleasant,
and you'll probably lose.
But if you want your daughter,
it's the only way.
And time is of the essence here, because
once Anna moves April out of state,
it becomes infinitely
more complicated.
So I beg and plea with him,
and he says he'll try and come.
but I'm afraid he won't,
and I just can't wait any longer.
So I take the ticket,
and I go running off.
I run all the way
back to the theater.
When I get there,
I burst through the doors.
There's sweat pouring off of
me and I'm gasping for breath.
And everybody's gone?
No, the director
is still there.
- No!
- I know, right.
- Can you pass the raita?
- Sure.
So I say to him,
"you have to let me audition."
And he says, "you can't audition,
because the auditions are over."
And I say, "the auditions can't be over,
because I haven't auditioned yet."
And he says,
"you're two hours too late."
And I say, "that's because
I was in a traffic accident,
and I have the
cop to prove it."
Just as I'm about to say,
"and he'll be here any minute,"
and, you know,
not really believing it,
officer Frick comes
waltzing through the door.
- No!
- Like Fred Astaire.
- Officer Frick came through.
- So you got the part?
- Oh, no.
I was totally wrong for it.
But officer Frick introduced
me to his nephew Drew,
and we went out a few times,
so that was cool.
Lucy, hands down, that is the best "dedicated
to my craft" story I've ever heard.
Why, thank you.
Hard-working and beautiful --
she's something special.
You got yourself a
good one here, Marty.
Thanks.
Oh, Rory's got way better
stories than I do.
Did she ever tell you about the time
she drove out to her professor's house
in Albany to replace the
last page of her final?
Well, it was in the wrong font,
and I got an "a" on that paper.
Wasn't that the professor
who had a crush on you?
Hey! Are you saying that
she didn't deserve the "a"?
I'm just saying the woman is the
object of many strange crushes.
Oh, that's not true.
The oddball who works
at Baskin-Robbins?
She can't walk within a block
of the place without the guy
running out with a triple scoop
of mint chocolate chip.
So not true.
Hey, she's something special.
Hey you know, I put four pages
of endnotes on that final.
I deserved that "a."
I'm not saying you're not dedicated to your
schoolwork. You're the hardest worker I know.
See, I was always about doing just
enough, or maybe a little less.
Well, look at you now, Mr.
Slaving away.
It's true. My rep is ruined.
Boyfriend works insanely hard.
Is that true, Marty?
I just have a couple jobs.
Four! The man has four jobs.
And a full class load.
It's nuts! Right, Rory?
It does seem a bit excessive.
- It's not four.
- Four. Rory?
I think so.
Finnegan's, the bookstore,
tutoring, and landscaping.
The landscaping is seasonal.
I haven't done that for months.
But you will,
and that will be four.
That's a lot of jobs, my boy.
Hey, I'm just waiting for
that trust fund to kick in.
I got it.
- There.
- Thanks.
So how did you two meet?
- Tell him.
- What?
- Tell him!
- Why?
He stalked me.
That's charming.
I was playing Portia in "The
Merchant of Venice" at the rep,
and every night,
I see this guy in the front row --
same seat, same intense gaze.
And after the fifth show,
I went up to him and I said,
"next time I see you, you better bring
flowers or have a knife and stab me."
And...
The next time I saw her,
I had daisies and a butter knife.
Sweet.
I can't believe I don't even know this.
How did you two meet?
Actually, Marty introduced us.
What?
I'm sorry.
I can't be a part of this.
- A part of what?
- Logan.
They've known each other
since freshman year.
I don't understand.
Rory and Marty, they used to hang
out all the time at Branford
and watch "Duck Soup."
What are you talking about?
W-What is he talking about?
- Lucy --
- You guys know each other?
Yes.
It was freshman year.
It's no big deal.
You've been keeping
this from me?
Why? I-I don't understand.
You guys are friends?
You know each other?
- I'm sorry, Lucy.
- We just didn't think --
So you both have been
lying to me about this?
I don't understand.
Why? For what?
I don't know.
Oh, my god. This is so messed up.
I have to go.
Lucy...
What is wrong with you?
I was asked a direct question.
I'm not gonna lie. She's a nice girl.
Yeah, I know she's a nice girl.
She's my friend.
You were gonna tell her anyway.
Not here. Not like this.
You totally humiliated her.
Lucy's humiliated because of what
you and Marty did to her, not me.
I told her the truth,
which is something she could use more of
from her supposed friend
and her boyfriend.
I can't believe you're
trying to justify this.
What you did was so obnoxious.
I was just being honest.
I'm just gonna head back
into the city tonight.
I've got a lot of
work to do tomorrow.
Fine.
Hi. 143.
What?
I want to talk to you, but I'm
gonna lose count, so remember 143.
- 143 what?
- Soaps.
- What are you doing?
- Inventory.
- At the inn?
- No, at the Pentagon.
I'm tracking soaps and nuclear
missiles for General Abizaid.
Isn't it a little late?
The general's a slave driver.
Mom.
Well, it had to get done at some point,
so I thought I'd do it at this point.
- I count better at night.
- Okay.
So what's going on?
I thought it was
an all-Logan week.
- It was.
- Was?
- Boys suck.
- Oh, hon.
- They totally suck.
- Sometimes they do.
Tell me it gets better
when they get older.
It gets better when
they get older.
- It does?
- Well, it gets more confusing,
more complicated, and more complex.
Does any of that sound better?
No.
- So what happened?
- It was awful.
We went to dinner
with Lucy and Marty,
and I told him
everything beforehand --
about how Marty pretended that
we didn't know each other
and I just had to go with it.
Yeah. So right in
the middle of dinner,
he decides that he can't lie to Lucy,
and he tells her
that Marty and I have known
each other since freshman year.
- Yikes!
- I know.
Who does that, right?
Right in the middle of dinner.
He has no reason to be jealous.
I mean,
he knows that I love him.
Of course he does.
So why would he do it?
I have no idea.
Mars and venus, you know?
Yeah, see,
I don't think that's right.
Because mars and venus
are both planets, right?
So they have
something in common.
I think it's more like
mars and a bowl of soup.
- Venus and a bowl of soup.
- What?
Venus is the woman.
Venus and the bowl of soup.
Really, mom?
Well, I'm just saying.
So how's Lucy?
I don't know.
Not good. She ran out.
And I've been trying to call her,
but she won't answer her phone.
I dont blame her. I mean,
I wouldn't want to talk to me right now.
Oh, she'll be fine. She probably just
needs time to cool down, you know.
Yeah, I hope so.
I mean, I feel terrible.
Of course you do.
You want to come home?
I'm about to start
counting dust ruffles.
No.
I should actually probably go
over there and try, you know?
See if she'll talk
to me in person.
All right.
Let me know what happens.
Yeah, I will. 143.
Ah, thank you.
Sorry boys suck.
Yeah, stupid bowls of soup.
Hey. Is Lucy here?
She's here.
Can I see her?
She doesn't want to see you right now,
and, to be honest, neither do I.
Olivia, just let me
explain, please.
No.
- Lorelai.
- Oh, my god!
Mom, you scared me half to death.
What are you doing here?
I want to talk to you, Lorelai.
Ugh. Is this about the party?
Because I've had
a really long day,
and I don't want to
talk about the party.
It's not about the party. I've come
to talk to you about your marriage.
- My marriage?
- Yes, I'm concerned.
I don't like what I'm seeing,
and I've come to offer
you some friendly advice.
Mom, I really don't
want your advice.
Well, then consider
it unfriendly advice.
Okay.
Christopher is immature,
often foolish,
and a little lacking
in common sense.
He doesn't always make
the best choices.
Like with me? Are you saying he
chose wrongly in choosing me?
I'm saying he's your husband,
Lorelai, for better or for worse.
I like Christopher.
Okay.
I think he's good for you.
But it's not going
to be perfect.
He's not perfect,
and god knows you're not perfect.
But marriage is not
about always being happy,
and often it's about
not being happy at all.
It's about compromise,
which is not your strong suite.
Marriage is about swallowing
your pride sometimes,
about doing what he wants.
It's not about
winning an argument,
which may make you sad,
because that's what you love.
But I don't want to
see you ruin this.
Marriage is serious
business, Lorelai,
and if you don't take
this very seriously,
then this whole thing
could fall apart
faster than you could
possibly imagine.
And he'll be gone,
and you'll be alone again.
A ring is no guarantee.
Sorry for scaring you.
www.tvsubtitles.net