Previously on
"Gilmore Girls"...
- Hey.
- Hey. How you doing ?
I had a really great
time last night.
Let's not make more
out of it than it was.
You slept with dad?
Yeah, I did.
Is that why you and Luke broke up,
because you slept with dad?
You don't belong with me.
You belong with someone
like Christopher.
You can go back to
being Lorelai Gilmore,
and I'll go back to being the guy
in the diner who pours your coffee.
I love you.
I know the other night didn't
mean for you what it did for me.
But I don't regret it and haven't
stopped thinking about it.
And if I have to wait until we're
both 80 years old for you to see it,
then I'll wait.
I can't wait to come see you, Logan.
I can't wait.
- I already got you a ticket.
- You're kidding.
I got it right here. I was gonna fedex
it to you. You'll have it by tomorrow.
Tell your mom you're not
gonna be home for Christmas.
Christmas?
Hi, Chris.
Let me bottom-line it for you.
Snakes are gross.
Snakes are scary and slithery,
and do you know where
snakes do not belong?
- On a plane?
- They do not belong on a plane.
It's not an ideal situation.
They do not belong
anywhere except in cages
stuck in safes buried deep,
deep underground.
- I hate snakes!
- So I'm gathering.
With their gross, no-legged bodies,
and their scaly, scaly skin,
and their wiggling,
and their hissing.
Okay, Lor. I respect your very
valid feelings about snakes.
Thank you.
But I have to say we
were fairly warned.
No! No!
A movie should not
just be its title.
"Driving miss daisy" didn't
all take place in the car,
"Dances with wolves" wasn't
one long wolf dance.
But this was nothing
but snakes, snakes,
relentless snakes,
snakes on a plane.
Snakes, snakes,
snakes on a plane!
This was our fifth
bad movie in a row.
It's got to be some
kind of a record.
We got to face facts--
movies have gotten bad.
Unless it's our fault.
What? No,
we didn't make the bad movies.
No, we made the movies bad.
Think about it.
We are the common factor.
Ohh.
All the movies --
very different.
Different genres --
different languages, even.
We saw them in different
theaters at different times.
What do they all
have in common?
They were all seen by us.
- Wow!
- Huh?
We can never see
"Casablanca" together.
I mean, I'm very sorry.
I don't care how much I love it,
but I will not be responsible
for ruining "Casablanca."
So...
So... we should
divvy up the candy.
- Divvy...
- The candy.
- Yeah.
Got half the Milk Duds.
Sour Patch Kids --
hmm, a third.
Twizzlers -- you got about 5 --
4 3/4 -- you pick.
Yeah, I'll take the Twizzlers.
No, I meant besides
the Twizzlers.
I tell you what --
you can have it all.
Such a gentleman.
We should...
- Yeah, I should, uh...
- I should...
Okay.
Yeah.
- Good night, Lor.
- Good night, Chris.
H i.
Well, well, someone is cutting
it pretty close to curfew.
Did you guys have a good time?
Yeah, really good.
Ooh, is it weird that
he didn't come in?
- Weird for me?
- Yeah.
Oh, I saw the guy two days ago.
I'm sick of him.
- Is it weird for you?
- No. No.
Okay. He could come in
if you wanted him to.
I mean,
I could make myself scarce.
Oh, no, you wouldn't have
to make yourself scarce.
Oh, then I could be un-scarce. I could
be here in all my plentiful glory.
That's more normal.
God, I forget what the protocol is
when your mom is dating your dad.
Yeah, me too.
We'll have to consult Emily Post again.
Yeah.
But I really don't
think it would be weird.
- It wouldn't?
- No. I mean, if it was,
it wouldn't be weird in a bad way.
I mean, if that's what you want.
Okay.
- Is that what you want?
- I don't know.
No. Not now. Maybe...
I want it.
I don't know. Twizzler?
- Okay.
It's good, though. You know?
He and I, between us --
it's -- it's going good.
Well, good.
Yeah, when I had lunch with him the other
day, he said things were really good.
- He did?
- Mm-hmm.
What'd he say?
Um, nice things.
Oh, yeah?
- Yep.
- Like what?
Nice things.
Did he talk about my sparkling
eyes and my glossy, raven hair?
Look, I'm not gonna pass
notes between you guys.
What if Emily Post says that's
part of the appropriate protocol?
If you can get it in writing
from the ghost of Emily Post,
then I will pass as
many notes as you want.
- But, mom...
- Yeah?
I'm really glad things
are good between you.
- Me too.
- I'm just...
Yeah?
I just want you to be careful.
Is this the safe-sex talk?
Because even if the ghost of
Emily Post says it's okay,
it is just plain weird.
No. Mom, I want you to be
careful with you, with him.
I just...
I don't want to see you get hurt again.
I am. I am being careful.
Okay. Good.
Oh, my gosh.
Am I coming with you to college?
Excuse me?
You totally want me to come
to Yale with you, don't you?
What? No.
Then why are you packing all of
my clothes -- my pink t-shirt?!
-  Where'd that come from?
- Oh, my goodness.
That is so nice of you to
think of me in school --
My sweet skirt!
I hope you brought a toothbrush
'cause, boy, oh, boy,
are we gonna have fun!
My cozy sweater...
Okay, two eggs over-easy,
hash browns cooked well,
whole-wheat toast buttered, and
with a side of marmalade.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
All right, what can I get you?
Kirk, you're scaring
away the customers.
I am not gonna ask you what's wrong.
Either eat or go.
Women troubles, Luke.
Haven't slept in days.
See the bags under my eyes?
See the glazed look?
Women.
See this glazed look?
Don't care.
Mom's been incredibly possessive lately,
as has Lulu,
and it's very tense.
I noticed they were beginning
to snipe at each other,
but I figured it was
a friendly competition
I could work to my advantage,
you know?
When you've got two women
making you sherry cobbler,
you're likely to end up with
some pretty good cobbler.
Basic capitalism.
That's not how they see it.
Oh,  no. Apparently,
it's mom's cobbler or Lulu's cobbler.
- I've got to choose.
- Are you gonna order something?
I'd love to order something.
I'm starving.
But what should I get?
Lulu would want me to get something hip,
like a bagel.
Hip?
But mom would say a growing boy
needs something more substantial,
like pancakes.
Well, neither of them are here,
so what do you want?
I don't know!
Bagel, pancakes, bagel, pancakes...
It's like their voices
are blocking out my voice,
and I don't know what
I think anymore.
I'll have a bagel and pancakes,
I guess.
Yeah, what kind of bagel?
Lulu would kill me if I got the onion,
you know,
'cause of all the kissing --
and mom would freak
over the poppy seed
'cause she thinks poppies
are a gateway drug.
What about... egg?
Egg, it is.
- Hey.
I didn't expect you till later.
I know, but I wanted
to go over April's schedule
before I brought her by.
- Is this a good time?
- Sure, let's sit.
Great.
So, this is her schedule.
I think I erred on the
side of too many details.
I like details.
These are some of the phone
numbers you might need --
pediatrician, dentist, orthodontist --
if her retainer breaks --
- optometrist...
- If her glasses break.
So, my mom has her back
surgery on monday,
but, apparently,
the recovery process is really slow,
so I'm gonna be in New
Mexico at least two weeks.
It's fine. April can stay with
me as long as you need her to.
Thanks. I really
appreciate this.
- All right, so what's this packet?
- Right.
Registration forms,
some waivers --
April will need to have this when
she goes to school tomorrow.
And she will tell you she
needs to be there at 7:30,
but she really doesn't need
to be there until 8:00.
Anyway, it's all in the notes.
- Don't worry.
- I'm not worried.
Okay, maybe a little.
It'll be fine?
It will be fine. I promise.
Wow! Today's secret
ingredient is gourds!
Aren't they beautiful?
I guess that depends
on the beholder's eye.
Jackson's whole squash
crop went crazy this year.
We had such a hot summer,
and these babies love the sun.
You've got to try this soup.
Wait, is that gourd soup?
It's so good.
It's sweet and rich.
It's like pie, only it's soup.
It's like pie soup!
No, I don't eat orange food,
- except for candy corn.
- You eat cheetos.
I don't eat food that's
naturally orange.
You eat oranges.
I eat food that's naturally orange,
but I don't eat gourds.
Fine.
What else is going on at home?
Ooh! Martha is so close to walking.
She's right on the verge.
Why don't you come over
tomorrow night for dinner?
Maybe you'll see
the inaugural steps.
Um, I'd love to, but...
But you want to wait to see if
Christopher calls and asks youout first,
and then if he doesn't,
you'll come over.
Something like that, yes.
You two have been seeing quite
a bit of each other lately.
Yeah, we're just dating.
Right, 'cause you can just
date the father of your child.
Turns out you can.
It's been a fun six weeks.
We're taking things slowly
And just getting to
know each other again.
Except for the fact that you've known
each other for more than 30 years.
Okay, I get it. Please get off my back,
and stop talking like this.
Okay, it's just that you and Luke
haven't been broken up all that long.
I know. I remember.
I was there.
Okay.  It's -- you know, after
breaking up out of a big relationship
it's normal to have
a rebound thing.
You know, a big, bouncy,
rubber ball of a rebound thing.
- It's... good.
- But?
But a rubber ball is
a 28-year-old surfer
or a jazz saxophonist
who drives a V.W. bus
or a really cute guy that
can't even spell his last name.
It's not the father
of your only child.
Christopher is not
your rubber ball.
Okay.
He's a big, heavy bowling ball.
I'm gonna tell
him you said that.
I just want you to be careful.
Okay, God, I feel like I should
set up traffic cones around me
for all the people
worrying about my safety.
I am being careful, okay?
That's all I want.
- All right.
- Great.
- Fine.
- Good.
- Better.
Hi, Chris.
So Lor, what's your life
looking like tomorrow night?
You available?
Well, I don't know,
is there some particular reason
you're checking
my availability?
Well, I have an idea
for a really fun date,
and if, in fact,
you are available,
I will put thought into action.
I thought our last
date was pretty fun.
Well, this will
be even more fun.
"Snakes on a boat"?!
I'll pick you up at 6:00.
Okay,  I'll be there at
6:00 to be picked up.
Sorry. These gourd
rinds are really thick.
What is the, uh, fun date?
No hints.
I hate not knowing things.
I know. I'll see you tomorrow.
Okay. Bye.
Sounds like somebody's
got a date.
- Sookie.
- Sorry.
- Sounds like somebody's got a date.
- Nice.
Hey, this is Logan Huntzberger.
Leave a message.
Hey, it's me.
I just got back to Yale.
I thought I would try you
and see if you're there,
but you're not.
I thought you would be,
Fascinating, my thought process,
isn't it?
Okay, I'll talk to
you later. Bye.
Hey!
Well, hello, Rory.
You sound chipper.
Oh, hi, grandpa.
You're back at Yale?
Yep. Back at Yale.
Tell her the good
news, Richard!
I'm coming to that.
- It's very exciting!
- What's exciting?
Well, when I was at my
Yale class reunion,
I had a chance to meet one of my
former classmates, Harold Laken.
You know him as the dean of
undergraduate education.
Harold was also a
fellow Whiffenpoof.
- The news, Richard!
- Yes, right. Well...
It seems there was a sudden vacancy
in the economics department,
and they need someone to
teach a course this semester,
and Harold immediately
thought of me.
Can you believe it?
Your grandfather, a professor!
I'm just a visiting lecturer.
Too starchy. Too starchy?
- No, I like -- I like --
- Too starchy.
What I want to know is whether
you'd be okay with this.
I'm gonna be on the campus
at the same time you are,
and there's a chance we
might run into one another.
I promise,
you will not cramp my style.
Well, that's wonderful,
because I have to admit,
I'm really quite
excited about it.
That's great,
grandpa. Congratulations.
Well, why don't we meet
up after your first class
and grab dinner and celebrate?
Oh, I would love that,
but I've already scheduled
dinner with Harold.
But, Richard, we have dinner
with the Sudburys on thursday.
Remember? We're going
to the Hill House.
Well, I'm sorry, Emily,
but I have dinner with the dean,
and you can't expect me to
include the Sudburys in that.
They are insufferable bores.
No,  of course not.
I'll just have to have dinner
with the Sudburys alone.
Oh, the life of
a faculty widow!
Did you hear that, Rory?
She's already turned on me.
I heard it, grandpa.
Razor blades? They've expressly
forbidden razor blades?
That's sound policy.
Are kids at this school
showing up with razor blades?
I mean, listen to this list
of stuff they've had to ban.
Drug use, bullying, graffiti,
theft, spitting, fighting --
including but not limited to punching,
kicking, gouging, and biting.
Seems to me like they're
just giving the kids ideas.
"Gee, I can't think of any
other bad things to do today.
Let me look at the manual.
Hey, gouging sounds fun!"
No one at that school
is gouging anyone.
Well, sure. Why bother with
that when they've got access to
guns, tasers, knives,
and nunchakus?
Nunchakus are cool --
and deadly.
That's ridiculous. Nobody's bringing
nunchakus to April's school.
Of course not.
They're way too bulky
to fit in your sock.
- Now, mace, on the other hand --
- Mace?
Kids are walking
around with mace?
Oh, honey, calm down.
Nothing's gonna happen to April.
They just spell out that stuff
for their legal protection.
Whenever you're taking care of kids,
that's a lot of liability.
It's the same with
my dance school.
And nothing bad ever happens?
Nothing ever happens.
Oh, except for that one time.
What one time?
Well, I took my
senior ballerinas
to try out for a performance
of "The nutcracker,"
and one of the girls
pulled a Tonya Harding
and knocked the front-runner for
Clara out of the competition.
Broke her leg in three places.
That is not nothing.
That is the opposite of nothing.
It's totally different.
That was a much rougher crowd.
Rougher crowd?
They're ballerinas.
Oh, yeah. I know.
Everyone thinks, "ballerinas --
so sweet, so fragile."
Trust me,
they're dancing on stress fractures
and ingrown toenails,
and they haven't eaten in weeks.
- Hey.
- Sorry we're late.
We were half-way here
and April remembered
the avocado pit was still in the
kitchen, so we had to go back.
We had to make to
make a pit stop.
- Hey, honey.
- Hi!
- You remember miss Patty.
- Sure!
- And Kirk.
- Yo.
- And Caesar.
- Hey, April.
I hate to have to rush,
but I actually have to rush.
That's fine. You go.
- Bye, mom.
- Ooh, I love you, sweetie.
- Say hi to grandma.
- I will.
- I'll call you when I get there.
- Okay.
Take care of her.
I will.
Okay, then.
So, is there somewhere
I can put the pit down?
Oh, you know what?
Go on upstairs, and I'll bring the bags.
Look at that turnout.
And the hips of Anna Pavlova.
You must bring her
to my ballet class.
Where ballerinas are maiming each
other to be in "The nutcracker"?
Fat chance of that.
Okay, here we are.
You remember the place.
All right.
Here's your bed,
and here's the desk.
I thought you could do
your homework on it.
A little chair for reading.
I know how you like reading.
And this is your dresser.
Now, if you have a hanging bag for,
like, dresses,
you can just hang it in my closet,
but I don't seem to remember
- you wearing a lot of dresses.
- Not big on dresses.
All right, what else?
Here's your kitchen, my bed,
bathroom's back there,
and the TV.
I had a remote but I lost it,
so you're gonna have to change the
channel by turning this knob here.
And here's the telephone.
If you're on it and you hear a
beeping sound, that's call-waiting,
So you've got to hit the flash button
to switch over to the other call.
Maybe I should
write all this down.
Oh, sure! Sure!
I was just kidding.
I know how call-waiting works.
Of course you do.
You probably also know how to open up
a refrigerator and turn on a sink.
Okay, well,
I'll get out of your way,
and you let me know if
you need anything. Okay?
Actually, my avocado
pit needs light,
and it's kind of dark in here.
Well, there will be a little
more light in the morning.
Will there be less
brown in the morning?
You know, this place is kind
of depressing, isn't it?
I'd say.
Sorry if that hurt
your feelings.
Mom says bluntness isn't my
most attractive quality.
Well, maybe we can
pick up a few things.
I don't know,
some pillows, a rug.
You know, lamps --
lamps brighten.
Hey, we could go to "targét."
Oh, sounds kind of fancy.
No. No,
that's just how we say "Target."
Oh, never been.
Wow. Um...
I don't think I've ever met a
person who hasn't been to Target.
Well, now you have,
so if you say that's the place to go,
- so that's where we'll go.
- It's the place to go.
Okay, so how about tomorrow,
after I close up?
- Cool.
- Cool!
- I'll let you get settled in.
- Okay.
All right.
Everyone, congratulations.
The first issue of the year
is officially locked down.
And special kudos to Bill
for landing the front page
with his campus housing exposé,
"Dormitory or death trap?"
Nice alliteration.
Slugline's half the battle.
Dormitory renovations --
that's quaint.
I recently had the opportunity to be a
fly on the wall at the Hartford courant
as the editor selected
their lead story.
It was down to the wire,
and I was on the edge of my seat
when at the last second,
a local-corruption story broke.
It was thrilling.
It made this place look like a joke.
- Your point, Paris?
- Oh, I thought I was clear.
Compared to the courant,
this place is a joke.
Okay. Assignments.
Bill, you'll go with part two
of the campus-housing series.
Got it.
We need someone to cover the
board of trustees meeting.
- I'm on that.
- Thanks, Joni.
And I want to do the traditional
freshman class composition article,
but I think we need to go deeper
than just ethnicities and hometowns.
I mean,
what is the class of 2010 really about?
Maybe take a different look.
At the courant, they use indesign to
integrate the words into the photos.
Gee, Paris, do you happen to
have an "in" at the courant?
Like, maybe your
boyfriend, Doyle?
What is he, a fact-checker?
The most requested
fact-checker at the paper.
He works seven days a week just
to keep up with the demand
for his fact-checking.
Maybe he's looking to get
away from a certain lunatic.
Jealous much, Sheila?
Yeah. You got me.
So, the art-show piece.
I've got a problem.
Animal, vegetable, or mineral?
I kind of had a thing with one
of the artists in the show.
Okay. Animal.
I just can't do it.
That's fine. I can do it.
That's it. Class dismissed.
So, you want to go to this
art-show thing with me tonight?
Sorry, can't, Doyle's celebrating his
one-month anniversary with the paper.
Having drinks with a bunch of the
staff bigwigs over at Duffy's.
- Cool.
- Yeah.
He's pretty loved.
Actually, we both are.
We're like the Ephron and
Bernstein of the group.
I think it's going
to be quite a fete.
Doyle says the editor of the
metro section might even show.
That's cool.
Well, I can just go by myself.
You know, if you're desperate, you could
force one of these staffers to go with you.
I used to do that all the
time when I was the editor.
I dragged Bill everywhere.
That is, until the time I picked
him up to go to the groundbreaking
for the new chemistry
research building,
and he was wearing
a cable-knit sweater
that had "date" written all over it.
As if.
I'm not desperate.
Look, don't give me those
Rory Gilmore puppy-dog eyes.
Even if I am your best friend,
I have to look out for my career first,
then Doyle's, then you.
Go to your party, Paris.
Be the couple whose
divorce was so painful
that it was memorialized in both
literature and film. I'll be fine.
Oh, yeah. Now it's just sad.
Huh!
Um... kind of, uh, casual,
seemingly routine
dating clothes.
Was that intended
as a compliment?
'Cause it didn't
come out like one.
No, you look good.
But I mean, how hard is it to look
good when you know where you're going?
- Not that hard.
- I could get some points.
I, on the other hand,
had to come up with an outfit
that could easily convert from
totally formal to totally casual
with just a few moves.
Look, here I am, all ready
for an elegant,
New York night on the town,
carriage ride through the park,
dinner at Pastis,
drinks at the Algonquin,
but if I change my shoes
and throw on a cardigan
and add necklace number two,
then I am ready for a concert
at the New Haven Green,
or I could use my cardigan to
cover up the security camera
in case the date turns
into some sort of heist.
I'd prefer the sexy
shoes to the sandals,
but you should be comfortable.
Comfortable?
"Comfortable" like we're gonna
eat moroccan and sit on the floor,
or "comfortable" like
we're gonna go up steps?
Steps? Steps? Steps?
Are we going to the Mets?
No hints.
So, tell me now.
Now! Tell me!
Oh, hello, "Bullitt."
Are you taking me on a car chase
through the streets
of San Francisco?
- It's cool, right?
- It's really cool.
- You like it?
- I love it.
- So is this the thing?
- It's a thing.
But is this the special
thing you planned?
'Cause if it is,
I want to give it its due.
If it's not, I want to have
the proper level of enjoyment
while still reserving myself
for the actual special thing.
The car is part of the thing.
It's not the whole thing.
I don't want to peek too soon.
Yeah, that's never good.
Ooh, you're being a gentleman.
Is that the special thing?
I always open your door.
Bucket seats --
is that the special thing?
No? Take a good,
long look at my hair now
'cause it's not gonna look like
this for the rest of the night.
Rumbly engine --
is that the special thing?
Buckle your seatbelt.
Buckling my seatbelt --
is that the special thing?
Yeah, that's it.
You're all buckled up. Date's over.
Look at this --
12-pack of socks for $6.
24 socks for 6 bucks.
That's only 25 cents a sock..
I knew you'd like it.
Oh, this looks good.
- You picked it out.
- Well, you said tablecloth.
That's true.
And what's the name
of that blue again?
Uh, cerulean.
I'm really into cerulean.
Yeah, I can see why.
I used to be really into olive.
Everything was olive, you know?
It was my backpack, my pants,
my sneakers. It was all olive.
And then one day, I just --
I woke up,
and I was like, "olive?
I don't like olive.
Not to wear, not to eat.
Olive -- Bleh."
Well, you know what?
I'm really glad we did it.
We had fun,
and the place looks great.
And, you know, now,
anytime you want,
you can have a nice
dinner on this table.
That's true.
You could put
flowers in this vase
- and use it like a centerpiece.
- Uh-huh.
You could dim the lights,
light these candles.
You know,
we can do it tonight if you want.
Yeah.
Or, you know, you could do it
when you have a lady over.
Oh?
It'd be really nice.
And she would be totally
comfortable in here now.
Right. Uh, you know what?
Why don't we, uh,
set up the desk lamp
so you can get at
your homework?
Actually, they don't give homework
on the first day of school.
One teacher said he was
gonna give us homework.
He even wrote it on the board,
but the homework was just,
"cover your books."
How lame is that?
- Very lame.
- I know.
So I'll set it up so you
can get to it tomorrow.
Cool. Um,
I'm gonna start covering my books.
Can I grab some grocery bags?
Yeah, go for it.
It's under the sink.
You know,
you can admit it if you're lost.
I will not lose any
respect for you.
I'm not lost.
Well, then,
are you planning to murder me?
Because people will
notice I'm gone.
They'll look for me.
Paul Anka saw me leave with you.
He'll bark.
He will bark,
and he'll sell you down the river.
Chris! Chris!
Good. Finally asking
for directions.
We're here.
Here, where? Are we at Woodstock?
I think we're late.
Shh! Just give it a minute.
Oh, are we meditating?
I think you need a word to repeat.
I don't have a word.
Stop talking.
That's two words.
Shh.
Oh.
"Shh." I like it.
Shh...
Ooh! What the --
I love this movie.
Check the glove compartment.
Oh, my god.
Hold this.
And...
popcorn.
Oh, my god.
You're unbelievable!
I thought it was time we saw a
movie we wouldn't complain about.
"Good morning, Mr. Ascot."
Mm-hmm.
But I have to tell you, Emily,
it's a whole new world
from the one we remember.
But the jacket was
still appropriate?
Oh, the jacket was fine.
Although I must say,
I felt wildly overdressed.
Boys in undershirts and
filthy baseball caps --
the girls wearing
pajamas and flip-flops.
Well, it's the style, Richard.
Well, it's most peculiar.
And you were firm with them?
That's one thing that never changes.
Young people respond
to discipline.
After all, you don't want your
course to be known as a "gut."
That's an easy class.
I learned that term at
dinner with the Sudburys,
who learned it from
their grandson, Paul.
And how are the Sudburys?
I hope you gave them my regards.
Of course. And they sent you theirs
and then proceeded to bore me
with the details of every
stunning vista they witnessed
on their recent
cruise to Alaska.
If you ask me, they saw more of the
baked Alaska than anything else.
You poor thing.
You have a disappointing evening,
and I have to give
you the bum's rush
to make my dinner with
Harold at the faculty club.
That's all right.
You enjoy yourself.
I probably won't wait up,
so I'll say good night now.
Good night, dear.
Oh, for Pete's sake! What now?
License and
registration, please?
Why do you need to see my license?
I wasn't speeding.
You were on a cellphone, ma'am.
I don't see how
that's your concern.
Do my bills go to your office?
It is illegal in Connecticut
to talk on a cellphone
while operating a vehicle.
Well, that is absurd. I can't talk
on my own phone in my own car?
License and
registration, ma'am.
If I can manage to drink a
cup of hot coffee and drive,
I can talk on a cellphone.
Or is coffee illegal, too?
Can I listen to the radio?
Can I open the
glove compartment?
Perhaps you should outlaw
scratching your nose.
That would certainly
cut down on accidents.
Ma'am, have you been drinking?
What? No!
This is outrageous.
You know, right now,
someone is robbing a kwiki mart,
and you're standing
there harassing me.
I'm going to need you to blow
into this breathalyzer for me.
Young man,
I don't know where that's been,
but I can say with
absolute certainty
it won't be going
anywhere near my mouth.
Excuse me. Do you know what
the light bulbs are all about?
Shock in your system.
Effective.
What are you doing?
Um, me?
She's touching your art.
What are you doing?
Are you actually drinking that water?
Oh, um,
I didn't know that it was art.
I thought it was
just a water cooler.
There's no sign or anything.
"Just a water cooler."
That's her self-portrait.
I'm kidding!
It's just a water cooler.
Oh. Okay.
We were just messing with you.
She is an artist, though.
I made the horse.
Oh, I really like that one.
Well, thanks.
Yes. It looks really big, too.
It looks bigger than the doorway.
Yeah. Well, it turns out it is,
as I found out four hours
before the show gonna start.
I had to detach the head,
then reattach it when I got here.
Does it look crooked?
Um, not to me.
- No, it does.
- If it does look crooked,
which it doesn't, I think it looks
better then it did before -- more jaunty.
What's it made out of?
Cans mostly. Tinfoil.
A couple hubcaps.
I do stuff with found objects.
I mean, you could call it trash,
but that'd be kind of negative.
She once made this
sculpture of an old lady
out of plastic sandwich
bags and milk cartons,
which was so cool.
She's awesome.
Oh, shut up!
So you're Olivia Marquont?
- Impressive.
- What are you, a spy?
Actually, I'm here for the paper.
I'm Rory.
Oh, the press.
So what do you think?
Honestly, I don't know.
I like your piece,
and I think I like the
robot in the underpants.
The robot is genius.
Olivia thinks
everything is genius.
Only genius stuff.
So, you're on the paper?
Oh, my god,
we used to be totally obsessed
with this girl who was on the paper --
Paris Geller.
- Sure.
- You know Paris?
- I know Paris.
- Okay, freshman year,
we were in this moral-reasoning
class with Paris,
and she was the most intense
person we'd ever met.
Um, she's pretty much
like that all the time.
Actually, I went to
high school with Paris.
Paris geller is a genius,
and I will go to the mat on that one.
Okay, you've got to let us
show you the rest of the show.
That's cool.
Come on.
We'll help you with your article,
give you the skinny
on everyone.
Did you see the
light bulb thing?
Um, my retinas
are still ringing.
Our friend Joel did that.
He just transferred from M.I.T.
Dude's wicked smart.
His work is always about technology.
I think Joel's a genius,
but I'll admit, I could be biased
by the fact that he's a total fox.
Is that the guy in
the '70s prom tuxedo?
No, that's Elijah.
He's doing a performance piece, actually.
He's been doing it since we were juniors.
Who knows if it'll ever end?
Okay, you've got to see
our friend Kasha's piece.
It's called "Girl without
clothes," and it's far out.
# You can't blame me #
# For feeling avarice #
# Oh, s'wonderful #
# S'marvelous #
# That you should care #
# For me #
Ooh, it's so good!
It's so chock-full of...
words like "chock-full."
And even if Audrey
Hepburn was 20
- and Fred Astaire was, like, 80 --
- He's still Fred Astaire.
I mean,
he could really tap-dance.
That was so nice, Chris.
That was so romantic
and fun and wonderful.
- S'wonderful?
- S'marvelous.
- I'm glad you liked it.
- I did. I really liked it.
You know,
the evening doesn't have to end here.
Gigi's staying with my mom.
We could go back to my place.
Oh. That's nice.
- Nice?
- No, that's not what I meant. Um...
- We don't have to.
- No, I want to.
- You do?
- I do, but I don't know if...
- ...you want to.
- ...if I should.
Okay.
I mean, everything's good, you know?
It's going really good.
- It's really good.
- Yeah, and I'm feeling good.
But?
I don't, uh...
know if I trust you.
Really?
Not just you. Me too.
I'm not sure if I
trust us yet with this.
Oh.
It's scary.
I'm scared, too.
I just hoped maybe...
we could stay here in this
place for a little while longer.
Well, it's gonna
snow eventually.
Right.
It's fine. We should wait.
I can wait.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah.
Thank you.
All this is perfect.
Okay.
Hello?
This is she.
What?
Oh. Yes!
What is it?
Who are you talking to?
Is she okay? What did she --
Okay. Where are you?
Uh-huh. I know where that is.
I'll be right there. Thank you.
Okay, bye-bye.
What?
We have to go.
We have to pick up my mother --
from jail.
Your mother's in jail?
Ooh, this night keeps
getting better and better.
Let's go.
You brush your teeth?
They're brushed.
So, there's a clear
path to the bathroom.
Can I get you a night-light?
I'm 13.
I'll take that as a "no."
I thought you didn't
have any homework.
I don't.
This is more for pleasure.
Sure. Sure,
a little light reading before bed.
I love my biology teacher.
She is so smart,
and she's really pretty.
She has this long, brown hair
that she kind of just
whooshes up into a clip.
She has all these piercings,
but it's just on one ear,
and she likes to fish.
No kidding?
A pretty fisher/scientist woman.
And I know she's single
because last year her
name was Mrs. Johnson,
and this year it's Ms.
Kaplan, so I was thinking,
one day, I could conveniently
forget my biology book,
and you could
bring it by for me,
and then maybe you could...
Have dinner at the candlestick
table with Ms. Kaplan?
Exactly.
Look...
April...
I guess you know
Lorelai and I broke up.
Yeah, my mom sort of told me.
Okay, well,
sometimes that happens, you know?
Sometimes it doesn't
work out between people,
and it's nobody's fault.
It's all about pheromone.
Right.
But I want you to
know I'm okay,
and you don't have
to take care of me.
I'm here to take care of you.
Okay?
Okay.
- Good night.
Is it okay if I read a little
more before I turn out the light?
- Real page-turner, huh?
- Oh, yeah.
Mitosis is insane.
Knock yourself out.
Oh... got it! Thank you!
- Am I smiling too much?
- You're smiling a lot.
All right,
I'll try to bring it down a notch.
Well, it's about time.
Oh, good.
I get to walk this
filthy floor again.
I don't need any help walking.
Thank you!
Oh, thank you for giving me
things that already belong to me.
Well, you can all be very
proud of yourselves.
You're doing a crack job.
You finally got menace-to-society
Emily Gilmore off the streets.
You'll be hearing
from my lawyer.
Come on. Put that thing away.
One, two, three! Ah!
Smile! Cheese!
Oh, I got you already. I'll get --
Okay, later. Bye!
Do you mind if I turn
on the music, mom?
That's fine.
Whatcha in the mood for?
"Jailhouse rock"?
"Folsom prison blues"?
You're very funny, Lorelai.
No, no, no. I know, I know.
"Working on the chain gang."
Yes, it's all quite amusing,
isn't it?
My being arrested,
held behind bars,
manhandled, and patted down?
Hardee-har.
Aw. I just have one
question for you, mom.
Why on earth did you call me?
I mean, thank you very much
from the bottom of my heart
for that incredible gift.
You don't need to get me anything
for the next five Christmases.
But why did you call me,
not dad?
It was his first night
teaching at Yale.
He was having dinner
with the dean.
I'm not about to call him
so he can excuse himself
to come bail his
wife out of jail.
I can't begin to tell you how
incompetent our police department is.
That officer Peters
who pulled me over --
he's going to be receiving a big,
fat subpoena,
and I'm not stopping there.
Wait.
What is this? What's this car?
What's going on here?
Are you two on a date?
No way.
You are not changing the subject.
We're not talking about anything
else except you in the clink.
Now, come on. Spill.
What was it like on the inside, huh?
Did you try to tunnel your
way out with a spoon?
You know ? Did they try to make
you join a gang?
And, mom,
now that you're on the outside
and they're still
on the inside,
are they gonna try to use you
as some kind of prison mule?
I just --
so much I need to know!
So, after my third callback,
he says to me,
"a girl can't play Oscar Wilde. I want
people to take this production seriously,"
like he's Peter
Brook or something
And not some goateed
sophomore from Arkansas.
So I give him my most
foppish stare and say,
"life is too important
to be taken seriously."
Nice.
But on the way out,
as I'm making my dramatic exit,
I walk right into the glass door,
like smack.
No. Ouch!
So the next semester, he keeps
hounding me about how I'd be perfect
for his production of
"California suite"
because I have such a
gift for physical comedy.
Holy crap!
Your boyfriend is rich.
And he's got some wild stuff.
I mean, what's this about?
Well, I must eat.
I'm positively famished.
Nice sound system.
Do you have popcorn?
Um, yeah,
there should be some in there.
You have a hell of a lot
of rice in here, Rory.
White rice, brown rice,
long-stem rice.
You are simply crazy for rice.
Who doesn't like rice?
Look who found an air popper!
Genius.
Now we just need some popcorn.
Or something else that
could be cooked in here.
Rice. Who's up for a late-night
snack of air-popped rice?
Oh, wow,
that must be my Logan call.
I didn't realize it
was so late already.
Time flies when you're
partying with an artist.
Hey!
- Hey.
- Hi.
What's going on?
You having a party there, Ace?
Oh, no, I'm just hanging out
with a few friends.
- Just friends, huh?
- Yeah.
Anybody I know, or...?
No. Just some girls I met.
- Hi, Logan!
Just girls, huh?
Your new boyfriend's not over.
Nope. Just us girls hanging
out in our underwear,
throwing pillows at each other --
you know, girl stuff.
Sounds very wholesome and loud.
- Yeah, we're --
- Hey, Rory!
Hold on just a sec. Yeah?
This says it's popcorn,
but it looks so fancy.
Can I open it, or are you saving it
for a special occasion or something?
Go ahead.
Hey, uh, sorry.
Is it okay if I call
you back later?
Sure, no problem. Have fun.
I will. Love you. Bye.
Is that too much popcorn?
- Uh, yeah.
- I'm really hungry.
Okay. Someone's got
some explaining to do.
I mean, they escorted her
out in her stocking feet.
Her shoes in a bag.
Somewhere in my
youth or childhood...
...you must have
done something good.
The universe owed me this one.
- I'm glad you had fun.
- I did. Didn't you have fun?
Yeah, I did. It was great.
It was one of the
"great" greats. What?
Nothing. I feel I may have
gotten overshadowed a bit.
I mean, how's my little barn
movie supposed to compare
with your mom in jail?
Chris, no!
It was just the cherry on top,
the mint on the pillow of what
was already a perfect night.
No, I loved our date.
It was amazing.
I loved the movie.
I'll never forget the movie I saw the
night I picked my mother up from jail.
You're never gonna get tired
of saying that, are you?
"Picked up my mom from jail"?
No, I don't think I ever will.
I'm just so glad you
were with me tonight.
I mean, anybody else who
would have seen me laughing
as I bailed my
mother out of jail
would have just thought I
was completely deranged.
Well, I know you're deranged but
for completely different reasons.
I mean, you just get it,
and you make everything fun,
and it's so nice to be with
someone who understands you
and makes you...
I'll call you tomorrow.
- Gigi's with her grandmother?
- She is.
You want to come in?
Yeah?
Yeah.
Transcript : Raceman
Subtitles : Willow's Team
www.forom.com
www.tvsubtitles.net