Tell me what happened.
We just broke up.
I don't understand.
We went to dinner,
and then we walked by the bonfire...
but it wasn't lit.
So we went to this junkyard,
and we sat in this car and... Oh, God!
- What?
- I forgot your meatball in the car.
Honey, forget it.
I can't believe
I left your meatball in the car.
Okay, come on.
After I told the waiter to wrap it up
and everything.
And everyone was like,
'What do you want with one meatball?'
I said, 'It's a mother-daughter thing. '
I'm sure he thought I was nuts,
but he was so nice.
And he did it anyway.
He brought one of those
little tinfoil swans or a duck...
or some kind of bird
and then I left it in the car.
Forget about the meatball.
Just tell me what happened.
He just broke up with me.
This doesn't make any sense.
This is Dean we're talking about.
He's crazy about you.
He calls 25 times a day.
The cover of his notebook
is one step away from stalker material.
- I have to go to bed.
- Wait.
- Take me through the night step by step.
- Why?
So I can help decipher
what happened here.
We broke up. He didn't wanna be
my boyfriend anymore, end of story.
- So not end of story.
- Yes, it is.
He did not plan a romantic evening
complete with dinner...
and a junkyard
which we'll get back to later...
- and then suddenly decide to dump you.
- How do you know?
I've read every Nancy Drew mystery,
the one about the Amish country, twice.
I know there's more to the story.
- What are you doing?
- Getting rid of all his stuff.
- What stuff?
- Everything he gave me and touched.
Everything he looked at.
Will you just calm down
for just one second?
He doesn't wanna be my boyfriend, fine.
Okay, it will be fine, but...
- What?
- Mine.
- Is there someone else?
- No.
- Is he moving?
Is he dying?
Did his football team lose a game?
- What?
- It's happened.
- Did he try something?
- What?
- Did he want to...
Did he want to go faster than you?
- God, no!
- Okay, I'm sorry.
You're just not giving me
much to go off of here.
That's your fancy dress
that I made for you.
That I wore to a dance
that I went to with him.
The sweater's brand-new.
- He saw me in it yesterday and liked it.
- Then he's got good taste.
He said it brought out the blue in my eyes.
Then he's gay.
- You're not funny and it goes.
- I'm a little funny.
If you throw away everything
he saw you wear...
you're gonna be walking around
in a towel.
Colonel Clucker? Are you serious?
He has been with you since you were four.
The first time Dean came over,
he picked it up.
That's not the Colonel's fault.
He was sitting, minding his own business,
and a guy picks him up.
What's a stuffed bird to do?
I don't want to joke about this, not now.
Here, I don't want to look at that anymore.
- I'll put it away.
- No, take it out of the house.
Throw it in a dumpster, burn it,
I don't care. I want it gone.
Someday when this is all in the past...
you may be sorry
you don't have those things.
I don't care!
- Okay, fine. It's gone.
- Thank you.
I'll take care of it, and you go to bed.
Get some rest.
Maybe you'll feel more like talking
in the morning.
Honey, good night.
- Mom.
- Yeah.
Far, far away from the house, okay?
- Hey, it sleeps with the fishes.
- Thank you.
Mom, get up.
- Rory, what's the matter?
- Nothing. I just want to get started.
I listed all the things
we say we're gonna do on weekends...
but when it comes around...
you say they're too boring
to actually do on a weekend day.
Then you say we'll do them during
the week which, of course, we never do.
I think we should get them
all out of the way today once and for all.
And to make it interesting,
we should come up with a reward system.
So once we're done with everything
on the list...
we could go get manicures.
Or we could go to that Swiss place
for fondue for dinner...
or we could stuff our purses
full of Sour Patch Kids and Milk Duds...
and go see the Stars Hollow
elementary school production...
of Who's Afraid of Virginia Woolf?
- It's 6:00.
- I know.
- On Saturday morning.
- That's right.
It's 6:00 on Saturday morning!
- Do you want to wear docks or sneakers?
- I want to wear slippers.
- Up, please!
- Rory, my heart.
- It is Saturday, the day of rest.
- Sunday is the day of rest.
- No, Saturday is the day of pre-rest.
- Pre-rest?
Yeah, so that way
when you actually get to Sunday...
you're rested enough to enjoy your rest.
That makes absolutely no sense.
That's because it's 6:00
on Saturday morning.
- Oh, jeez!
- Up, please!
- You made a rhyme.
- I'll see you downstairs.
- Hello. Did you rearrange the furniture?
- Yes.
Good. I thought we were having
a problem with decorator elves.
I was gonna have to call an exterminator
and tent the place. But it was just you.
So was there any reason
that you suddenly felt the need...
to move around large pieces of furniture
in the morning?
- I was up. It was there.
- Okay, good thought process. Great.
Now I noticed that
you didn't move the TV though.
- It was too heavy.
- Right, okay.
Well, I like this. This is good.
Of course when the sofa faced the TV,
it was a little easier to watch.
But this is good, too. It'll be like radio.
- Are you ready to go?
- I am. Just one quick sec.
Why don't you...
Could you put the pen down?
I'm just finishing the list.
Yes, I see. As much as I love your list...
let's just finish this particular one
in a little while, okay?
Okay.
I'm concerned about you.
I wish you would talk to me.
I don't want to deal with it right now.
I can't deal with it right now.
Fair enough. But listen,
I've had my heart broken before.
It's really hard.
It's hard for everyone,
so can I give you a little advice?
Okay.
I think what you really need
to do today is wallow.
- Wallow?
- Yeah. Get back in your pajamas...
go to bed, eat nothing but gallons
of ice cream and tons of pizza...
don't take a shower, or shave your legs,
or put on any kind of makeup at all.
Just sit in the dark, watch a sad movie
and have a good long cry...
and just wallow. You need to wallow.
- No.
- Rory, your first love is intense...
and your first breakup even more intense.
Shoving it away and ignoring it
while you make lists is not going to help.
I don't want to wallow.
- Try it for one day.
- No.
One day of pizza and pajamas.
I'll rent Love Story and The Champ,
An Affair to Remember, Ishtar.
- I don't want to be that kind of girl.
- The kind who watches Ishtar?
The girl who falls apart
because she doesn't have a boyfriend.
That hardly applies to you.
- It will, if I wallow.
- Not true.
So I used to have a boyfriend
and now I don't.
That's just the way it is.
Sitting in the dark eating junk food...
and not shaving my legs
isn't gonna change that, is it?
- No.
- So I don't even want to go there.
I have things to do.
I have school and Harvard to think about.
Harvard's three years away.
But now is the time to be preparing for it.
I mean, Harvard is hard to get into...
and I don't know why I even spend
my time thinking about anything else.
Because you have a pulse.
And you're not the president
of the audiovisual club.
I'm 16. I have the rest of my life
to have a boyfriend.
I should be keeping my eye
on the prize right now.
- I admire your attitude.
- Thank you.
So should we rent Old Yeller, too?
Or is it just a guy's crying movie?
You're not listening to me.
I am listening to you.
I just don't agree with you.
I don't want to wallow,
and you can't make me.
- Okay, fine.
- Thank you.
- So that must be the list.
- Yes, it is.
May I see it, please?
- We do not need a garden hose.
- We don't have one.
We don't have a garden either.
But maybe if we have a hose,
we can grow one.
- Could I see the pen for a sec?
- Why?
Small adjustment.
It's on the list.
Don't you have to do it if it's there?
I am not going to wallow.
But I put it after going
to the recycling center.
What are these people doing up?
It's Saturday morning.
- Some people like getting up early.
- You lie.
- No, they do it voluntarily.
- Really?
- Every day.
- Jump back.
Excuse me?
Kevin Bacon in Footloose,
reaction to the no-dancing-in-town rule...
as revealed by Chris Penn,
Sean's brother, sage to all.
You should have known
what they teach you in that damn school.
- What?
- I can't go that way.
- Why, we're going to Luke's.
- No.
You pulled me out of bed at 6:00 a. M...
and then you say no to Luke's?
Don't you know that's dangerous?
- I can't go that way.
- Reason, please?
- We'd have to go by Doose's market.
- So?
- So we might run into...
- Oh, right.
You don't know if he's working?
I don't remember.
His weekend schedule changes a lot.
We'll just take the long way.
- No, we'd have to go by the school.
- There's no school today.
On his days off,
he plays football there with his friends.
- Well, what time?
- It varies.
We'll just go down Peach, circle around...
You're shaking your head, why?
Dean lives on Peach.
Rory, honey, love of my life...
you realize you've cut us off from Luke's
where the happy coffee is.
- I'm sorry.
- No, it's okay.
We'll figure something out.
- Sorry.
- No, this is good.
It's like G.I. Jane,
but we get to keep our hair.
- I just couldn't.
- Honey, say no more.
Think of this as an adventure.
Two girls battling the elements,
desperate for survival.
- Or coffee.
- Same thing.
I bet you can tell a lot about people
from their garbage.
Think about it. Trash is discarded aspects
of people's lives.
It talks about their eating habits,
what they read...
do they go to concerts,
are they responsible...
do they pay their bills on time?
You know that trash doesn't actually talk
unless it's on Sesame Street.
I'm just trying to make a point.
That going through garbage is interesting.
- And educational.
- And stinky and a little nuts.
There's nothing nuts about wanting
to know more about human nature.
- Curiosity is how we grow.
- We need to get you out of this alley.
- Who are all these people?
- It's the 6:00 a. m. Crowd.
I officially recognize nobody in this place.
- Coffee while you wait?
- Bless you.
So Luke put you to work?
I figured if I'm hanging around here
for a while...
the least I could do is help out.
So you're gonna be hanging around
for a while here?
Yeah, I think so.
- That's nice.
- Yeah.
So where is Luke?
We were kind of up late last night,
so I let him sleep in.
Sleep in? Luke?
Believe me, it wasn't easy
to get him to agree to it...
but in the end, a little sweet talk,
a couple Excedrin PMs, he finally caved.
- There's a seat over there.
- Great.
- Go! I'll be over in a sec.
- Okay.
I feel like everyone is staring at me.
Yeah, because you've got a banana peel
stuck to your foot.
- I do?
- I'm kidding.
- Nobody's staring at you.
- They know.
- They don't know.
- It's probably all around town by now.
It just happened last night.
It's 6:00 in the morning.
Everyone knows that I've been dumped.
- Do you want to go home?
- No, we have a list.
Okay. Great.
I'm gonna order us something.
Any preferences?
Eggs, French toast, key to the dumpster?
- I don't care.
- I'll be right back.
Lorelai, what a nice surprise
so early in the morning.
So how's things?
You know, don't you?
Yes, and I feel awful.
I feel completely responsible.
You should.
I got Dean that job,
and I certainly encouraged them.
I felt they were so right together.
Please don't say anything to Rory about it.
She's concerned
about everybody finding out.
Of course. Not a peep.
- And spread the word, okay?
- Consider it done.
Would you give the angel a hug for me?
You don't have to say it's from me.
Just give her a hug.
- Got it.
- Okay.
Good morning, sleeping beauty.
Rachel thought I looked a little tired.
- No, it's good. You need a little break.
- I guess.
You do.
She seems pretty comfortable here?
She always could just fit in places,
you know. It's a talent of hers.
- She looks good in your apron.
- Yeah, can I get you anything?
Do you think you can make
those crazy chocolate chip pancakes...
and go extra heavy on the chocolate?
Yeah, sure. Any special occasion?
- Dean broke up with Rory.
- What?
Quiet. She doesn't want anybody to know.
I knew it. I knew that kid was trouble.
Yes, you did. You knew it.
Pancakes, please.
God, he's got a nerve.
What does he think?
He's gonna do better than Rory?
Is he crazy? Jeez. All right, forget it.
Good riddance, adios, bienvenidos,
hasta la vista.
Could we get off the Small World ride
and get cooking?
- How is she?
- She's been dumped by her first boyfriend.
Man, I swear I would love to...
Okay, I'm gonna put some whipped cream
on the pancakes, too.
Thank you, Luke.
- Not a word, okay?
- I got it.
I never liked him.
I don't know exactly what it was.
Something about the shape
of his forehead...
or his height or the floppy hairstyle.
Actually, on reflection,
I think it was the floppy hairstyle.
Good morning, Kirk.
I want to express my apologies
for not voicing my concerns...
about that floppy-haired jerk earlier,
because if I had...
You know what, you need to leave now.
I cannot go until you accept my apology.
- I accept your apology.
- All right.
- It will not happen again.
- Okay.
Thank you.
Honey, are you sure you don't want to...
- Do not say wallow.
- Swallow your coffee before you eat?
- I am fine.
- But if you could see the look on your face.
It's the same look you had on your face
when you broke up with Max.
Did wallowing help you get over him?
I'm not saying wallowing
will help you get over Dean.
It's part of the process.
It's the mourning period.
It's a step, an important step.
The only thing
that'll get you over somebody is time.
How much time did it take you
to get over Max?
- I'm not sure exactly.
- Approximately?
- I didn't clock it.
- Ballpark figure?
- A while.
- Be vaguer.
Rory, come on.
More coffee?
Pancakes are coming right up.
- Anything else I can get you?
- No, thanks.
I've got some strawberries back there.
You like strawberries, don't you?
- I like strawberries but...
- I'm getting you strawberries.
- You told him, didn't you?
- No. Miss Patty did.
- Who told Miss Patty?
- I don't know, numerous sources.
- Stop right there.
- What?
- Where you going?
- To get coffee.
- Wrong.
- Excuse me.
- You're not going in.
- What are you saying?
Turn around, bag boy.
- Are you serious?
- You see a smile on this face?
- No, but what's different about that?
- What's that supposed to mean?
You're not exactly known
as the town crackup.
So you're a smart guy now?
What the hell are you doing?
Exercising my right not to serve you.
What are you talking about?
I'm not even inside yet.
- Let go of me!
- You first!
If you tell Miss Patty,
everybody in town's gonna know.
People have their own lives and problems.
I hardly think you and Dean breaking up
is the main thing on their minds.
- Oh, my God!
- What?
Oh, my God.
Cut it out! Break it up!
What are you doing?
Back off! Come here.
What do you think you're doing?
- He started it.
- By doing what?
- He was coming in.
- Are you a lunatic! He's 16!
What was I supposed to do?
Stand in the street
and have a slap fight, of course.
Come here.
- Are you okay?
- I'm fine.
Good. I don't know what got into Luke.
He's usually so...
I have to go.
Sure. Bye.
- Get inside now. Inside. Now!
- He started it.
- So where's that list?
- What?
The list. We've got a lot to do today.
Otherwise I'll be dragging your butt...
out of bed
at 6:00 again tomorrow morning.
So where do we start?
We need a soap dish for the kitchen.
A kitchen soap dish.
Quite decadent, but what the hell?
Let's go.
- That was a very successful outing for us.
- Yes, it was.
We got everything
except for the brown extension cord.
Which will be in on Tuesday.
- So I think that qualifies as a check, too.
- Are you happy?
I appreciate a job well done, yeah.
I can't wait to try the toaster pizza.
It looks so gross...
which is usually the mark
of a great junk food.
- Beefaroni.
- Enough said.
I'm gonna plug in
my new wall air freshener.
Give me five minutes
and then come sniff my room.
- Cheese or pepperoni?
- Whatever.
Both. Good choice.
Sugar, I just heard. Where is she?
Poor little thing.
- Rory, sweetie!
- Come on.
Is she outside?
Babbette, I appreciate you
coming over like this...
but Rory's not really
in a talking mood just now.
- But I can help!
- I know.
I can tell her how to go through
a lot of bad relationships...
- to get to that really good one!
- It's very good advice.
And I can tell her about all
the horrible men I've known in my day.
Really truly awful men.
I was pushed out of a moving car once.
- That's a peppy little anecdote.
- Let me tell her.
I want you to tell her all that
but just not right now.
Is she really bad?
She'll be fine. Really.
- They had some of our mail.
- Look.
- 'Madeline's having a party. '
- I'm going to go.
- You're going to a Chilton party?
- Yes, I am.
Why don't you stay home
and read The Bell Jar? Same effect.
I'll be going to school there
for the next two-and-a-half years.
It wouldn't kill me to be social.
Right? What's wrong with that?
Nothing.
Okay, then it's settled.
- Can I make a suggestion?
- Go ahead.
Why don't you see
if Lane can come with you?
If the socializing doesn't turn out
how you planned...
you got a friendly face around.
- Okay, good idea. Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- Can I take the car?
- Yes.
- Can I borrow something to wear?
You gonna give in to anything
'cause you feel sorry for me?
I'll make a list.
- Here, hand me that blush.
- Okay.
Am I all twisty back here?
A little. Here.
So how are you?
I'm fine.
How are you really?
Life goes on, right?
I saw Dean today,
I wasn't sure if I should tell you.
Why not?
- I wasn't sure you'd want to know.
- No, that's fine. What did he say?
Nothing. He crossed the street
as soon as I saw him.
But if it's any consolation,
he looked really sad.
I don't want him to be sad.
Are you sure you wanna go out tonight?
Why does everyone keep asking me that?
Because you just broke up.
I'd be perfectly fine...
to just hang out here and listen to music,
talk, not talk, whatever.
No, I am not hanging out.
We're going to this party.
It's gonna be great.
I don't want to dwell on this. That's final.
Don't argue with her, or you'll find yourself
the proud owner of three garden weasels.
Three, 'cause one's just not enough.
- Here, turn around.
- Why?
Fourteen hours of labor, that's why.
And hair.
What is this?
I thought it would go with your dress,
and it does.
- It's pretty.
- It's really pretty.
Here is the phone and some mad money.
If you think you're not
gonna be home before 12:00, you call me.
We'll be back by 12:00.
- Call me.
- Sorry.
The cornstarch.
What?
The first time Dean kissed me...
I forgot to put it with the other things.
I'll throw it out.
Why don't you let me do that?
You guys get going, okay?
Okay, bye. Have fun.
Look in somebody's sock drawer.
Rich people have hilarious sock drawers.
Be good.
- Lorelai, hey.
- I wanted to ask you if...
- Sure, whatever.
- Sookie, hello?
Hi. How are you?
Good, I'm fine.
How's that x-ray vision coming?
Jackson's inside.
- Is he doing something dirty?
- He's making me dinner.
- That's so nice.
- Yeah, it is.
It really is, it's sweet. I'm just...
- Do you hear something?
- Like what?
Like someone using the wrong size pan
to sweat the onions in.
No, nothing like that.
Okay, maybe I'm hearing things.
So, hi, how are you?
Fine. So I wanted to see...
Could you peek inside the kitchen
and tell me...
if the orange Le Creuset
is on the far left burner.
Why don't you just go in there?
I would, but Jackson kicked me out.
He did.
He won't let me back in there.
It's driving me crazy.
Maybe he just wants you to relax.
I wouldn't mind that, either.
Just take a peek for me, will you?
Tell him you want some water.
And here. Take a picture for me.
Sookie, I'm not spying on Jackson.
What if he's using the wrong spoon
in the wrong sauce?
- Then the world as we know will end.
- I have to go in there.
You stay right where you are.
You're being unreasonable.
When a person offers
to make another person dinner...
because this person is a chef
and is always cooking for others...
that is what happens to be a nice gesture.
And when that person
accepts the first person's offer...
that means that the first person,
the one who offered to cook...
would actually be doing the cooking,
while the other person relaxed...
had some wine,
and stayed out of the kitchen!
I wasn't cooking. I was suggesting.
You suggested the ladle
right out of my hand four times!
I had to skim the top of the sauce or it...
Damn it, Sookie,
this is supposed to be romantic!
- It is!
- Stay out of here.
I am cooking this meal alone.
I'm also cleaning up alone.
- No.
- Yes.
But you don't know
how to load my dishwasher. I've a system.
I'll wing it.
There's a diagram in the pantry!
Use it! I'm begging you.
I'm doing two loads just because I can!
Honey, try to sit down and relax.
It's nice what he's doing.
I know, you're right. It is nice.
Okay. All right.
I'm sitting. I'm relaxing.
I'm focusing on you.
Good. Actually, I wanted
to ask you a favor.
- What?
- Could I take your car for a little while?
Rory's got mine,
and there's something I want to do.
Yeah, of course.
- What's so important?
- I'll tell you later.
It sounds so serious.
I'll have it back to you as soon as I can.
- Take your time. I'm in for the night.
- Okay. Bye, hon.
What happened? What did you do?
Lorelai, what...
Rory and Dean broke up.
I'm sorry.
Rory and Dean broke up,
and she won't wallow.
And I told her that she should wallow...
because that's supposed
to help you get through the pain...
and then you can accept it,
and get over somebody...
and you can move on with your life.
And then she asked me
how long it was before I got over you.
And I didn't know what to say
because I can't lie to her.
I realized that if I gave her
any time frame at all...
that I would be lying
because I'm not over you.
And I don't know
how long it will be before I am.
Who am I to teach her about healing,
moving on, and breakups?
I might as well be teaching her
to eat fire or swallow a sword...
or put her legs behind her head
because at least that's a trade.
I mean, the first two. I don't know
about putting the legs behind your head.
But the point is
that I'm an idiot, and I'm a hypocrite.
And I really...
miss you.
- Do you want to come in?
- Yes. Please.
This is unbelievable.
My wedding won't be this big.
This is amazing! People live here?
This is Madeline's house.
Is this what
your grandparents' house looks like?
No. I mean, it's big,
but it's not this Hearst Castle-y.
There should be a map or a tour guide
or Robin Leach or something.
- Lane, thanks for coming with me.
- Anytime.
- My God, there's a pool table.
- And a deejay.
It's like a teenage Sodom and Gomorrah.
You came!
Who's watching the farm?
- Madeline, your house is beautiful.
- Thanks, it's my stepfather's.
So, where is he?
- My stepfather? He's in Japan.
- Not your stepfather. Prince Charming.
He didn't come.
His white horse was in the shop.
You guys didn't break up, did you?
- Hi, I'm Lane.
- As in, walk down a?
- Yes, exactly.
- Hi, I'm Madeline.
So when does
the tour of the pool house start?
You've seen the pool house before.
But they haven't seen it at night, right?
Madeline, you are not confused.
Think, process, focus.
Bye.
- Later, Paris.
- No glove, no love.
Lovely.
- I didn't think you were a party girl.
- I'm not usually.
But I thought I might come by
and check it out.
It's the same exact people
we see every day at school...
except now we get to see them dance.
So where is your boyfriend?
We broke up.
At least you had a boyfriend for a while.
Do you know which way
will lead us to some soda?
Keep up because I'm not turning around.
- You didn't exaggerate.
- Paris needs no embellishment.
All of this soda is French.
Madeline's mother has a French fetish.
She's obsessed with all things French.
French wine, French food, French water,
French cellulite products.
- Why won't you answer me?
- Because you didn't say 'please. '
Can we do this later?
There's a party going on.
Tell me what you were doing
locked in the bathroom with Austin.
- Nothing.
- Yes.
- No.
Why don't you tell me what I was doing,
since you seem to know everything.
- You are my girlfriend.
- Now he is a caveman.
What are you gonna do?
Knock me on my head with a club...
and then drag me back to your Porsche?
Summer, please.
Good song.
I just love that Summer, don't you?
9:45.
- Why do you keep checking your watch?
- My mom says I have to stay till 10:30.
Why would she care?
She thinks
I'm not enough of a people person.
- Shocking?
- I'm floored.
I doubt highly that Madame Curie...
was voted 'most likely
to dress like Jennifer Lopez. '
- You want to be a scientist?
- Cancer research.
- Cool.
- Yeah.
- Oh, no.
- What?
It just figures that
the only Korean boy at this party...
has his Korean-girl radar turned on.
- I'm Henry.
- I'm Lane. This is Rory and Paris.
- We've met.
- Hi, Paris.
- So would you like to dance?
- We're talking here.
Yeah, but, I mean, one dance?
You can put the conversation on hold
for one dance.
Unless this is
a Mid-East Peace Talk conversation.
- One dance.
- A short one. No crazy dance mixes.
- Okay.
- Thank you.
If I'm not back in one dance,
you're coming down...
with a really bad case of anything
that means we have to go home.
- Is it getting warm in here, or is it me?
- Thank you.
Unbelievable. She's here
five minutes, she has a date.
I've been going to this school 9 years,
and I'm the French-soda monitor.
Just in case this comes up later,
I did not come here for this.
Okay, got it.
- This is crazy!
- No, it is. It's nuts.
I don't see you for months,
and then all of a sudden...
Ding-dong, Avon lady.
- It's insane.
- Completely.
You do that so good.
- We got to get a grip.
- I thought that's what we're doing.
You're gonna sit over there on that couch.
And I'm gonna sit over here on this chair...
far away from the couch.
And I'm gonna put this table
right in between us...
just like that. Good, okay.
And we're gonna sit here
and talk about this calmly.
Sounds good.
- How you been?
- Really good.
- You look really good.
- So do you.
- I missed you.
- I'm glad.
Otherwise that greeting there
would have been a little inappropriate.
Actually, I've been
thinking about us lately.
You have?
- Haven't you?
- No.
- I haven't given it any thought at all.
- I'm flattered.
I needed not to give it any thought...
otherwise I would give it
too much thought and that would be hard.
So I just didn't deal.
- Like mother, like daughter, I guess.
- I understand.
With all the thought you've been giving,
have you come up with any solutions?
No. You're still Rory's mother,
and I'm still her teacher.
And we're still us. I got nothing.
- So nothing's changed?
- Nothing's changed.
I guess my coming here
was probably a bad idea.
Probably.
Screw this!
- Am I sick yet?
- Not yet. It might just be allergies.
Keep me posted.
My watch stopped. What time is it?
- It's 10:35.
- Yes! Bye.
Tristan, stop it.
You're making me chase you
around the whole party.
Just trying to have fun.
You won't talk to me or dance.
Why did you even come with me?
Stop yelling.
Summer, please, can we just go?
- Please.
- No. I'm sick of fighting with you.
I'm sick of hearing 20 times a day,
'You're my girlfriend. '
Could we do this where
a roomful of people aren't staring at us?
I think we should break up.
- I want to go outside and talk about this.
- Then go. Bye.
Summer, come on!
- I have a major problem.
- What?
Henry, the guy I have been dancing with.
Okay, he's really good in school.
He's gonna be a doctor.
Pediatrician, to be exact.
His parents are extremely involved
in their local church.
He himself helps out with Sunday school.
He speaks Korean fluently,
he respects his parents.
And he's also really cute, very funny,
and surprisingly interesting.
Lane, I'm sorry, but I'm totally failing
to see the problem here.
I'm falling for a guy
my parents would approve of!
They'd love him! They'd go crazy!
There'd be dancing in the Kim house!
- Dancing!
- Really?
Followed by a lot of praying.
But initially, there'd be dancing.
This is horrible. It can't happen.
I have to stop it. We need to go.
No, now. You need
to grab your stuff, we got to go.
Okay. Whatever you say.
- Hey!
- Henry, hi!
Sorry, I've been
monopolizing Lane all night.
No, that's okay. I've had her for 15 years.
I'm actually a little sick of her.
- Thank you.
- You are welcome.
- We should go.
- You're going?
Yeah, I have to get home.
I have a very strict mother.
Sorry about that. You couldn't even stay
for one more dance?
- I don't think...
- Yes.
- Excuse me?
- One dance would be fine.
Great.
I'll be back!
I certainly did not come over here for that.
I know.
You are a wonderful man.
What happens now?
I don't know.
It's late. I have to get Sookie's car back.
Wait a second.
So this is it? You leave,
and we forget this ever happened?
No.
Then what?
I leave, and we go on with our lives...
and then at some point
we buy some soup.
- What? Soup is good food.
- Stop.
I don't want to leave here
and forget this ever happened.
I want to think of a solution
that will make everything better.
And I've been racking my brain for an idea.
Hence the babbling
about soup being good food.
But I can't think of anything.
I think we should talk.
- What?
- On the phone.
You and me, about us, on a regular basis.
We're not gonna solve this thing
away from each other.
No, we're not.
And obviously,
we are not gonna solve this...
by not staying away from each other.
But we'll burn more calories.
- I want to solve this.
- So do I.
So we'll talk?
We'll talk.
- I thought we were supposed to be talking.
- There's plenty of time for talk.
Sorry.
No problem.
I'm sorry.
- About what?
- About you and Summer.
I don't want to talk about Summer.
How did you do on that biology test?
What?
The test. It was hard, wasn't it?
Yeah, it was hard.
I got a B plus.
- What are you doing?
- Talking about the test.
Why?
You said you didn't want
to talk about Summer.
I don't.
Okay, so I moved to biology.
Sorry, did you want to talk about Spanish?
You just loved it, didn't you?
- Loved what?
- Seeing me nailed like that.
- It must have been a great moment.
- Not really.
You loved it, she loved it,
everybody loved it.
I did not love it.
- I really liked her, too.
- Yeah, I know.
So where's your boyfriend tonight?
He's not my boyfriend anymore.
- Why not?
- He didn't want to be.
Idiot.
So is Summer.
You think you'll get back together?
He was pretty set in his decision.
- When did it happen?
- Yesterday.
Wow.
It was our three-month anniversary.
- That sucks.
- Yeah, it does suck.
Do you think you guys will?
- No.
- So, no?
No.
I'm sorry I gave you
such a hard time for a while.
- That's okay.
- It is?
No, but you're sad.
I am sorry.
I accept your apology.
Man, it's a great party?
Yeah, not bad.
It gave me a chance
to catch up on my reading.
You are very odd, you know that?
Thank you.
You're welcome.
I'm sorry. What did I do?
Did I bite your lip or something?
No, it's not you. I just have to go.
- We have to go.
- Rory, are you okay?
- I have to go.
- Wait, can I get your number?
Last name's Kim.
We're the only ones in Stars Hollow.
I can't believe I just gave my number
to a potential Korean doctor.
I'm ready to wallow now.
Hey, Joe, it's Lorelai.
I need a pizza with everything, okay?
Thanks.
www.tvsubtitles.net