So the hunter comes out of the tent,
looks around, and says,
"ah, very well then.
Now, where's that gorilla?"
Well, now you've heard dad's big
game-hunter-and-the-gorilla joke,
you're officially
part of the family.
It's not too late to back out.
Yes, Richard, I beg you --
get some new material.
I actually like the joke,
and the family is
not bad, either.
Thanks for a great meal, Emily.
Yes, thank you, grandma.
You're quite welcome.
Did you really like the meal?
It was incredible, mom.
On our recent trip to Mexico, your
father and I were served quail Mazatlán,
and I insisted that
Bridget find the recipe.
Well, she found it.
Yeah. Tell that Bridget that that
quail Mazatlán was a triumph.
It's the tequila-cactus
sauce that makes it special.
- So special.
- Really just great.
Well, young lady,
I'll see you around the campus.
Yes, you will.
And Lorelai, it turns out that I have
an emergency D.A.R. board meeting
on tuesday,
so I won't be able to get together
to finalize the seating
chart for the party.
No seating-chart get-together?
How will I live?
I'll help you get through it.
Christopher, are you sure
you can't stay for a cigar?
Cuban. Montecristo.
Perfect complement to
a tequila-cactus sauce.
Dad, we really
have to get going.
She's right, but maybe I
could get a Montecristo to go.
Oh, nice try.
I thought I'd give it a shot.
Another time for cigars.
I'll see you, Rory.
- Bye, grandma.
- Bye, bye.
- See you in class, Rory.
- See you!
Oh, my god!
I thought for sure your mom
saw me put mine in here.
How could so tiny a quail
have such a big, awful taste?
I think the sauce burned
through my napkin.
And now we just throw
it in the bushes?
No! We tried that before.
The chicken Kiev.
The baava, too.
Yeah. The neighbor's cat find it
and dragged it to the back patio.
So busted.
How do we get rid of it?
We take it with us in the car.
And we give it the old
heave-ho over Tyler's bridge.
Got to make sure we get every
piece in the water, though.
Oh yeah.
One stray piece of quail Mazatlán,
and grandma will have
the river dragged.
We need something to weigh them down.
Hey, how attached are you to that watch?
Transcript : Raceman
Subtitles : Willow's Team
www.forom.com
Morning!
Ow! What was that for?
Thought maybe I was dreaming.
Then you're supposed to
ask me to pinch you.
You're not supposed
to pinch me.
Well, I'm confused.
I haven't even had my coffee yet.
I have your coffee and
muffins hot from the oven.
Well, actually, they're not really
muffins. They're muffin tops
because the muffin tops are
the only parts you like.
You baked me a whole
basket of muffin tops?
Yep.
I have got apple-cinnamon-walnut,
lemon-poppy seed,
apple spice,
and double chocolate chip,
which is really more
cake than muffin.
But if calling them a muffin means
you can eat them in the morning,
then I am all for it.
So, which would you like?
Um,  the cake one, please.
Ooh, good choice.
Ta-da.
Sookie?
What are you doing here?
It's not even 7:00.
What?!
Why can't a girl get up
super early on her day off,
make some muffin tops,
and bring a hot cup of coffee
over to the best friend and business
partner a girl could ever have?
I guess.
I mean,
I had to get up early anyway.
Jackson and I are going skiing.
We're so excited.
We haven't done that
since before the kids.
Hmm. That's cool.
Yeah, Jackson loves to ski,
and I love to dress up in those
cozy clothes, the furry boots,
and curl up with
a Sue Grafton mystery.
I got "'R' is for 'ricochet'"
and "'S' is for 'silence.'"
If the ski conditions are good, I can get
a good eight hours of Kinsey Millhone in.
Yeah, we were so excited.
"Were"?
Our, uh,
babysitter called last night,
and she's got mono.
Yeah. How is that,
uh, muffin top?
It has the faintest
aftertaste of bribe.
I know it's a lot of work to
take care of the kids, and...
and I know that it's your day off, too,
but I would really, really appreciate it,
and I would really,
really, really owe you big.
I'd love to take care
of Davey and Martha.
Oh, did I happen to mention
that you're the best friend
and business partner a
girl could ever have?
I believe you led with that.
Oh, good, because you are.
Thank you.
No problem.
God, this coffee is good.
Well, yeah, it should be.
I got it from Luke's.
Sorry. Is that weird?
Oh, no, that's not weird.
Good.
I mean, it shouldn't be weird.
No, it shouldn't be weird.
It would be weird if I intentionally
didn't drink the coffee.
- That would be weird.
- Yeah, that would be weird.
I mean, it's good coffee.
Yeah, and there's no reason you
shouldn't enjoy good coffee.
- Exactly.
- Good.
Yeah, so it's not weird.
What did you do with
the muffin bottoms?
I made a muffin-bottom pie.
It's actually pretty good.
I'm thinking about patenting it.
Mmm, muffin-bottom pie --
sounds dirty.
Mm-mmm! There are
baked goods in here.
At first I thought
I was dreaming.
- Please don't pinch me.
- When I realized I wasn't,
I thought, "somebody must've
broke in here and started baking."
Baking and entering --
it's a crime wave sweeping the nation.
Just not used to that smell.
Well, enjoy.
Sookie brought us coffee
- and freshly baked muffin tops.
- Muffin tops?
- They are the best part.
- Okay.
You got to be careful, though,
because they induce a sugar coma
where it makes you say,
"yes, yes, anything, yes."
I needed her to babysit today.
- You need anything from me?
- Nope.
Then we're good to go.
Actually, this is gonna work out well.
Ship the daughter unit
off to her grandmother,
get rid of the wife unit,
leaving the husband unit free
to do some good,
old-fashioned manual labor.
He's  putting up a flat-screen.
Oh, flat-screen what?
Come on. Are you serious?
TV.
- Oh.
- Yeah.
You'll see.
You're gonna love it.
Well, I should get going.
I have to get ready for skiing.
Oh, hey,
do you have any magazines
in case I get through
both "R" and "S"?
- Yeah, on the hall table.
- Okay, great.
I'll get them on the way out.
Thank you, Lorelai.
I really, really appreciate it.
It's okay.
No, I mean, it takes a special
person to, you know, on her day off.
- No problem.
- Okay.
Look what you're making me do.
- Okay. Bye.
- Bye. Okay.
- Okay.
- Bye.
- Bye, Sookie.
- What was that?
- I don't know.
She's really excited about
her skiing/reading trip.
This is good coffee.
It is good.
It's from Luke's.
- Is that okay?
- Yeah.
Sookie brought it.
Are you sure?
Of course.
Why wouldn't it be?
Because.
It's fine.
Okay.
So, what do you do with
the muffin bottoms?
Oh, she turned them into a pie,
you know?
She's like an indian.
They use all the parts of the buffalo.
I don't fully
understand that woman.
She bakes good stuff.
That I get.
Oh, my god,
The Eagle Has Landed.
Yep, they delivered it while
you were in the shower.
Did they deliver
it or throw it?
Comes with a lot of equipment.
Isn't it beautiful?
Yeah. And big.
All the better to watch Reggie
Bush score touchdowns on.
I forget. Which one of the
Bush daughters is Reggie?
You're gonna love it.
Hey, have you seen the level?
The thing with the green bubble
that goes back and forth?
Yeah.
Yeah, Paul Anka and I
were playing with it.
You were playing with
it with the dog?
Yes. I was trying to
hypnotize him with the bubble,
see if I could talk him
out of the habit of chewing
on the corner of
the welcome mat,
or I was gonna give him a
wacky posthypnotic suggestion,
like the doorbell rings,
and he spins around in circles.
Were you able to hypnotize him?
No, Chris, he's a dog.
All right. I think you've got this under
control. I'm gonna go sit on some babies.
You do that. When you get back,
we'll sprawl out on the couch
and  watch flat-screen
plasma TV,
and the world as you know
it will never be the same.
- You smell good.
- Yeah?
Familiar.
Is that my conditioner?
Maybe. I don't know.
Are you using my conditioner?
Sometimes. Why?
You don't like to share?
No, I'm married now.
I love to share.
So, why is it so funny?
Because you don't have
that much to condition.
I know that, but --
It's just been really
unruly lately?
All right.
I got work to do here.
All right, listen,
I love that you're using my conditioner,
and I love that you're putting up this
Jumbotron thingy all by yourself,
and I can't wait to come home
and watch flat sports with you,
and I love you -- goodbye.
I will be here.
Hey, if you feel like shaving, I've got
a brand-new lady schick in the drawer.
Feel free to use it.
Oh, I might just do that.
Danes vs. Nardini?
Custody case.
Oh, yeah, right.
Uh, no, Nardini is not here.
Nobody is here.
I mean, well,
nobody from -- okay.
Luke.
Oh, hey, Jim. Hey.
- Been waiting long?
- No, no, no, I got here early.
I wasn't sure where I was supposed
to park, so I got here early.
- Always a good idea.
- Yeah, listen, uh...
I meant to ask you --
will I start with a statement?
No, no,
you won't start with any statement.
Okay.
Actually, the less you say,
the better,
which is good because the more you say,
the more they can, well, you know.
Right, right. Will they make a
decision right away? Do they tell us?
Listen, I got to make a quick call.
Give me a sec?
Oh, yeah, no. Go.
Go right ahead.
Oh, hey.
Hello, Luke.
They're not -- we're not --
Oh, are we early?
Yeah, I guess,
or they're behind.
Did you park in the garage?
Yeah, do I get this
thing stamped or what?
I don't know.
I didn't park in the garage.
Oh. Okay.
Man, this place, huh?
Yeah, what a waste of time.
Yeah.
Especially  since there's
no reason for it.
Well, I mean...
But you have to finish
what you started, right?
What I started?
Yes, when you hired a lawyer.
Well, I had to hire a lawyer.
It was the only way I could see my kid.
I mean, come on.
You really think you have a chance?
Yeah, well,
that's for a judge to decide.
Well, step back.
Take a look at it.
I mean, look at yourself.
You're... you --
a hermit living above a diner in
some old, converted hardware store.
It doesn't exactly paint a
picture of "capable father."
It doesn't matter where I live,
and I have been nothing
but a good father to April.
And you're not gonna get any points
for your history with women, either.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Bailed on Lorelai,
got divorced in a heartbeat.
I did not bail on Lorelai.
You have had no long-term
relationships, Luke.
Why would a judge trust
you to have one with April?
April -- huh! -- knows --
Hi. Anna, all set?
Hello, Barbara.
Jim.
Can we go in?
The judge is ready for you.
Perfect timing.
- Hey, Paris.
- Hey, Rory.
Just a second.
I'm in the middle of something.
- Did you have a good --
- Shh! No.
I have to set up that Goldman Sachs
interview before spring break.
My Christmas was fine, thank you.
I assume yours was, too?
It was nice.
Good. We've got the pleasantries
out of the way. Can we move on?
I hope so.
I am emotionally spent.
What's all this?
This is the game plan for what
I call operation finish line.
- Need more.
- Okay.
We only have five months
left before we leave
the warm and comforting
bosom of this university
and face the bitterly cold
shoulder of the real world.
- "We"?
- You and I.
You're the green marker.
Green was a random choice,
not a subtle comment about how inexperienced
you are with real-life matters.
Then again, maybe it was.
So I applying for an
oceanography fellowship?
And I might point out that the application
is due by february 28.
But I know nothing
about oceanography.
I can't even tell you which
direction the ocean is.
You apply, you get the fellowship,
then you decide if you want it.
I already know I don't want it.
It's a defensive move.
It's like monopoly.
Your little wheelbarrow lands on St.
James place.
You think, "I don't really want
St. James place, but I don't want
some other schmo to get it,
so I'll stick a plastic house there."
Am I getting through to you?
You're making me want
to play monopoly.
Look, come the semester's end,
you're gonna thank me for this chart.
We cannot graduate unprepared.
Paris, there is no way we're gonna
have time to do all this stuff.
I'm not saying it's not gonna be
time-consuming, but there's two of us,
so we'll divide it all up and
report back to each other.
I think we should have
weekly report-back sessions.
How about friday
afternoons at 5:00?
There's something to look forward
to at the end of the week.
- Jackson!
- One minute.
- Jackson, get the door!
- One minute!
That's okay. I'm fine.
Get the door!
Getting it, getting it.
- Sorry, Lorelai.
- That's okay.
I just put Martha down for a nap,
and Sookie is getting dressed.
She's picking out
an outfit now.
Thanks again for doing this.
Sure. So, where is Davey?
I don't know.
I haven't seen him all day long.
That's too bad. I brought over
something special for him,
but if he's not here,
I guess I'll just take it back home.
No!
Oh, there you are. Here you go.
Check out what's in my bag.
So, how's Christopher?
Oh, he's good. He's putting up a
ginormous flat-screen as we speak.
Cool. What's the
pixel aspect ratio?
- It's got two remotes.
- I'll ask him.
Good idea. Hey.
Do you like this sweater on me?
Yeah, honey, it's great.
I don't like it.
I'm gonna change.
So, the four of us should
go out sometime soon.
Sounds good.
I mean, I was gonna ask you
two to join us next week
in Woodbury for
couples-bowling night,
but you don't really seem like
the couples-bowling type.
Why? What's the
couples-bowling type?
I don't know,
sort of boring married people.
But I am a boring
married person now.
-  Do you even like bowling?
- Not when I was single,
but maybe now that I'm boring and
married, it would be right up my alley.
- You have to wear the shoes.
- Forget it.
- How about this?
- Ooh, that I really like.
That's nice,
the style and the color.
No, it's all wrong.
I'm gonna change.
Is she okay?
Sookie? Um, yeah, she's fine.
So, buddy,
what did Lorelai bring?
Her magic socks.
I could tell you what they do, but it's
kind of private between me and Davey.
Oh, yeah.
That's perfect --
perfect, perfect, perfect. Let's go.
- Are you sure?
- Absolutely.
Kinsey Millhone is
waiting for you.
You don't think it's
a little too --
No, I love that sweater.
Don't you, Lorelai?
Yes, I love, love, love it.
Great. See?
Everything is great.
See you later, buddy.
Thanks again for doing this.
- Come on. Let's go.
- I can't leave them.
- You can.
- No, I can't. They need me.
They're going to be fine.
Come on. Let's go.
Don't you want mommy to stay
here and play with you?
Wouldn't that be fun?
Come on. Let's go hit those
slopes and crack those books.
- Thanks again, Lorelai.
- Okay. Bye.
All right. Come here. Let's see
your magic socks. Let's see 'em.
Come here.
Where do you want to go?
- The jungle.
- The jungle?
You better start kicking.
Start kicking to get to the jungle.
Kick! Kick!
You got to kick to get there.
Don't apologize, Connor. That's
precisely why I have office hours.
Oh, and I'm supposed to tell you
that you can also query me by email,
although to be honest, I check it about
as often as I do the Daily Racing Form.
Thanks.
Yeah.
Miss Gilmore,
I believe you're next.
The visiting lecturer
will see you now.
Thank you.
Oh, I like your office.
It's cozy.
That's one way to
describing it.
So, have you come as a loving
granddaughter visiting your grandfather
or as an obsequious student trying
to butter up her professor?
Well, I'm not buttering up.
Oh, good.
Well, actually --
Oh, I thought I smelled butter.
You know my, uh,
roommate, Paris?
Oh, I've met Paris.
Well, and you don't
have to do this,
but she wanted me to ask you if
you might be able to help her
to set up an informal
get-together with Dean Kerrigan.
To what end?
I think she wants some kind of
recommendation for after graduation.
I see.
And I guess it wouldn't hurt
for me to meet him, as well.
But you don't have to.
I suppose I could
speak to Dean Kerrigan.
He's an affable gentleman.
He's probably not averse to getting
together for wine and cheese
and meeting a pair of bright,
soon-to-be graduates. I'll look into it.
Really? Okay. Thanks, grandpa.
So, I'm looking forward to
having you in class again.
Me too.
I think you'll find this class more
stimulating than last semester's.
I'm expanding on some
economic principles here,
like pricing strategies under
varying economic conditions
that can be actually
useful to -- sorry.
I shouldn't bore you until
you're sitting in my class,
getting credit for it.
No, I'm not bored.
I'm sorry, grandpa.
I just have a lot off my mind.
Is everything all right?
I just -- It's senior year,
you know, last semester.
There's charts all
over my apartment,
and I'm going through
something with a friend, so --
- Paris?
- No, someone else.
I hurt her feelings, and even after
writing her a very long letter of apology,
she hasn't gotten back to me,
and I just feel terrible.
I see.
Well, I doubt it's as
bad as you think it is.
I'm sure the girl
will get back to you.
Maybe she's just a
very slow reader.
Oh, honey,
anybody who knows you
knows you would never do anything to
purposely hurt someone's feelings.
That's just it.
We don't know each other that well.
She's a new friend.
We don't have a history.
Well, I wouldn't
worry about it.
Rory, you're a person
of great heart
and great character.
And that combination
will always win the day.
I hope so.
So, can I interest
you in syllabus?
I was just trying
to be helpful.
Cut it out. You're bugging me.
Hi. Wow, you're home early.
I'm sorry it's such a mess.
Um, the magic socks
took us back in time.
We were cavemen. It was really bleak,
so we lived like this.
I would've cleaned up,
but when they woke up,
the magic socks were gonna take
us to an orphanage in England
where they had to tidy up in
exchange for one teaspoon of gruel.
Sounds fun.
Don't worry about the mess.
So, how was the skiing/reading?
Oh, uh, terrible.
Oh, come on.
You had fun all morning.
I could've had fun all day.
We meet up for lunch. He spills
my hot toddy all over the table,
and he won't let me
order another one.
- "Let you"?
- Yeah, let me.
He said if I ordered another one,
he'd just do it again.
I just don't think drinking
is appropriate at lunch.
It was one drink.
Sometimes that's all it takes.
And he wouldn't let me ski.
- You mean read?
- No. Ski.
"'S' is for 'silent'" sucked,
so I thought,
"why don't I strap on some skis
and try a little downhill?"
This one wouldn't let me.
Conditions were terrible.
It was really icy.
Well, apparently you make all the rules,
your highness.
Could I go check on my children?
Could I do that, huh?
No, that's fine. Sounds good.
So, thanks a lot for sitting.
We really appreciate it.
Jackson, seriously,
what's going on with you two?
Nothing much. You?
Jackson, why wouldn't
you let her drink?
- It's a bad precedent.
- Or ski?
I didn't want her to get hurt.
There's all these snowboarders
on the hill these days,
and they just come
tearing down --
Jackson, what is
going on with you two?
Nothing.
- You're acting strange.
- No, I'm not.
So is Sookie.
She's all weird and moody.
The last time she was like that,
she was pregnant.
- What?
- No.
- No
Maybe?
Jackson, I thought
you got a vasectomy.
Oh, so she says,
"go get a vasectomy,"
and I'm just supposed
to go get a vactomy?
No, you shouldn't do it if
you didn't want to do it,
but if you didn't want to do it, you
should've told her you didn't want to do it.
I didn't see the point.
- Now I see the point.
- Jackson.
She said she was staying on the pill.
She said it gave her skin a healthy glow.
Yeah, she went
off it last month.
I know that now.
You'd think that's the kind of
thing a wife would tell her husband.
Not when she thinks the
husband had a vasectomy.
I know. I know.
Jackson, you have to
tell her she's pregnant.
I was going to today
after we had a great time
and she was in a great mood,
but then she wanted
to ski and drink.
- Well, you wouldn't let her.
- She's pregnant.
I know that and you know that,
but don't you think Sookie should
be let in on the good news?
All right, all right.
- Good luck.
- Yeah. Thanks.
Honey? Honey?
No!
You can't just order someone
to go get a vasectomy...
You know what?
J-Just be really quiet right now!
...like it's a haircut.
Don't speak. Don't breathe.
Don't even look at me.
I'm gonna go for a walk,
and while I'm gone,
you're gonna have that taken care of.
- But --
- No. No talking.
Just do it,
or when get home, I will.
Lorelai, let's go!
As we all know, your honor,
custody cases must center
on what's in the best
interest of the child.
And as we all know,
"best interest" is
a subjective term.
For Mr. Danes to have as much
access to April as he's seeking
would certainly not be
in her best interest.
To deny the child
access to her father
would be
psychologically damaging.
Why? The child has only seen Mr.
Danes on sporadic occasions
whenever he found time in his
schedule to allow her to visit.
He made himself available to
her as often as she liked.
Truth be told,
during the past year,
April has spent more
cumulative hours
with the man who drives her
school bus than with Luke Danes.
Why don't we ask my client to allow the
bus driver shared custody of the child?
Bit of a stretch there,
miss Campbell.
My point, your honor,
is that April's connection
to Mr.
Danes is superficial at best.
To her,
he's a man who works in a diner
who only recently revealed
himself to be her father.
Owns. I own the diner.
I don't just work there,
and April came to me.
Yeah, without my knowing it.
Exactly. You had no intention of
letting me know I had a daughter.
Excuse me.
I suggest you let your
attorneys speak for you.
It is why you pay them all
your hard-earned money.
I apologize, your honor.
Yeah. Sorry.
I just -- and he really --
ohh! You know?
And he didn't, and then I-I
can't believe that he -- ohh!
Ooh! You know, 'cause he didn't have --
He didn't.
And I can't believe
that he could've.
You know you can't walk
off a pregnancy, right?
I had just delivered his baby,
and then what?
I'm supposed to go and
hold my husband's hand
while he get's a vasectomy
to make sure he does?
No. It's too much.
I mean, I-I-I'm not his mother.
I'm already a mother.
I don't have the time
to baby a grown man.
I know.
What am I supposed to do --
start watching him brush his teeth?
Does he want me to
start cutting his meat?
I don't think he wants
his meat cut at all.
Well, how could he do this?
I guess he didn't really
want to have a vasectomy.
- Well, then, tell me.
- I agree.
- Uhh!
- I know. Uhh!
I didn't --
There was less than 4,000 left.
- 4,000?
- Diapers, diapers.
For the last year and a half,
I've been changing 20 diapers a day,
and finally --
finally I've got Davey.
He's potty-trained. It's good.
Martha has always gone
through a little more.
I mean, girls --
it's a boy-girl thing. I don't know.
Boys seem to be perfectly happy
sitting in their own filth.
I didn't know that.
Yeah, and Martha is
12 diapers a day.
And then if you add the --
but that's not the point.
The point is that there was a
light at the end of the tunnel,
and now the light at the end of the
tunnel is no more because you can't
do that
with 23 diapers a day. 26.
If it's a girl,
that's 26 diapers a day.
You could use cloth diapers, you know?
You wash them and --
That's not the point. That's not the
point. I get it. That's a lot of diapers.
But you know,
babies are more than diapers, right?
- No, no.
- Sookie.
No, all I remember is eat,
sleep, poop.
Well, there's other stuff.
Yeah, like diaper rash and
colic and potty-training.
No, the good stuff.
Well, I'm having trouble
remembering that.
For one thing,
they're pretty cute.
Well, but cute is not gonna help
me sleep through the night.
They smell great -- that newborn smell.
I mean, you can't beat that, right?
The smell is pretty good.
How about, you know,
when you give them their first bath?
I remember when I gave
Rory her first bath,
she looked up at me like,
"what the hell is going on?"
And I kept saying, "I'm sorry,
I'm sorry, I'm sorry."
Davey loved his first one.
Martha screamed bloody murder.
Oh, my god, all the screaming.
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
but how about the first time
when they're crying and crying,
and you go in to pick them up,
and then they stop crying
because they recognize you?
- That's pretty cool.
- Yeah.
I'm not gonna sleep, though.
Well, you won't sleep,
but you'll get another first smile.
You know,
Davey had his at three weeks.
It's really advanced.
How about when you're lying down,
you're holding the baby,
and the baby falls
asleep on your chest?
They're all warm and cuddly.
Oh, god, I know what you're doing.
You're trying to make this sound good.
In the middle of the night,
when you're rocking the baby,
and everyone is asleep. And then they
fall asleep, and you fall asleep.
I'm hormonal,
and you are playing dirty.
It's pretty good stuff, huh?
I guess.
Really good.
Are you talking memory,
or are you thinking ahead?
Oh, uh, I don't know --
a little of both, I guess.
Really?
Well, the subject has come up.
It might come up again.
Oh, my god,
I'm gonna have another baby.
Yes, and I will be there to help you.
No muffin tops required.
Thank you. I know.
Oh, god, I hope I have a girl.
Ooh! Or a boy.
Well, chances are pretty good
you'll have one or the other.
So, we seem to have a block of
eight days here in late march
that is disturbingly free
of résumé-building activity.
Might be a good time to commit
to some volunteer work.
I'm not crazy about wheeling
around elderlies in bathrobes,
so I'm leaning
towards tree planting.
Sounds good.
I'll check out some
community-service sites online.
I found out the cutoff for the Lawrence
Way journalism fellowship application
is march 1st,
so we have to get on that.
And... Oh, have you written your
sample for the Iowa poetry prize?
Yeah, I think that one's
a little farfetched.
I mean, I only took one poetry class --
sophomore year.
Hannah Freeman is applying for a
Fulbright to study space travel
in Luneberg, Germany.
Do you think she's ever
traveled to space?
Besides, the writing
sample is a poem --
takes 20 minutes to write,
2 if it's haiku.
I know, but --
You could've told me you were
going to be so resistant
to operation finish line
when we agreed to it.
I'm sorry.
When did we agree to it?
And this is not about making charts.
It's about our careers.
It's about life.
I'm trying to help you here.
Did you talk to your grandfather about
hooking me up with Dean Kerrigan?
Hmm? Hum, yeah, I did.
I did that.
And?
Um, he said he'd look into it.
"Look into it"?
That's not going to cut it.
You have got to put
the screws to the guy.
I don't care if he's your grandfather.
He's part of our game plan,
and he's got to play ball.
Why do you keep...
- Is that Lucy?
- Yeah.
- Have you heard from her yet?
- No.
Oh, so now she's decided
to just ignore you?
How very "Heathers" of her.
I don't think she saw me.
Paris, no.
Okay, look,
it's time to put an end
to this little junior-high
game you're playing.
Hey, Paris.
Have you read Rory's
letter or not?
Um, yeah, I just --
Would you please tell her you
forgive her and kiss and make up,
because it's really
messing with her head?
Um, sorry, Lucy, I didn't --
Don't apologize.
I've got her on the ropes.
I just got back an hour ago,
so just read your letter.
Yeah? And?
Well, it's not really fair,
I mean, you being a writer.
Yeah, yeah, life's not fair.
Can you let her off the hook,
for god's sakes?
In case you didn't know it,
Rory is a great person,
and she does not deserve
to be treated this way.
Anyone should fell lucky
to call her a friend.
I know I do, and you're
throwing away one of the best.
Paris, please.
I appreciate where this is coming from,
but can we just have a minute?
It was a really
beautiful letter.
Thanks.
Look, I know that Marty put you
in a really crappy position.
Yeah, but I -- Well, he did.
Totally crappy.
But I could've said,
"no, Marty,
you're being stupid and immature."
Which he was so being.
But I just --
I handled it wrong. I mean,
can I say again how
much I screwed up?
No, you didn't screw up.
Marty asked you to do something
really weird and wrong,
and you did it 'cause
you're a great person.
Ask Paris.
Well, I don't know about --
I even tried to figure out what
I would've done in your shoes,
and, I mean, I even tried to act it out
with Olivia playing the role of Marty.
- Seriously?
- I know, right?
Any chance to act.
But it didn't really work
because as much as I love Olivia,
her Marty was so over-the-top.
Are things okay
with you and Marty?
Not so much. We broke up.
Oh, no.
Oh, well, right?
I'm so, so sorry.
No, I mean,
it wasn't your fault.
It wasn't meant to be.
Listen, I got to go
to my first class.
- Oh, yeah, okay.
- But I'll call you, okay?
Okay. Yeah. See you.
- Everything okay now?
- Yep.
Good. Did you ask her about
actresses she knows at Yale Dramat?
Why have I even bothered
to do all this?
Yeah. There we go.
What?
That's straight.
It's straight.
Fine, you want to prove it?
I'll find a level and prove it.
Where's the level, Paul Anka?
The level!
Find the level, boy!
All right.
You've been absolutely no help.
All right, now, miss Nardini,
what kind of provisions
have you made for your
daughter in New Mexico --
house, schools?
I've already rented a
house in a nice area,
checked out the
immediate neighborhood,
and there's a lot of kids
there that are April's age.
I have enrolled her in a local school
that is very highly recommended,
um, put her up for swim team.
Your honor,
we don't contest that miss Nardini
will make April's transition
to the new living situation
as seamless as possible.
We contest the part where she cuts
the child off from her father.
A father she barely knows,
who does not have -- let's face it --
the most sterling
personal history.
Okay. Look.
I know what you're talking about,
and, yeah,
I've made a few mistakes.
- Luke, hang on.
- It's true.
I was married before,
and it only lasted a few months,
but it ended amicably...
pretty much.
Mr. Danes, I need you to --
I may live above a diner,
and some people may
see me as a hermit.
And I'm the first
person to admit
that all of my relationships
haven't exactly been long-term.
Mr. McNally.
Yeah, you know,
but this is different.
We are talking
about my daughter,
who I didn't even know I had for
the first 12 years of her life.
And now that I know her,
and I know I'm her dad,
I just want to be with
her and be her dad
'cause I know I
will be a good dad.
Mr. Danes, be quiet.
I'm sorry, your honor.
This won't happen again.
All right.
Now that I've had the opportunity to
hear from both sides in this case,
I'm going to read some personal
references into the court record.
The first letter is written
on behalf of Mr. Danes
by a miss Lorelai Gilmore.
This is dated january 9, 2007.
"To whom it may concern,
"in the nearly 10 years that
I have known Luke Danes,
"I have come to know him as
an honest and decent man.
"He's also one of the most kind
and caring persons I have ever met.
"I'm a single mother,
and I raised my daughter by myself,
"but once Luke Danes became
my friend in this town,
"I never really felt alone.
"Luke and I have had our ups
and downs over the years,
"but through it all, his relationship
with my daughter, Rory,
"has never changed.
"He's always been there
for her no matter what.
"He was there to
celebrate her birthdays.
"He was there cheering her on
at her high school graduation.
"Luke has been a sort of father
figure in my daughter's life.
"With his own daughter,
Luke wasn't given the opportunity
"to be there for
her first 12 years,
"but he should be given
that opportunity now.
"Once Luke Danes
is in your life,
"he is in your life forever.
"I know from personal experience
what an amazing gift that is,
"and not to allow him
access to his daughter
"would be to seriously deprive
her of all this man has to offer,
"and he offers so much.
"Thank you for your time.
"Sincerely, Lorelai Gilmore."
Hiya!
I want to see the TV.
Holy cripes, that's big.
Oh, my gosh.
Does that come with a slushee machine
and a gangly teenage Usher?
Honey, the deal with Sookie...
Chris?
I read your letter.
Honey, it's not a letter.
It's just a character reference
that Luke asked me to
write for his court case.
Reads like a letter.
Oh, yeah?
Almost like a love letter.
No, it's a favor that Luke
asked 'cause he needed --
You know what? Before you go
through a whole list of excuses,
let me just ask --
is our marriage for you
basically just marking time?
- What.
- Come on, Lore.
Of course not.
Obviously you still have very
deep feelings for the guy.
No, no, I just have known
him a long time, and he's...
Always been there,
always will be there.
Luke needed a character
reference for court
to prove that he deserves
partial custody of April,
and I know him really well.
Yes, you do.
And so it just made sens
that he would ask me
to write that
character reference.
I can't believe I just
had coffee from his place.
Coffee? Sweetie,
I told you Sookie brought that, okay?
Do you still talk to him?
I mean, do you see him?
This is crazy.
Hey, I got a right.
I have a right to know.
Occasionally I see him because
we live in the same town.
- Yeah, and I know you, Lore.
- And?
And I know that you're
not done with him.
Okay, this is ridiculous.
This is -- Hey.
This is a ridiculous
conversation, okay?
I have a history with him, yes.
I was engaged to him, yes.
But I married you.
Tell me you're not
in love with him.
I'm not in love with him.
I should've known.
I mean, all the signs were there.
What signs?
The fact that you didn't
want to leave Stars Hollow,
that you were dead set
against redoing the wedding,
that you didn't want to
have a baby with me.
I mean,
it's all because of him, right?
No. How can I tell --
It's over, okay?
What I had with him,
it's over, Chris.
Then why did you hide
the letter from me?
I wasn't hiding it. I put it in the
drawer in case they lost the typed copy
or the judge spilled coffee on it,
the dog ate it.
I don't know why I didn't
tell you about it.
I think that it's because
you're still in love with him.
No, I love you. I love you.
You know what?
I-I'm sorry, Lore.
I just -- I can't handle this.
- Handle what?
- This. You and him.
I just -- I can't handle
being your second choice.
I thought I could,
but I can't, all right?
I can't be your rebound.
I'm sorry.
Christopher?
Chris?
Okay, I will check out the
poposaurus project at the peabody,
but there is no way I'm
signing up for the lsats.
Sure you are.
Don't get lazy on me now.
The finish line is in sight.
I'm not being lazy, Paris.
I'm not interested in being a lawyer.
I'm interested in journalism.
Just because you go to law school doesn't
mean you have you have to be a lawyer.
Look at Dan Abrams -- he's a journalist
-- but because of his law degree,
he became the face of
the Scott Peterson trial.
I don't want to be the face
of the Scott Peterson trial,
and I hate Dan Abrams.
I will also not be taking the mcats.
Sanjay Gupta,
senior medical correspondent at CNN.
Right now,
he's got the market cornered.
Well, good for Sanjay.
Hello?
Oh, hey, Lucy.
Now?
Um, yeah, yeah.
No, that sounds great.
I'll see you there. Okay. Bye.
Grab your coats.
We're going tray sledding.
What?
We're gonna meet Lucy
over at the dining hall,
sneak out a couple of trays, and
then go tray sledding down Science Hill.
We can cross it off the list.
Come on.
But tray sledding isn't slated
to happen for a few more weeks.
Well, that's okay, 'cause there might
not be as much snow in a couple weeks.
And Lucy and Olivia happen to
be going today, so let's go.
Are you sure you want
me to come with you?
- Paris.
- Okay, okay.
Hey, uh, listen.
Thanks for saying those things you
said about me in the cafeteria.
Oh, well, I just didn't want your juvenile
hysterics to muck up the whole chart.
I know.
You two were behaving
like children.
I thought I was gonna have to
put you on the naughty step.
Still, it's just nice
to hear sometimes.
You're not going to cry,
are you?
- No, I don't think so.
- Good.
- Are you ready?
- I'm ready.
Let's go. Oh, wait.
If you fall and break your face,
as many tray sledders do,
don't worry about it 'cause you can
spend the night in the infirmary,
which is another typical
college experience.
Wait. What?
Come on.
Hello?
Hey, I didn't wake you, did I?
Uh, no, hi. No, I'm up.
I just had to tell you. I won.
You won?
It's incredible.
I thought I was screwed.
I mean, her lawyer dug up every last
bit of dirt she could find on me, but...
Oh. Oh, yeah.
Luke, that's great.
Yeah, the judge waited until this
morning to give us her decision.
Oh, man, was that the longest
night of my life. But...
I just got off with my lawyer.
I get shared custody.
Wow. Congratulations.
Yeah, I get to see April at
least one weekend a month,
every other major holiday,
half the summer.
We're gonna work it all out.
It's so great.
So great.
Yeah, I guess the judge just took
everything into consideration
and realized how much I
wanted to be in April's life.
And, of course,
your letter was a big help.
Well, I just wanted to help you,
help April.
Well, you did,
and I'm really grateful.
Anyway, uh,
sorry to call so early.
Thanks again.
Congratulations.
Now, when it comes to papers,
I'm guessing that some of you,
of course,
will be asking me for an extension.
You will be happy to learn
that I have no problem
with extensions.
Here's what you do.
You look at the due
date of the paper,
and then you mark it on your calendar
two weeks prior to that date.
And there you have it.
I've just granted you
a two-week extension.
By the way, my office hours
are every tuesday morning,
and you're welcome to come to me
with any questions or problems,
economic or non, my expertise
extends beyond Keynesian theory,
and I will be happy
to lend an ear.
So, let's get started.
As you know, this course...
will take a specific look at...
processes and determinants...
of overall economic p...
Someone call 911!
www.tvsubtitles.net