Are you sure we got
enough plain onesies?
Let me see. 40 people have
RSVped "yes" to Lane's shower,
and we bought 60 onesies
for them to decorate.
I don't want to go all
"beautiful mind" on you,
but according to
my calculations...
Yes, Mr. Nash, but you are forgetting
about the first-pancake phenomenon.
Yes, the first pancake --
you always throw it out.
What if people start
decorating their onesies
and they hate what they do,
so they want to start over
and we don't have enough onesies
because we only estimated one each?
Why do you throw out
the first pancake?
Because the griddle's too hot.
It gets burned.
Oh, my god.
Next year, no excuses.
We are making you that
audition tape for "Top Chef."
This is pretty basic stuff.
Do you do it with hamburgers
and waffles, too?
No, it's pancake-specific.
Oh, my goodness.
Well, that's good news,
because onesies are the
exact opposite of pancakes.
They're totally
impossible to screw up.
You can slap anything on a
onesie and it looks cute.
- Anything?
- Yeah.
Alligator, fried egg, tools --
these are not generally
considered cute items.
"I'll take the adorable phillips-head
--" not something you hear normally.
- But you put that on a little onesie...
- You're right, it's pretty damn cute.
So cute.
All right,
we got streamers and balloons,
and the cake's in the fridge.
The chairs are getting
delivered later.
All we have to do now is
go home and decorate.
But did we agree on one
table for presents or two?
One.
Don't you think two
would be better?
One is fine.
Okay. But I'm not going
for "fine," you know?
Lane's shower cannot be fine.
I want it to be great.
It will be.
Yeah, but how do you know? I don't
exactly have the best track record.
Lane's bachelorette party,
we ended up in Brian's aunt's basement.
Well, it was your
first pancake.
Hold on.
Hello?
Yes, this is Rory.
New York Times.
Hi. Um, thank you for calling me back.
Thank you so much.
Yes.
Uh... as a matter of fact,
I will be.
The corner of 9th and -- great.
Um, okay.
Uh, I'll see you then.
- Oh, my god.
- The New York Times?
- The New York Times!
- They called you?
- They called me.
- Why did they call you?
- Well --
- Don't even answer.
If I was the New York Times,
I would be like,
"Get me Rory Gilmore
on the phone, stat."
"Stat"?
Whatever the equivalent
of "stat" is in the news.
- "Now"?
- No!
At the New York Times,
the language is very fancy. You say
"promptly," "presently," "two
shakes of a lamb's tail."
Why did they call you?
Well, okay, remember that guy Hugo
Gray that I met at Logan's work party,
the guy who edits
the online magazine?
- Yeah, you're writing pieces for him.
- Exactly.
Hugo has an in at the Times --
this guy A.J. Abrams.
He's an assistant managing editor --
really big.
He gave me A.J.'s number and
said that I should call him
and see if he would get together with me
for coffee so I could pick his brain.
A.J.'s brain?
Well, Hugo's brain
had been picked clean.
But, yeah, I called A.J.,
and I never heard back.
I didn't think he was gonna call me,
but that was him just now on the phone,
and he said that if I was gonna be
in the city tomorrow around 1:00,
he could meet me for coffee.
And I said, "oh, well,
as a matter of fact, I will be."
He said something about a place on 9th,
and I said, "okay,"
and he said, "see you tomorrow,"
and I said, "see you then."
Oh, my god, if this is any indication
of the crackling spitfire dialogue
to come at your coffee
tomorrow -- ha!
This is the worst possible time,
but I just couldn't say no.
No, you couldn't say no.
I mean, let's face it.
"Top Chef" is a long shot.
This is the New York Times.
I know!
But I have so much to do to get
ready for Lane's baby shower.
- I'll take care of it.
- Are you sure?
Yes, I'm like a
professional party-thrower.
- Well, I know, but --
- No buts.
Okay, I mean --
that would be great.
I should probably spend the
night at Logan's tonight.
My laptop's there. I need to
print out my résumé, I should --
God, I need to prepare.
He's gonna expect me to ask him
really intelligent questions.
Honey, you've been asking intelligent
questions since you were 3.
Yeah, he's probably expecting
something a little more sophisticated.
Than "what is a color?" That one,
like, blew my mind.
Something a little more
newspaper-related, at the very least.
You're gonna be great.
I hope so. Even if they
don't have an opening there,
he knows people all across the country,
you know?
If I impress him, he can probably set
me up with some really good leads.
Yeah, well, tell him your mother
thinks you're spectacular.
I will do. Oh, my god.
The New York Times called me --
and not the subscriptions department.
Is it straight?
Oh, it's cute.
Yes, that's funny.
Thanks.
- Not what you asked.
- No.
- Hit me again.
- Is the sign straight?
- Uh, perfect.
- Great.
Ooh, Angelina and Brad
had their baby...
months and months ago!
Yeah, you're a little
behind the times.
This is the problem with having
two kids under the age of 4 --
world events just pass you by.
Are you done with those favors?
I cannot believe Britney is driving
with her baby on her lap like that.
What is she doing with that guy,
by the way?
Well, you'll be glad to know
they've since broken up,
although it turns out he was kind of
a stabilizing influence in her life.
- Who knew?
- You're kidding.
I know --
why don't you blow up some more balloons
or hang some streamers?
I would love to, but it seems
like the baby really wants me
to just keep sitting here
and reading in touch.
You know that excuse expires the
minute you pop that baby out.
Yep, but I've got
128 lazy days left.
Hey, why don't you go through
the stack of pictures?
'Cause Rory is looking for one of
Lane that she wants to blow up.
Ooh, baby pictures -- fun!
What do we got?
Oh, god. Ooh!
This one is so cute.
- That's just of Rory, though.
- I know.
She was just an itty-bitty, teeny,
little, cutie-patootie, wasn't she?
Yeah, she's cute.
Oh, she weally,
weally was, wasn't she?
Seriously, with the voice...
Well, sorry. I'm hormonal.
I just can't believe
this wittle girl
might be working at
the New York Times.
She's not so wittle anymore.
Hey, less Rory, more Lane.
Don't blame me. I'm not the one that
got camera-happy for this Rory kid.
All right. I'm gonna call Mrs.
Kim. She'll have some good ones.
Have you seen the phone?
See, the thing is,
when I sat down,
I realized it was behind me,
kind of right on my lower back,
and normally I would have pulled it out,
but it's really kind of hitting just
the right spot where I've had a knot
for like a week.
Did I mention I was pregnant?
Logan?
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Go back to bed. Go back to bed.
- Logan, it's really late.
- I know. I know.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Go back to bed.
Is this all the cheese that we have?
I could have sworn we had more cheese.
- It's 3:00 in the morning.
- I know.
Here, keep that closed. We're gonna need
that in the sandwich-making process.
Where were you?
What? I was at work.
You were at work till
3:00 in the morning?
I work till 3:00 all the time.
I mean, not tonight --
tonight, I worked till about 10:00,
and that's when Philip and I got something
to drink, and then a little something
- turned into a lot of something.
- Yeah.
Who keeps bread in the refrigerator?
I hate cold bread.
God, these twist
ties are impossible.
- Okay, move.
- What?
- I'll make you a sandwich.
- You will?
- Yes, I will.
- Oh, you're so sweet.
Well, I'm not being sweet.
You're just making a mess.
- I should have called you.
- Yes, you should have.
- Uh-oh. You're mad.
- Yes, I'm mad.
I was worried about you.
I called you four times
before I went to sleep, okay?
You didn't answer,
no call back.
- I'm sorry.
- You're sorry?
Well, my phone was on "off."
Which totally sounds like it's on,
but it's not. It's on "off,"
which is on "off."
- On "off," got it?
- I get it.
What, I'm not allowed to go out with
my friends every once in a while?
I work hard, okay?
Life is hard. I just --
- I need to --
- You need to what?
I need to not be doing this right now,
okay? I just --
You know what? Forget the sandwich.
I'm just gonna go to bed.
So you're telling me you
won't eat this oatmeal?
The are rolled oats
repeatedly cut,
twice steamed,
and processed extensively.
And the oatmeal you thought
you were ordering was...
Steel cut,
which are whole-grain oats,
retaining the more natural, nutty
flavor of the original oat kernels.
Okay, okay. I think I got it.
You're like an analog
guy with a CD.
You miss the vinyl's
cool scratches and pops.
I think I can work with that.
This dude over here wants to replace
this with some sort of steel oatmeal.
Tell him we've got it but it takes forever
to cook, and then deliver those plates
- to table 5.
- I'm on it.
Luke, check it out.
I've been published.
You have?
Mother wanted to sell her dinette set,
so I put pen to paper,
got my creative juices flowing,
and voilà.
You put a want ad in the
Stars Hollow Gazette?
It's a powerful feeling seeing
yourself immortalized in print.
Sure, it's only newsprint. It rips
easily, it comes off on your fingers,
and the next day,
people use it to wrap fish, but,
hey, it's how
Dickens got started.
In want ads?
Man, this thing really flows --
"vintage dinette set, formica,
barely chipped,
priced to move."
It's precise, efficient,
Hemingwayesque in
its terse simplicity.
With two buns in the oven, you wouldn't
be interested in a dinette set, would you?
- 64.
- No, thanks, man.
Hey, Luke, you still haven't
RSVped for the baby shower.
Yeah, I don't
think I'm gonna go.
- Oh, really?
- Yeah, it's not my thing, you know?
But there's a gift for you in the back.
You should take it before you leave.
Wait -- gifts are required?
Yeah, that's kind
of the whole point.
At least that's how Lane talked
me into the whole thing.
Damn. It's my
first baby shower.
I've been so caught up with
the wardrobe question.
Just to clarify, people don't
actually dress like babies, do they?
I think what you're
wearing is fine, dude.
- Luke, you should come.
- Yeah, thanks.
Look, it's not gonna be
too much of a rager --
real mellow vibe,
and I promise not too much baby stuff.
There won't be anything weird
or queer about it at all.
I'll think about it.
Listen to this one --
"Does the spray of the open
ocean call your name?"
Evocative, huh?
This guy can write.
"Sturdy 15-foot fishing boat.
Back-to-back seats, closed bow,
meticulously handcrafted."
How far out of town
is 1211 Elmwood?
1211 Elmwood?
- That's what it says here.
- Let me see that.
- That's my boat!
- Really?
How much are you asking?
Because I wasn't looking for a boat,
but that ad is so snappy,
it makes me think I
wouldn't mind owning one.
So, what's it going to be,
yes or no?
Well, I really like them.
I'm just not sure
how they're gonna
work in the room.
They will work. They are teak.
Teak is a hardworking wood.
How about I take
them out on memo?
Memo?
You know, bring them home,
see how they look.
If I like them,
then I'll buy them.
No! I do not work with memos.
I work with money.
You buy them,
and then you take them home.
What if they don't
fit next to the bed?
Then you'll get a new bed.
- Hi, Mrs. Kim.
- Lorelai.
- How's business?
- People die, go bankrupt.
- There's always furniture to sell.
- Sounds good.
- You've come for pictures of Lane?
- Yeah.
- Here you are.
- Thanks.
I am giving these to you
in pristine condition,
and I expect that that is
how they will be returned.
Do not cut them up or
put glue on the back.
I will do my best.
I will return them in the condition
in which they were received.
See you at the shower.
Oh, no, you won't.
- Why?
- I'm not going.
You're not going to your
daughter's baby shower? Why not?
Lane knows why.
Oh. There's a problem
between you two?
Yes.
Do you think you could
put it aside for one day?
No.
- It's that big a deal?
- Yes.
Is there anything Lane could say
or do that would change your mind?
Yes.
- Does Lane know what it is?
- Yes.
What do I have,
like 14 questions left?
I have work to do.
Mrs. Kim, I know Lane would really
like you to be at the shower.
Well, life is full
of disappointments.
You can show yourself out.
Too late!
You cannot buy those tables anymore!
Okay, then.
- Hi.
Wow. Sorry, but, hoo! Wow.
I know, every day, I think I can't
possibly get any bigger, and then I do.
It's looking homey in here.
Thanks. According to my book,
I'm nesting.
I hope it stops soon.
It's sort of creeping me out.
So, what's up?
Um, well,
I wanted to talk to you about your mom.
- What happened with you guys?
- Ask her.
No, I've already been through that.
You tell me what happened.
We got in a fight.
And now she says she's not
coming to my baby shower.
So, fine. She's not coming.
I don't care.
Lane.
I don't. Why should I?
She doesn't.
Of course she does.
Not more than she cares
about fried shrimp.
You lost me there.
Well, last night,
my mom was over.
And Zach had cut out an ad for
the seafood festival red lobster.
He was trying to figure out, if we
went there after we had the babies,
could we get the endless
shrimp but at the kids' price?
No, you can only get the kidsprice when
accompanied by an adult paying full price.
- That blows.
- I know.
Then what happened?
So then my mom sticks her
nosy head in and said,
"the children are not gonna
be eating fried shrimp."
And I said, "not only are my children
gonna be eating fried shrimp,
they're gonna listen to
whatever music they want
and go to school dances, and they're
not gonna spend their whole lives
in church hearing about how
doing all that makes them evil.
In fact, they'll probably never
set foot in a church at all.
My kids are gonna have total freedom.
End of story."
- Total freedom, huh?
- Yep.
Wow, you're just gonna let them follow
their passion, no matter what it is?
Exactly.
What if you get kids who are
passionate about religion?
You may have kids who
want to study the bible.
Trust me -- my kids are not
gonna want to study the bible.
You don't know what your
kids are gonna want.
You think your mom thought
she was gonna get a kid
who loved Jane's addiction?
Well...
You might get kids who are nuts
for exodus, crazy for deuteronomy,
and then what? You want them hiding
their bibles under the floorboards?
Well, look,
if my kids want to go to bible study,
they can go to bible study.
Well, see?
And then what about church?
If they want to go to church,
you're not gonna let them,
even at Christmas,
when they have the manger
and the petting zoo with
the sheep and the donkeys?
Well, I might take
them at Christmas.
Okay, so when you say they're never
going to church, you don't really mean
they're never going to church.
Okay, not never never,
but mostly never.
- Can't you tell your mom that?
- No way.
Can I tell your mom that?
Okay, if you want, but tell her I
am not bending on the shrimp thing.
I got you there. Fried shrimp is one
of the best things on the planet.
A double whammy --
unclean meat fried in unclean oil.
That doesn't sound as good,
but look at it this way.
For the first year, your kids
won't be eating solid food anyway,
and I don't think they
make mashed fried shrimp.
- So?
- So,
you could tell your mother that
your kids will not eat fried shrimp
for at least a year, right?
Well, technically.
"Technically" is
good enough for me.
You sit tight. I'll be back.
It's after 12:00.
Is anyone alive in there?
I'm alive,
but I think my brain is dead.
I'll alert the transplant team.
You gave away my organs?
They're waiting on the
roof with a cooler.
Take these.
Will I wake up in a bathtub
full of ice with no kidneys?
If you did,
would you feel better or worse?
About the same.
Your dad's secretary called
three times this morning.
Okay, now I feel worse.
Logan, what's going on?
Nothing.
You're not gonna
call your dad back?
My head grew three sizes overnight.
I'm in no condition to talk to anybody.
Why are you so dressed up?
Coffee with the
New York Times --
the whole reason why I
stayed over last night.
Oh, yeah, that's right.
That's today.
Yes, and Lane's baby shower.
I'm gonna need you to be ready
to leave for Stars Hollow
the second I get back.
We're gonna be cutting it really close.
Lane's shower starts at 4:00.
I should be back by 2:00 or
2:30 at the latest. Got it?
Got it.
Okay, I'll just come home,
grab my outfit, and we'll go.
I'm gonna need you to drive because
I have to change in the backseat,
"Dirty Dancing"-style.
Do you want me to get that?
Leave it.
- If you don't want to get up, I can --
- I said, "leave it."
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I better go.
I don't want to be late.
It's Logan. Leave a message.
Hi, Logan. It's Doris from
your father's office again.
If you could just give us a
call back here at the office
as soon as you
get this message.
I know you have the number,
but just in case...
See? Look at it.
It's just sitting here
gathering dust and
taking up space.
If we got rid of the boat, we could turn
this place into a workshop for my jewelry,
and I really could
use the space.
Doula's gonna be crawling around soon,
getting into everything.
And jewelry-making's really
a dangerous business, Luke.
You got all those tiny beads --
choking hazards galore.
Yeah, babies really like to
put stuff in their mouth.
They can't help it.
They get mesmerized.
The little suckers look so much
like candy or pistachio nuts,
you just want to pop
them in your mouth.
Yeah, so as you can see,
we could really use the space.
So you were just gonna sell
the boat out from under me.
Of course not.
We just figured we'd take an ad,
get an offer, see what you say.
Yeah, could be great, huh?
You get a little extra cash,
we get a little extra space.
Plus, we were thinking maybe you
could invest some of the profits
from the boat in
Liz's business.
If you felt like it was
the right thing to do.
But it does kind of make sense
since we went through the trouble
of selling the boat...
and storing it.
Whoa. Doula alert.
Not up yet -- just a squawk.
Look, guys,
I appreciate your situation here,
but I'm not selling the boat.
Dad left it to me.
It's my boat. End of discussion.
Hey, look, don't worry,
all right?
- I'll find another place to store it.
- Like where?
I don't know. I'll find a place.
Another place.
What's the point of hanging on to it?
You're never gonna use it.
- I might.
- You might. Dad might.
- What are you talking about?
- The boat.
Dad spent like 20 years
working on the thing.
- You spent another 20.
- So?
So? How many generations are
gonna cart this thing around town?
Look, get rid of it for your own sake,
before you end up like dad.
What does that mean?
Oh, okay. Okay, forget it.
No, I want to know.
What does that mean?
- He was stuck, Luke.
- He was happy.
He was stuck doing the same
thing at the same time
the same way every
day of his life.
So? He did the things
that made him happy.
Dad didn't do stuff
'cause it made him happy.
He did stuff because he was
afraid to do anything else.
Come on, that's crap.
- Luke, I loved dad as much as you did.
- Look, he was good to us.
Of course he was.
I'm just saying
sometimes a little change
can be a good thing.
My boat, my decision.
I'm not selling it.
- All right? All right.
- Okay. Okay.
I'll have it out of
here by tomorrow.
Hello?
How bald do you have
to be to be bald?
Is this a zen call?
You know I hate those.
Does it mean completely bald,
or does it count
if there's no hair on top
but a little on the sides?
Well, in my experience,
if a man describes himself as bald,
there is nary a hair.
Nice use of "nary."
I'm trying to get you in
the New York Times mood,
use some fancy language.
Well, I will remember that
if I can ever find the guy.
Who knew New York was the
bald-guy capital of the world?
I think that's on
their license plate.
I'm telling you, they're everywhere, and
since I don't know which one A.J. is,
every time one walks in the door,
I just smile at him.
And let me guess --
they're all smiling back.
What's wrong with me?
What kind of reporter am I going to be
if all I got was "bald guy"?
Oh, relax.
He knows what you look like, right?
I just hate this waiting.
What should I do?
Should I go order a coffee without him?
Should I wait for him?
Order coffee. He won't mind.
Well, I can't, really.
I'm at a table.
I don't even know if I should be
sitting down already, but I walked in,
it was really crowded, and this woman
left her table, so I grabbed it,
and now I'm scared to get up
because maybe I'll lose it.
- Keep the table, skip the coffee.
- Really?
Yeah. And when he gets there,
go decaf.
Yeah, I know I'm a little nervous, but it's
only because doing well at this meeting
could mean the difference between
interviewing world leaders
and standing on street corners
with pictures of celebrities
in matching outfits asking
passersby who wore it best.
Pretty high stakes.
I know. Distract me.
How's the shower stuff going?
Oh, something's wrong!
No, nothing's wrong.
Oh, I knew it.
My second pancake's gonna suck, too.
I've got it all under control. You just
focus on finding the right bald guy.
Oh, another one just walked in.
- Oh, head-to-hair ratio?
- Very low.
Stand by while I attempt
to make eye contact.
Lookt it this way --
you're making a lot of bald men
feel very good about
themselves today.
- I better go.
- Knock 'em dead, kid.
So, you're giving me a guarantee
for Christmas and easter.
As a minimum.
And there will be a
possibility of bible study
and no unclean meats
for at least a year.
That's a start, at least.
- So, do we have a deal?
- No, I never take first offer.
This is what I want --
attendance at weekly church services,
bible study twice a week,
adventist summer camp,
no unclean meats or
hydrogenated oils,
Christmas will be
celebrated with no gifts,
and there will be no sandboxes
or parties with pony rides.
What's wrong with ponies?
Flies buzzing around,
carrying infectious diseases.
No infected ponies, fine.
But sandboxes? I mean, come on.
Kids play, they go to the park.
You have to be reasonable.
It is not reasonable
for Lane to think
that she will raise my
grandchildren as heathens
while I stand by
and do nothing.
I understand, Mrs. Kim.
It's a really sensitive subject.
No, you don't.
Your daughter doesn't reject
everything you stand for.
But Lane is not rejecting you.
You guys are just different.
God knows my mother
and I had differences.
Yes. God does know.
Look... there are times when you
have to put those differences aside.
Like, you know Joseph,
from the bible,
and how his brothers got all
mad at him about that dreamcoat.
Yes, and so they sold
him into slavery.
Yeah. I don't think that
was in the musical.
The point is there are fights you can
recover from and fights you can't,
and not going to your
daughter's baby shower --
I mean, I know it's hard,
but I don't want you to draw a line in
the sand now that you can't cross later.
My mother missed so much.
I don't want that
to happen to you.
- Hello?
- Hey.
Hey, dad.
How was swim practice?
Drills, drills, drills. Coach scott
made us swim with our fists closed.
- What does that do?
- Probably nothing.
Just looks funny. I did get to
work on my backward racing start.
How'd that go?
Not so good. I think I ended up
with half the pool up my nose.
Eh, you'll get better.
Can't get much worse.
So, how's your mom doing?
Good. Little stressed
about the new store.
She likes the space,
but she's not sure about the location.
Strip malls bum her out.
So what's going on?
Nothing. You know,
business as usual.
I saw your cousin Doula today.
She looks good. She's getting bigger.
You promised you'd
send me new pictures.
I will. I will.
So, look, I was thinking about this
summer when you come to visit.
I can't wait.
Yeah, me too.
So, I was thinking maybe
we should take a trip.
A trip?
Yeah, a big one, you know?
You're gonna be here
for six weeks, right?
So maybe we should
just take off.
And go where?
You know, I don't know.
I was thinking Florida.
Florida?
Yeah, you know,
go down to Disneyworld.
You want to go to disneyworld?
Yeah. You've never been there.
I've never been there.
We could fly down to Florida
and check out Miami Beach
and then go to... Disneyworld.
I-I can't imagine you at Disneyworld --
or at the beach, for that matter.
W-Why not?
I don't know --
riding roller coasters, getting
your picture taken with mickey mouse.
I'm just having
trouble picturing it.
Yeah, well...
Look, dad, you don't have to do this.
It's okay.
I'm looking forward to the summer, but
it's not like I'm expecting anything.
Oh, no, sure.
I mean, I'm fine just hanging out
at the diner like we always do --
wipe down tables,
refill salt and pepper shakers.
It's our thing.
Really, honestly, it's fine.
Oh, okay.
Oh, mom wants to talk to you real
quick about some travel stuff
for my spring break.
But don't hang up when you're done,
'cause I want to read
you something I wrote.
Oh, yeah?
We had to write a
five-page fictional story
featuring someone we know as the hero,
and I chose Kirk.
It's hilarious.
I'll give you to mom,
and I'll get the story.
Okay, great.
Hi.
Can we come in?
Sure. Whatever.
Isn't that nice? So great.
Okay.
Here we go.
So...
So.
So, what?
Your mother has something
she'd like to say to you.
You say it.
Me? Um... you'll jump in?
Okay.
Uh... Lane, um...
your mother realizes that the
two of you have differences.
She might not always agree
with all of your decisions.
No "might." She doesn't agree.
I know.
You've made yourself perfectly clear.
Lane.
Sorry. Go on.
She doesn't agree with
all your decisions.
However, she knows how much
you love and respect her.
Don't you, Lane?
Of course I do.
And she'd very much like
to come to your shower.
- Really?
- Really.
Thank you, mama.
- Lane?
- You okay?
I think so.
What's wrong?
Are you going into labor?
I don't know.
I've never been in labor before.
You might have
had a contraction.
We'll wait and see
if you have another.
There will be no waiting. You will
drive us to the hospital right now.
- Hurry, Lorelai.
- Okay.
Careful, Lane.
Wait. I'll get it.
Uh, well, okay. You got it.
- You got it.
- All right.
Here we go.
I can't believe I'm on bed rest.
This sucks.
Oh, come on, haven't you ever
had one of those lazy sundays
where you stay in bed all day? Just
think of this as one long lazy sunday.
Yeah, babe. Plus you get to
eat all your meals on trays.
That's pretty cool.
And I'm gonna hang out with you,
- just like John and Yoko.
- This is your fault.
Mine? See what I deal with?
Lane...
We shouldn't have
gone to the hospital.
Better I watch my
daughter writhe in pain?
I wasn't writhing.
Lorelai, tell her I wasn't writhing.
Does it really matter who
was or wasn't writhing?
Your mom was worried about you.
Yeah, right.
She's probably happy.
- Why would I be happy?
- 'Cause now I can't have my party.
Lane Van Gerbig,
what is wrong with you?
Parties are not the most
important thing in life.
I know.
- Do you?
- Of course.
It's just that this
one is my last.
Why is it your last?
I'm about to be a mother.
Um, mothers can have parties.
Not for themselves.
They only do things for their children.
She did everything for me.
And... I'm...
gonna be the same way.
You will have the party.
How?
Uh... Lorelai will
figure something out.
Cool!
Hello. I'm home.
Hey. How'd it go?
Awesome.
Logan! You're not dressed!
It's 2:30.
You were supposed to be dressed
- and ready.
- I'm dressed.
But not for Lane's shower.
Come on, get up. Let's go.
Wait, wait. Sit down.
Tell me how it went.
I'll tell you on the way.
Come on.
Wait. Sit down.
I have to tell you something.
Well, that doesn't
sound so good.
It's not.
Look, I screwed up,
okay? Big-time.
What's going on?
The company I bought,
the new business I was trying to start?
- It's a bust.
- What?
We're going belly-up
because of me.
I lost everybody's money --
my money, my dad's money,
all our investors' money,
the parking-lot attendant's money,
the hot-dog vendor's money.
I lost money I didn't even know I had.
- Logan, be serious.
- I am.
Well... if you are, then back up a step.
Explain this to me.
There's nothing to explain.
The second we bought this company,
all these lawsuits came
out of the woodwork.
- So?
- So one of them has merit,
which means we're screwed --
no money, no jobs, no nothing.
Um... I don't understand.
How long have you
known about this?
Weeks.
Weeks?
Why didn't you say
something about it to me?
I don't know. I thought maybe
I could fix it, you know?
I was looking for loopholes.
Well, you can keep looking.
You'll find one.
No, we can't. Look, it's over.
Philip and I got the final call
last lignt from our patent lawyers.
Their case is solid.
There's nothing we can do but settle.
I screwed up, okay?
I rushed in.
I didn't do my research.
It's all my fault.
Well, I'm sure that's not true.
I'm sure there's something --
Rory, you're not getting this.
This is huge.
This isn't something you can fix
with a plucky,
good attitude and a can-do spirit.
- Well, I'm just trying to help.
- I know.
Well, what about your dad?
What's he say about all this?
I haven't talked to him.
Logan, you're gonna
have to talk to him.
Rory, don't give me
any grief about this.
Any minute now, Mitchum is gonna
be busting through that door
champing at the bit to tell me
what a gigantic failure I am.
God, I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry about all this.
I know you are.
Well, you'll get through it.
We'll get through it.
I mean, whatever happens,
we'll figure it out together.
Sure. And I'm
sorry about today.
I just can't deal
with a baby shower.
No, I know. I get it.
The minute it's over,
I will come back, and I'll bring cake.
- You don't have to hurry.
- I want to.
No, it's cool, don't worry about it.
I'm not gonna be here.
You're going out?
I'm gonna go to Vegas
with Colin and Finn.
What?
Yeah, I just need to blow
off steam for a couple days.
- With Colin and Finn.
- It's perfect timing.
Colin's got his dad's jet gassed up at
Teterboro. I'm gonna meet him in an hour.
To go to Vegas with
Colin and Finn.
Yeah. Finn bought a
racehorse with George Maloof.
How hilarious is that?
I'm gonna go take a shower.
Are you kidding me?
This is really what you want to do?
I just need a break, okay?
Tell Lane I said congrats.
Word on the street is you
want to sell your boat.
I called you, Kirk.
Yeah, but I was on the
street when I got that call.
And to be honest with you,
I was a little surprised
to hear about this
turn of events.
It's not a turn of events, Kirk.
I just want to sell my boat.
But you've always been really
attached to this boat.
Hell, I thought you'd take
it to your grave with you,
maybe row yourself
across the river Styx.
Turns out I'm not using it.
You interested?
It does suit me.
And it'd be great for water-skiing.
Lulu loves water-skiing.
She also loves carriage rides.
You're not selling a carriage, are you?
Just the boat, kirk.
You interested or not?
- How much we talking?
- $600.
- I was thinking more around $300.
- Price isn't negotiable.
- Okay, $400.
- Non-negotiable --
$600 price includes everything,
Kirk, even the trailer.
- $590.
- $600, Kirk.
$595, and you throw in a life
preserver and a captain's hat.
$600, you buy your
own captain's hat.
- But you'll throw in a life preserver?
- Deal. Just have it out of here A.S.A.P.
Sucker.
Oh, plates and cups
right by the food.
Art supplies over at the
onesies table. Thanks.
Hey, Sookie, I forget --
are these edible or soap?
Soap.
Oh, this is a party favor --
not near the candy pacifiers.
Sugar, what do you think?
Is it straight?
It looks great.
Patty, how are you doing?
Adorable.
There is nothing cuter
than a baby in a onesie --
except, of course,
Anthony Quinn in a onesie.
I'll take your word for it.
- Mom!
- Hey! How'd it go?
Why did the baby shower
get moved to miss Patty's?
Oh, it's a long story.
Now tell me about the meeting.
It was great. It was so great.
But what's going on here?
Okay, "great's" not gonna do it.
I need big, juicy details.
All right, Lane had contractions.
She went to the hospital,
but it was a false alarm.
She's okay. She is on bed rest.
- What?
- I know.
But now tell me from the moment that
the right bald guy smiled at you --
- And walk.
- Where are we going?
- How are your shoes?
- My shoes?
Good arch support?
Good traction? Good.
Slow down. Hold it! Hold it.
Too fast.
Mom, I'm fine.
Hey, this is fun.
Don't they push a bed through the streets
in the opening credits of "the monkees"?
I'm pretty sure
it was a bathtub.
Actually it was both -- Davy's in
the bed. Peter's in the bathtub.
Are you sure?
'Cause I could have sworn --
Zach, you don't want to go head-to-head
with her about "monkees" trivia.
You did not come to a full stop!
And use your blinkers!
- Okay, we're turning around.
- Okay, hold on, Lane!
Hold on. Are you ready?
Here we go.
Hold tight. You all right?
Yep. I'm good.
Looking good.
You done there, Patty?
I'm done. How you doing, hon?
Oh, doing great.
Yeah? I mean about the
whole Christopher thing.
Oh, um... fine, you know,
moving forward, moving on.
Good.
If you ask me,
Gil's the one to beat.
Oh, yeah,
I saw him do that whole thing freehand.
He's an amazing man.
As is Kirk.
Don't worry, Lulu.
It's the rock-star thing.
Dean Martin singing "mambo italiano" --
I will never forget it.
Oh, great. I need another one.
Oh, no, no. What are you doing?
Well, I was trying to
make a little truck,
but the flatbed kept
running around to the back.
Well, no do-overs,
so just turn that into something else.
I tried to make Snoopy --
figured he's easy to draw,
and what kid doesn't
like snoopy, right?
Plus, as the added bonus, he's black-and-
white, and the onesie's already white,
so I only got to add the black. But it's
looking more like a chocolate-chip cookie --
a big one.
Which is okay,
'cause what kid doesn't like a cookie?
What am I supposed
to turn this into?
I don't know -- a blob?
Make it a bunch of blobs --
a baby's first rorschach test.
Oh, yeah.
I see a ballerina about to take flight.
I see cheese.
See? Something for everyone.
All right, have fun.
Whoa! This one's homely, man.
Look, it's got Zach's giant ears and
Lane's glasses. I feel for that kid.
Gonna have a rough life.
But it will probably
help to fuel his music.
You know, you got to feel pain
to create the really good stuff.
Yeah, this one's
gonna get the chicks,
but that one's
gonna be the genius.
You know these aren't what Lane and
Zach's kids are gonna look like.
It's one of those computer
morphing programs.
Yeah, dude. I have kids.
I know how it works.
Thanks for coming.
Yo, hello. What's up, guys?
Hi, everyone.
I don't want to interrupt the fun.
I just wanted to say
thank you for coming
to this somewhat
unconventional baby shower,
which is actually perfect,
because when do Lane and Zach
ever do anything
that's conventional?
I've known Lane now for --
what has it been? 17 years?
And... I'm just sick
of her already.
No, actually,
I just love you and Zach so much,
and I just can't wait
to meet those boys.
So thank you so much for coming.
Keep having fun.
And just eat, drink,
and keep decorating those onesies.
Thanks, Rory. This party rocks.
It's all due to my mom, though.
I planned, she executed.
Well, you both rock.
Well, how often does a girl's
best friend have twins?
Just once, let's hope.
Yeah, no kidding.
You want a drink, babe?
- Maybe a lemonade.
- Coming right up.
Seriously, Zach's right.
This party is amazing.
Everything you guys did --
truthfully, I didn't think it
was actually gonna happen.
Yes, well, that whole bed-rest
thing really threw a wrench in.
- Plus the fight.
- What fight?
You didn't hear
about the fight?
Me and my mom,
classic Kim family grudgefest?
If not for your mom, we might have gone
the way of pretty girls make graves.
They were so young and had so
many killer albums left in them.
So my mom brokered peace?
Hard-core.
Listen... here's the thing.
My kids are gonna need that,
too --
You know, when they're hiding
bibles and they can't stand me.
So what I wanted to know is...
would you be their
Lorelai Gilmore?
I guess that's the proper term.
Really?
I can't think of anyone
who would be better.
Plus, you already
have the name.
- I'd love to. Yeah.
- Thanks.
- Here.
- Hi, Mrs. Kim. What's this?
Open it.
- It's a doorknob.
- Not just any doorknob --
John Adams' doorknob.
You are familiar with our
second president, I assume?
Not personally.
- You're making a joke?
- Little one.
That's what I thought.
Anyway, I'm glad to be here,
- and I wanted you to know that.
- Hence the doorknob.
- Yes.
- Thank you.
Don't tarnish it,
or its value will decrease.
Okay.
- Do you have my pictures?
- I left them at home.
- I'll drop them off tomorrow.
- You do that.
- Hey, you guys.
- Hey, you.
Way to go. It's a great party.
It is, right? I could have used
another gift table, though.
Yeah, somebody went crazy.
I wouldn't say "crazy."
Wait -- that's all from us?
Well, I felt bad.
I had already promised them all of
our old stuff from Martha and Davey,
- and then I had to renege.
- So they get all new stuff,
and we have to keep the crappy hand-me-
downs? How does that make any sense?!
Whose fault is this, huh?
Nice talking to you.
See you later.
Ahoy, Lorelai.
Yeah, Kirk.
What's with the hat?
Oh, this? No big deal.
Just bought myself a boat.
- A boat?
- Yeah, the S.S. Lurk.
It's a combination of my name and
Luke's since it used to be his boat.
Oh, you bought Luke's boat.
Yeah, she needs a little more
work before she's seaworthy,
but as soon as she is,
I'll take you out.
You can be Ginger
to Lulu's Mary Ann.
Let's lock down dates now.
- When are you free?
- Mom.
Oh, well,
we'll figure it out later. Bye.
Perfect timing. You save me from a
three-hour tour of the S.S. Lurk.
The what?
Kirk bought Luke's old boat.
Does he even have
a driver's licence?
I don't think so.
- I'm staying out of the water.
- Good kid.
Why didn't you tell me about
the whole drama with Mrs. Kim?
Honey, you had your meeting.
You were nervous enough already.
Yeah, I was, wasn't I?
You got the whole brunt of
that freak-out. I'm so sorry.
That's okay.
So, do you think it went well?
I do,
I think it went really well.
I mean,
the reston fellowship is a long shot.
They only pick four people out of the
whole country, and that's including
college seniors and
graduate students.
So? You and three other people.
Yeah, but can you imagine it? I would
be an intern at the New York Times.
- I'd be up for bylines.
- I can imagine it.
I don't want to get my hopes up,
so I'm not even gonna think about it.
- Can I think about it?
- Yes, but not around me.
Deal. So,
when is Logan getting here?
- Oh. He's not.
- Why?
Um... it's a long story. I guess there
was this huge disaster at his work.
- Oh, no.
- Yeah.
I guess the company he
bought is being sued,
and he's losing all kinds of money --
not only his own money,
his dad's money.
It's awful, and he feels awful.
At least that explains
why he's acting awful.
What do you mean?
Well, right now, he's on a private
jet to Vegas with Colin and Finn.
"Got kicked out of Argentina with
the bush twins" Colin and Finn?
So sorry. You okay?
Yeah, I'm fine. I just wish that
he'd told me about this earlier,
that I'd known it was going on.
Maybe I could have helped.
Honey, I don't think there's
anything you could have done.
Yeah, I know,
but maybe I could have tried, you know?
And now he just took off, which -- I
get it. He needs to blow off some steam,
but I just wish he could
have come to the party.
It would have meant so much to me.
He could have met everyone.
I know.
But I'm sure we'll
figure it out.
Oh, hey, Lane asked me to be
her Lorelai Gilmore to her kids,
like you were to her.
Yeah.
Big shoes to fill.
Well, luckily,
we have similar feet.
What?
Oh, it's nothing.
Come on.
I just think my first pancake
turned out pretty darn good.
Hey. Sorry to interrupt.
That's all right.
I was wondering if we should
bring the cake out now,
because Lane's got that
low-blood-sugar look in her eye.
Oh, yeah, let's do it.
Seems like yesterday she was taking
up three tables at the diner
with those giant books of hers.
Yep. She was something.
Is something.
So, what's this I hear
about Kirk buying your boat?
Oh, well... I just realized I was
never gonna take that thing out.
I mean, all that time I
spent trying to fix it up...
So I bought a new one.
When?
Today -- got the idea in my
head a couple hours ago,
went down to the shipyard in Bridgeport,
and just did it.
You just bought a boat.
Yeah, and it's even bigger
and better than the old one.
It's got everything.
It's got a little kitchen,
a bathroom,
even a place to sleep.
- Wow.
- I'm gonna keep it in the marina.
And then when April comes
to visit in the summer,
take it out on little trips,
go away for a few weeks.
- Luke, that sounds really nice.
- Right?
God, I can't believe you
bought a boat in a day.
It used to take you a
week to buy a t-shirt.
Yeah, well, things change.
I'll see you inside?
All right, everyone,
here comes cake!
Ready, fellas.
One, two, three, four...
# Hush, little baby,
don't say a word #
# Papa's gonna buy
you a mockingbird #
# And if that
mockingbird don't sing #
# Papa's gonna buy
you a diamond ring #
# And if that diamond
ring turns brass #
# Papa's gonna buy
you a looking glass #
# And if that looking
glass gets broke #
# Papa's gonna buy
you a billy goat #
# And if that billy
goat won't pull #
Transcript : Raceman
Subtitles : Willow's Team
www.forom.com
www.tvsubtitles.net